(When someone's leaving, you come together...)
(to a certain place to say goodbye to them.)
(It's called send-off.)
(June 13, 2021)
(Lee Kwang Soo's last day on Running Man)
(A day)
It's Kwang Soo. Hello, Kwang Soo.
光洙
不是 光洙啊
It's Kwang Soo. Hello, Kwang Soo.
(A month)
Hello.
您好
(A month)
Hello. Hi.
(A year)
您好
Hello. Hi.
(10 years)
Hello.
(He's been with us for 10 years and 338 days.)
Good morning.
早上好
(He's been with us for 10 years and 338 days.)
- Feeling! - Intuition!
-必 -觸
(Even without Kwang Soo, Running Man's time, )
- Cross! - Cross!
cross
(Even without Kwang Soo, Running Man's time, )
安靜 安靜
(Running Man's betrayal, )
Lee Kwang Soo is out.
(Running Man's joke, )
- Okay. - Gosh, what's that?
太慢了
(Running Man's joke, )
(Running Man's laughter...)
(will continue endlessly.)
(And the joy of each episode will keep piling up.)
(But we hope...)
(it will always be fun and pleasant...)
(to reminisce about the shining time we've spent with Kwang Soo.)
(Today, we are going to send him off with joy, )
Let's begin.
-開始了 準備 -好 可以了
(Today, we are going to send him off with joy, )
All right. Thank you.
(but Kwang Soo will...)
(also have to say goodbye to Lee Kwang Soo of Running Man.)
- So the last shoot is finally over. - Right.
-今天最後的拍攝就開始了-是
(also have to say goodbye to Lee Kwang Soo of Running Man.)
(10 days before Kwang Soo's final shoot at Cafe A in Geumho-dong)
So this will be your last pre-recording.
也是最後的事前拍攝 是最後所以弄了這樣的
(10 days before Kwang Soo's final shoot at Cafe A in Geumho-dong)
Since this is your last shoot, we prepared this for you.
(On his last day, he gets dessert without any mission to accomplish.)
會好好吃的
Thank you.
(On his last day, he gets dessert without any mission to accomplish.)
哇 真的很好吃啊
This is really good.
(On his last day, he gets dessert without any mission to accomplish.)
哈哈 不是PPL
This isn't product placement.
- No? - No, it's not.
-不是嗎-不是的
(He tries hard to advertise things until the last moment.)
We are going to do some races where you can build...
我們想用李光洙和成員可以積累回憶的東西
good memories with the members.
來做這次比賽
We'd like you to think about...
最後拍攝的話想和成員一起做的事
things you want to do with the members,
(Things he wants to do, )
(food he wants to eat, )
things you want to eat,
想吃的東西還有想去的地方
(and places he wants to go to...)
or places you want to visit...
(with the members on his last day)
on your last day on Running Man.
可以說說你的想法嗎
(with the members on his last day)
I want to go to the place where we shot the first episode.
想去的地方是第一次拍攝的地方
It's the SBS building.
在SBS 其實 那個時候不是露天的嗎
(11 years earlier from today in 2010,)
We don't usually get to go there.
(Running Man was first filmed in SBS Rooftop Garden.)
- You mean the roof garden? - Yes.
-上樓頂 -是的是的
(Running Man was first filmed in SBS Rooftop Garden.)
Actually, it's not like...
其實現在是想去也去不了的地方
I can go there whenever I want now.
And we went to the Han River many times.
還有漢江也去過好多次
We crossed the river in winter.
冬天還橫穿了漢江
And...
在漢江拍攝過很多次
We shot a lot of episodes at the Han River.
(They rowed across the river on a paper boat.)
The right side, row harder.
右邊使勁 右邊
(They rowed across the river on a paper boat.)
This is absolutely crazy.
要瘋了真是
(And they swam across the river.)
- It's really cold. - What kind of punishment is this?
怎麼還有這種事啊
(And they swam across the river.)
-我們選擇李光洙-像這樣在漢江不管做什麼
I want to go to the Han River...
(And they swam across the river.)
(They also greeted the two new members at the Han River.)
whatever we do there.
The weather is nice these days.
(They also greeted the two new members at the Han River.)
天氣也很好
The weather is nice these days.
Things I want to eat?
想吃的是 首先是以前
There was a day...
when we shot an episode at my place.
有過在我們家拍攝的時候
I had chicken soup...
那個時候吃了一整隻雞
with the members.
(They went to Kwang Soo's place and ate chicken kalguksu there.)
- Welcome. - Thank you.
大家一起吃的
(They went to Kwang Soo's place and ate chicken kalguksu there.)
Okay.
It tastes even better at Kwang Soo's place.
(They went to Kwang Soo's place and ate chicken kalguksu there.)
得在光洙家裡吃 真的很好吃
The chicken breast is for Jong Kook.
(They went to Kwang Soo's place and ate chicken kalguksu there.)
雞胸肉在這裡 鐘國哥哥的
I'll eat it.
(They shared the hot soup giggling together on a winter day.)
我來吃掉吧
I think that's my happy memory about food.
(They shared the hot soup giggling together on a winter day.)
在我個人看來那好像是我回憶中的美食
I think that's my happy memory about food.
And we recently went to a pork belly restaurant.
還有不久前不是去了五花肉店嗎
That day,
那時候他們吃的那麼香的樣子
I saw the members enjoy the food a lot.
(The members shared pork belly two months ago.)
真的好像很久都沒有見過了
We've been to many good restaurants, but that day...
(The members shared pork belly two months ago.)
我們去過很多美食店
I really enjoyed it too.
而且我也覺得很好吃
(He felt happy to see the members enjoy the food.)
如果可以的話 也想吃五花肉
If it's possible,
(He felt happy to see the members enjoy the food.)
(He has warm memories about chicken kalguksu and pork belly.)
I want to eat pork belly too.
In the same episode,
(He has warm memories about chicken kalguksu and pork belly.)
還有回去的時候不是去了LP吧嗎
In the same episode,
we also went to the LP bar.
再去一次LP吧的話 應該會很開心吧
If we go there one more time,
they will like it.
(Kwang Soo only chooses the foods and places that the members like.)
Personally, I just want...
按我個人來說的話希望和平常一樣
(Kwang Soo only chooses the foods and places that the members like.)
things to be normal as always.
平常 平常拍攝的時候那樣
Just like an ordinary day.
(He hopes his last day to be as fun as usual.)
Honestly, that's how...
真的是我真情實意的想法
(He hopes his last day to be as fun as usual.)
I'm feeling now.
What? Since this is Kwang Soo's last day,
什麼 因為今天是光洙最後一天
(So today's race is prepared according to Kwang Soo's wish.)
所以在首播時的地方
we're at the place where we shot the first episode.
(So today's race is prepared according to Kwang Soo's wish.)
- Am I right? - It looks just the same.
覺得是這樣吧
(They start at the first filming site of Running Man...)
一樣啊
- Hello. - This is where we shot the opening.
(They start at the first filming site of Running Man...)
你好
- Hello. - This is where we shot the opening.
首播時的場所 因為光洙今天是
(that Kwang Soo wished to be at.)
We're doing this for Kwang Soo's last day.
最後一天所以
(that Kwang Soo wished to be at.)
- Hello. - Hello.
你好
(July 11, 2010, Running Man's first episode)
Running Man
Running Man. Stop walking and run. This is like...
(July 11, 2010, Running Man's first episode)
不要走要跑 這個怎麼有點
Running Man. Stop walking and run. This is like...
-啊 大哥 -來了嗎
(The members look somewhat young.)
- Hello, Seok Jin. - Hey.
是 我是李光洙 年齡是26歲
My name is Lee Kwang Soo, and I'm 26 years old.
(The members look somewhat young.)
(They introduced themselves in the pouring rain.)
My name is Lee Kwang Soo, and I'm 26 years old.
I'm...
我是...幼苗
a sprout.
- It rained a lot that day. - Right.
那時下了好多雨
- It suddenly poured down. - It rained when Kwang Soo talked.
忽然下的吧忽然
(He shoots his final episode...)
- It suddenly poured down. - It rained when Kwang Soo talked.
就光洙說話的時候下了雨
(at the place he introduced himself in the rain.)
I think so.
-對 那時好像那樣
(at the place he introduced himself in the rain.)
- That's when it started. - As I said, "I'm a sprout."
-那時開始
(He still remembers the moment vividly.)
是幼苗
Hey!
(He still remembers the moment vividly.)
喂喂你在最後一天留鬍子做什麼呢
Hey!
- Why are you... - This is your last day,
but why did you not shave your face?
I didn't see that earlier because of his mask.
戴口罩沒看到
(They attack his beard with no room to reminisce.)
- Hey! - You can't do this.
-喂 不能這樣來啊
(They attack his beard with no room to reminisce.)
-上週不是這樣
- I looked like this last week. - You should look neat.
(They attack his beard with no room to reminisce.)
-不是 要清爽的過來啊
I guess it's connected. He had a beard in the first episode.
原來是有關聯
第一集時不是有鬍鬚嗎
(26-year-old Kwang Soo and 37-years-old Kwang Soo...)
-有聯繫有聯繫 啊 好可怕
- It's not like that. - You're right.
(26-year-old Kwang Soo and 37-years-old Kwang Soo...)
-有聯繫 -有聯繫
- You're so meticulous. - No, it's just for my movie.
(26-year-old Kwang Soo and 37-years-old Kwang Soo...)
(still look the same except for his mustache.)
-不是不是 不是有聯繫的
- Today... - He's not usually like this.
(still look the same except for his mustache.)
I guess even the crew is sad that this is his last day.
有聯繫啊
呀今天編導人員們也依依不捨啊
Let's talk about Kwang Soo. This is his last day.
最後的錄播
(Starting things)
呀今天就說光洙吧
畢竟是光洙最後一天
No.
(Starting things)
啊 不是不是 這個哥
He didn't say a word when the cameras were off.
(Starting things)
攝影機不轉的時候一句話都不說
Once the camera was turned on,
攝影機一轉
he said, "This is Kwang Soo's last day,"
呀今天是光洙最後一天
(Once the camera starts rolling, Seok Jin talks.)
在拍攝第一集的地方拍呀
"so we're at the place where we shot the first episode."
(Once the camera starts rolling, Seok Jin talks.)
-安靜一點啊
Say "Feeling! Intuition! Cross!"
(Once the camera starts rolling, Seok Jin talks.)
(The big brother of Lee Jee Brothers never speaks without the camera.)
-哥在說話怎麼這樣呢
- He didn't even look into my eyes. - Seok Jin.
(The big brother of Lee Jee Brothers never speaks without the camera.)
-連眼神都不給
- Why would he do that? - Seok Jin, come over here.
(The big brother of Lee Jee Brothers never speaks without the camera.)
石鎮哥出來一下
- Why? - Don't stand next to him.
怎麼了怎麼了
(He's kicked out to prevent his further unnatural remarks.)
-別站他旁邊 -對
- Why do you suddenly care for him? - It's not like that.
(He's kicked out to prevent his further unnatural remarks.)
-幹嘛一直逼人啊 -沒關係
不是逼迫的
It's not sudden.
(He's kicked out to prevent his further unnatural remarks.)
(Big Nose gets more affectionate on Kwang Soo's last day.)
光洙懂我的心吧
- Kwang Soo, you know how I feel. - Of course I do.
(Big Nose gets more affectionate on Kwang Soo's last day.)
唉 哥
All right.
(Big Nose gets more affectionate on Kwang Soo's last day.)
Kwang Soo is about to end his 11 years on Running Man now.
所以光洙要結束11年的
(Kwang Soo will finish his 11 years on Running Man...)
Running Man
So we should send him out into the world.
(Kwang Soo will finish his 11 years on Running Man...)
(and move out into the world.)
我們要送到社會
Send him out to where?
(and move out into the world.)
你說送到哪裡 送到社會嗎
- It's not like... - Into the world?
(and move out into the world.)
(Kwang Soo goes out into the world where there are no missions.)
- I'm getting out of prison. - The thing is,
出獄嗎
(Kwang Soo goes out into the world where there are no missions.)
現在 以往11年中
For the past 11 years on Running Man,
(Kwang Soo goes out into the world where there are no missions.)
(For the past 11 years on Running Man, )
在Running Man
日常犯許多罪和行動的李光洙
Kwang Soo has committed lots of sins and mischievous acts.
(For the past 11 years on Running Man, )
(he's committed countless crimes.)
And we should reform him before he goes out into the world.
為了要弄乾淨後送到社會
(This race is to reform him before sending him out into the world.)
我們準備了再見我特別的兄弟比賽
So we prepared the Goodbye, My Special Brother Race.
(This race is to reform him before sending him out into the world.)
(Goodbye, Our Special Brother)
哇 我特殊的兄弟 考慮到電影了
"My Special Brother"? They referenced your movie title.
(Goodbye, Our Special Brother)
東九 對吧 東九
(Lee Kwang Soo, actor and comedian)
You played Dong Gu, right?
So we analyzed...
所以我們分析了
(Kwang Soo has been obsessed with missions for 11 years.)
what Kwang Soo has done over the past 11 years...
累積11年的李光洙的行為
(Kwang Soo has been obsessed with missions for 11 years.)
用罪行來判定的話
(If we were to judge his crimes...)
- to give him a verdict. - I see.
對對
(If we were to judge his crimes...)
由前法官 現任法務審議官
And we had a former judge...
(If we were to judge his crimes...)
(A former judge who's now...)
who is now a deputy director general of legal counsel review it.
(a deputy director general of legal counsel reviewed it.)
親自檢查會有什麼刑罰
- He will never be released. - Wouldn't he get a life sentence?
(a deputy director general of legal counsel reviewed it.)
-他出不來了
- He will never be released. - Wouldn't he get a life sentence?
-不是本來就這麼拍的嗎
(What is the punishment that suits his 11 years of eccentricity?)
- Do we have to go that far? - He will never be released.
-他出不來的 -做到這種程度嗎
(What is the punishment that suits his 11 years of eccentricity?)
Kwang Soo can't get out of prison.
-光洙以後上不了電視吧
(What is the punishment that suits his 11 years of eccentricity?)
-請播放視頻
- Please play the video. - He will be there for life.
(What is the punishment that suits his 11 years of eccentricity?)
(A monitor turns on in front of the members.)
-光洙以後上不了電視吧
First, please introduce yourself.
(A monitor turns on in front of the members.)
首先 請簡單介紹一下自己
我是以法官的身份工作十幾年的
Hello. I worked as a judge for about ten years.
(A monitor turns on in front of the members.)
(The former judge appears.)
鄭在民
My name is Jung Jae Min.
(The former judge appears.)
- He's a real judge. - He's a judge.
-真的法官 -鄭在民法官
(Jung Jae Min)
Why are you being so serious?
怎麼這麼認真的定罪
(Former judge, current deputy director general of legal counsel)
- Is he a real judge? - He's Judge Jung Jae Min.
是真的法官嗎
(A real judge appears to judge a petty criminal.)
對 鄭在民法官
- Is this serious? - Is he seriously...
(A real judge appears to judge a petty criminal.)
-哇 真的
- Is this serious? - Is he seriously...
(We will now weigh Kwang Soo's every crime.)
-怎麼這麼認真的定罪
He's a deputy director general of legal counsel and a writer now.
(We will now weigh Kwang Soo's every crime.)
-哦 原來是法務審議官
而且還是一位作者
(We will now weigh Kwang Soo's every crime.)
We've collected all the mischievous acts...
製作人翻找了559集的李光洙
(The filming crew analyzed all of Kwang Soo's behaviors...)
that Kwang Soo has committed over the 559 episodes...
所有行徑 按照我們的標準來劃分
(during the 559 episodes.)
- and classified it. - Okay.
(We categorized them by applying the standard of variety shows.)
嗯
- Property damage. - Right.
(We categorized them by applying the standard of variety shows.)
財物損壞
嗯
He committed it 58 times.
大概做了58次
(58 property damages)
58 times?
58次
(58 property damages)
哎呀 很多啊
- That's a lot. - He destroyed stuff.
(58 property damages)
跳神就是跳神
(Kwang Soo got carried away and destroyed a lot of props.)
- Hang on. - You can't do that.
哥 這要一起來啊
光洙
Kwang Soo.
58 times?
-58次 -真的好忽然
(He even kicked away the members' belongings.)
Look at what he's doing.
看你做的事情 這個真是
Who do you think I learned it from?
覺得這些都從誰身上學的
That's really...
這個真是
And he committed assault 353 times.
還有暴行353件
(353 assaults)
嗯
I got hit as well.
(353 assaults)
我也被打了
I got hit as well.
(He beat the members, )
(crew members, )
(and even citizens.)
He beat everyone.
都打了都打了
(He kicked, bit, and hit.)
- He hit Jong Kook a lot. - I got beaten a lot.
鐘國被打的最多
真的被他打了很多
- He hit Jong Kook a lot. - I got beaten a lot.
(He used every conceivable means to get his own way.)
And there's public indecency.
還有公演淫亂罪 37件
(37 public indecencies)
- He committed it 37 times. - Public indecency?
淫亂罪 啊 對
Oh, right.
(37 public indecencies)
- That's right. - That's what he did.
(He didn't take good care of his pants during the shoots.)
對 這個
- That was the best. - And there's fraud.
詐欺我們概括的較大
(Fraud including perjury, falsification, and default on loans)
嗯
- He committed it 1,812 times. - I see.
(Fraud including perjury, falsification, and default on loans)
有1812件
- He committed it 1,812 times. - I see.
(1812 times)
啊 好的
Actually, we just stopped counting because there were too many cases.
(1812 times)
這還是我們中途放棄的 因為太多
Actually, we just stopped counting because there were too many cases.
Aren't you Lee Kwang Soo?
你不是李光洙嗎
No. I saw him up there.
不是 在上面見過
(He kept lying and bluffing with no shame.)
在上面見過李光洙
I saw Kwang Soo up there.
(He kept lying and bluffing with no shame.)
You can't trust any man but me in the world.
這世界的男人全都一副德行 除了哥哥
一共拍了五百多集
He committed 1,812 frauds in about 500 episodes?
(We found 1812 frauds during the last 559 episodes.)
怎麼能做到1800件
Kwang Soo is the one who started forgery.
(We found 1812 frauds during the last 559 episodes.)
偽造其實光洙是第一個開始的
Kwang Soo is the one who started forgery.
(He even went through the crew members' bags to forge hints.)
Obstruction of justice, verbal abuse,
妨礙執行公務 地痞 威脅 敲詐
(Property damage, assault, public indecency, fraud, )
blackmail,
(bribery, illegal solicitation, theft, defamation, and insult)
- public disturbance... - Is this how we send him away?
這麼看光洙啊
(bribery, illegal solicitation, theft, defamation, and insult)
He's just a criminal.
不是 這不是壞蛋嗎
(A total of 3,353 crimes)
3353次
There are 3,353 cases.
(A total of 3,353 crimes)
(There have been 3,353 cases of his mischief.)
哇 好可怕
Gosh, this is terrifying.
(There have been 3,353 cases of his mischief.)
表情變陰沉了
- He looks serious now. - I know.
(There have been 3,353 cases of his mischief.)
對啊
So...
但是這個 是強制性壓制那人
(Former Judge Jung Jae Min analyzes...)
he used force...
(according to the filming crew's variety show standards.)
to take someone down.
但是這麼被搶的時候
When he loses something,
(according to the filming crew's variety show standards.)
(Additional crimes are revealed as we analyzed them.)
he'd grab something.
一般會抓什麼東西吧
(Additional crimes are revealed as we analyzed them.)
If he runs away... That's assault.
對準了 那就是變成暴行
(Additional crimes are revealed as we analyzed them.)
這是強盜 搶劫罪
It makes him a robber. It's a serious robbery.
(Additional crimes are revealed as we analyzed them.)
(Serious)
It makes him a robber. It's a serious robbery.
怎麼說呢 罪犯的性質很壞啊
The nature of the crime is quite serious.
"The nature of the crime is quite serious."
-說罪犯的性質很壞
(Laughing)
-罪犯的性質很壞
We were doing a TV show with a criminal.
(Laughing)
和犯罪者一起拍攝了呀
If that's the case, we are all criminals.
(Laughing)
(The variety show defendant, Lee Kwang Soo, is unstoppable.)
那麼算的話全都是罪犯吧
In the view of variety shows,
(The variety show defendant, Lee Kwang Soo, is unstoppable.)
首先按照演藝來看
In the view of variety shows,
what would be the sentence...
在這些罪中量刑的話
for the crimes he's committed?
大概是幾年左右
(He decides the sentence for Kwang Soo's crimes.)
節目 這樣不能上節目吧
Kwang Soo, you can't leave our show like this.
(He decides the sentence for Kwang Soo's crimes.)
Considering the nature of crimes and the degree of illegality...
罪犯的性質 或犯法程度
(A vast amount of and evil nature of 3,353 crimes)
還有次數 次數太多太多了
- And he's done it so many times. - I see.
(A vast amount of and evil nature of 3,353 crimes)
Considering all that,
包括這些的話被告人李光洙
the defendant, Lee Kwang Soo,
要服刑1050年
is sentenced to 1,050 years in prison.
- What? - What? 1,050 years?
1050年
- Seriously? - Take him.
抓出去 這個給抓走
(Punishment was added as he was a habitual offender.)
Arrest him.
你不行啊 抓走
We can't let him go. Catch him.
(Punishment was added as he was a habitual offender.)
-500 540 -540
- In about 500 episodes... - In the 559 episodes...
(Punishment was added as he was a habitual offender.)
(He becomes a sinner of a 1,050-year sentence.)
你結束了 結束了
Hey, Kwang Soo.
(He becomes a sinner of a 1,050-year sentence.)
You're done for. You're doomed.
- 1,000 years? - Catch him.
1000年
How would he serve 1,000 years?
According to the consultation with the former judge,
(Based on the former judge's advice, )
就這樣 前法官諮詢結果
(Kwang Soo is sentenced to 1,050 years in prison.)
Kwang Soo is sentenced to 1,050 years in prison.
目前為止李光洙犯過的最
大概服刑1050年
(Kwang Soo is sentenced to 1,050 years in prison.)
In order to get Kwang Soo out of prison,
成員們為了罪犯李光洙的出獄
(To help Kwang Soo be released from prison, )
執行適應社會訓練和教化任務
the members will perform missions to reform and train Kwang Soo.
(To help Kwang Soo be released from prison, )
(the members must perform missions to reform and train Kwang Soo.)
Before the three reform sessions come to an end at 6:30pm,
在第三個教化時間結束的
(Before 6:30pm when the three reformation sessions are over, )
6點30分為止全部減刑才能成功
the members have to reduce his sentence.
(Before 6:30pm when the three reformation sessions are over, )
(the members have to reduce his sentence.)
- Over 1,000... - You have to get rid of...
要減慢1050年才行
(the members have to reduce his sentence.)
all 1,050 years.
- It will be tough. - If you fail to do so,
(the members have to reduce his sentence.)
減刑失敗時 全員懲罰
- It will be tough. - If you fail to do so,
you all will get a penalty.
(If they fail, they all get the penalty.)
Since this is Kwang Soo's last day,
慶祝光洙最後的拍攝
(The filming crew has a variety of gifts as it's his last day.)
製作人準備了各種各樣的禮物
we prepared various gifts for Kwang Soo as well.
(The filming crew has a variety of gifts as it's his last day.)
Really?
真的嗎
(The filming crew has a variety of gifts as it's his last day.)
每次減刑150年時
Every time you get rid of 150 years,
(The filming crew has a variety of gifts as it's his last day.)
(Every time they get rid of 150 years, )
會給李光洙提供福不福禮物挑選機會
Kwang Soo will get a chance to draw lots to pick his gift.
(Every time they get rid of 150 years, )
(Kwang Soo will get a chance to draw lots to pick his gift.)
還有今天總共有3處教化地點
And there will be three venues for his reformation.
(Kwang Soo will get a chance to draw lots to pick his gift.)
(The 3 venues for his reformation...)
We had a pre-interview with Kwang Soo...
我們提前採訪李光洙的時候
(The 3 venues for his reformation...)
再融入社會之前
and decided three places that he wants to visit...
(The 3 venues for his reformation...)
(are the places he wanted to be with the members...)
想跟跑男成員們一起度過的場所組成
with the members before his release.
(are the places he wanted to be with the members...)
(as mentioned in his pre-interview.)
And in order to commemorate your happy memories today,
為了包裝今天的回憶
(A professional photographer will take photos during the shoot.)
在錄製節目的期間會有專門的攝影師拍大家
a professional photographer will take photos of you.
(A professional photographer will take photos during the shoot.)
會給我們拍照啊
There he is.
(A professional photographer will take photos during the shoot.)
會給我們拍照啊
There he is.
(Photographer, Kim Eui Kyum)
最後會將今天拍的照片當作禮物送給大家
You will get the photos at the end of the show.
(Photographer, Kim Eui Kyum)
- We all get the photos? - Yes.
-每個人都會得到嗎 -是的
You will get the photos at the end of the show.
最後會將今天拍的照片當作禮物送給大家
(The members start posing for the photos immediately.)
-每個人都會得到嗎 -是的
- We all get the photos? - Yes.
(The members start posing for the photos immediately.)
好贊
That's cool.
(The members start posing for the photos immediately.)
(Actually, the members are hiding some secret today.)
- Hello. - Hello.
-大家好 -大家好
(1 hour before today's shoot)
PD您好
Hello.
(1 hour before today's shoot)
因為光洙是今天的主人公
Is Kwang Soo coming late since he's the main character today?
(1 hour before today's shoot)
(The members came 1 hour earlier than Kwang Soo.)
-所以他會晚來嗎 -是這樣嗎
今天是跟李光洙一起錄製的最後一天
Today is our last day with Kwang Soo.
(The members came 1 hour earlier than Kwang Soo.)
- Right. - Kwang Soo doesn't know about this.
(They came in early without letting Kwang Soo know.)
李光洙還不清楚現在的狀況
所以他以為今天會在12點進行錄製
He thinks we will start at noon.
(They came in early without letting Kwang Soo know.)
-是嗎 -因此他正在做準備吧
- Really? - So he's getting ready now.
(They came in early without letting Kwang Soo know.)
節目組兼顧了成員們的心意
And the crew members...
(They came in early without letting Kwang Soo know.)
prepared special gifts...
(The filming crew prepared a gift for Kwang Soo...)
為了光洙準備了多種特別的禮物
for Kwang Soo with the members' sincere hearts.
(The filming crew prepared a gift for Kwang Soo...)
(with the members' love included.)
在進行任務期間
During the missions,
(with the members' love included.)
Kwang Soo will get the gifts...
會通過各位和李光洙的配合
by drawing lots with your help.
通過挑選福不福讓光洙獲得禮物
- Really? - Here are the gifts.
是嗎
禮物的種類是最高級香檳唐‧佩裡儂
The premium champagne, Dom Perignon.
(Today's gifts: Dom Perignon, )
- My gosh. - We know that.
當然知道這個品牌
(Today's gifts: Dom Perignon, )
還有
And a brand-name hoodie.
(Today's gifts: Dom Perignon, )
還有名牌連帽衛衣
And a brand-name hoodie.
(a brand hooded t-shirt, )
- Bal-something? - Yes. Bal-something.
巴黎世家嗎
(a brand hooded t-shirt, )
絕了
- That's amazing. - It starts with Bal.
(a brand hooded t-shirt, )
是巴黎
And a brand-name bag,
(a brand hooded t-shirt, )
還有名牌包包 還有很潮的褲子
And a brand-name bag,
(a brand-name bag, )
pants, a decorative picture frame,
(trendy pants, ) an interior picture frame,
裝飾畫框 高性能音響 最高級床品套裝
a sound bar, and a bedding set. This is what we prepared.
(a high-performance soundbar, and bedding at its finest)
準備了這些禮物
禮物好多啊
但會根據任務結果會獲得不同的禮物吧
But he can only receive them if he succeeds.
(a high-performance soundbar, and bedding at its finest)
(But all of these gifts will be distributed randomly.)
各位要通過任務
You will help Kwang Soo get...
(But all of these gifts will be distributed randomly.)
儘量讓李光洙獲得這些全部禮物
You will help Kwang Soo get...
(The mission for the 7 members)
as many gifts as possible through the missions.
(Help Kwang Soo win as many gifts as possible.)
我們嗎
- We'll help him? - I see.
(Help Kwang Soo win as many gifts as possible.)
又
此外成員們也可通過隱藏任務
You will also have a chance to get the same gifts as Kwang Soo...
(Help Kwang Soo win as many gifts as possible.)
獲得跟光洙獲得的禮物相同的禮物
You will also have a chance to get the same gifts as Kwang Soo...
(Members can also win the same gifts...)
- through hidden missions. - Really?
(through hidden missions.)
我也可以獲得禮物嗎
- I can get gifts too? - Then we have a reason to help him.
(through hidden missions.)
如果這樣 那我們會認真做啊
要認真做啊
可以獲得巴黎世家嗎
- I can get a hoodie from B brand? - Yes.
(through hidden missions.)
(Tempted)
-OK -我也想穿那個連帽衛衣
- Okay. - I always wanted a designer hoodie.
(Tempted)
Throughout today's shoot,
所以在進行錄製的期間
(Hidden missions for members to win prizes)
我們邀請了專門的攝影師
a professional photographer that we hired...
(Hidden missions for members to win prizes)
(A professional photographer will take photos all day.)
那位會用膠卷攝像機一整天拍攝好看的照片
will take photos of you using a film camera.
(A professional photographer will take photos all day.)
我喜歡膠卷攝像機
Kwang Soo likes photos taken with a film camera.
(A professional photographer will take photos all day.)
-OK -但是
You will be ranked in the order of the number of photos...
(A professional photographer will take photos all day.)
會通過跟李光洙同框的照片數量決定排名
You will be ranked in the order of the number of photos...
(The mission is to take as many photos as they can with Kwang Soo.)
taken with Kwang Soo.
The person in the first place...
(The mission is to take as many photos as they can with Kwang Soo.)
第1名可以跟光洙一起獲得所有的禮物
will get the same gifts as Kwang Soo.
(The mission is to take as many photos as they can with Kwang Soo.)
(The person with the highest number of photos with Kwang Soo...)
That's awesome.
絕了
(will get all the gifts with Kwang Soo.)
但倒數第1名會有嚴厲的懲罰
But the person in the bottom place will get a terrible penalty.
(will get all the gifts with Kwang Soo.)
(But the person in the last place will get a terrible penalty.)
為什麼今天要有懲罰呢
Why would any of us get a penalty on a day like this?
(But the person in the last place will get a terrible penalty.)
是大家特別厭惡的地方
The penalty can be a hassle and scary at the same time.
(The penalty can be a hassle and scary at the same time.)
厭煩和恐怖共存的地方
It's crossing the sky bridge that is 541m high,
(The penalty can be a hassle and scary at the same time.)
在世界最高處541m上空
It's crossing the sky bridge that is 541m high,
(It's crossing the sky bridge that is 541m high, )
(the highest in the world, )
一邊欣賞著首爾全貌 一邊走過天橋
the highest in the world,
(the highest in the world, )
(where you can enjoy the whole view of Seoul.)
where you can enjoy the whole view of Seoul.
Hey, Seok Jin will cry.
(where you can enjoy the whole view of Seoul.)
如果這樣他會哭啊
Hey, Seok Jin will cry.
(They need to take as many photos as possible to avoid the penalty!)
又會哭嗎
- He'll cry again? - Yes, he will.
(They need to take as many photos as possible to avoid the penalty!)
又會哭
- He'll cry again? - Yes, he will.
Seok Jin, come over here.
石鎮哥 您來這邊
(So they started fighting to stand next to Kwang Soo.)
-為什麼 -別站在他身邊
- Why? - Don't stand next to him.
(So they started fighting to stand next to Kwang Soo.)
-對啊 -我站在那邊
- Right. - I don't understand.
(So they started fighting to stand next to Kwang Soo.)
為什麼突然要站在光洙的身旁
Why do you suddenly act all friendly standing next to Kwang Soo?
(So they started fighting to stand next to Kwang Soo.)
- You know how I feel, right? - Of course, Seok Jin.
光洙 你瞭解我的心意吧
知道
Hey, So Min, you stand here.
-你過來 -站在光洙的身旁
(They all tried to stand next to Kwang Soo.)
好 你站這邊吧
Right, Ji Hyo. Come stand here.
(They all tried to stand next to Kwang Soo.)
(They continued to accumulate photos with Kwang Soo.)
I mean, why suddenly...
為什麼突然...
(They continued to accumulate photos with Kwang Soo.)
有540億韓元嗎
- 54 million dollars? - How much money do you have?
(They continued to accumulate photos with Kwang Soo.)
你現在有多少啊
- What? - How much money do you have?
(Likewise, the 7 members' rankings kept changing.)
沒多少
- I don't have much money. - 1,000 years is too long.
(Likewise, the 7 members' rankings kept changing.)
-怎麼會有1000億韓元啊 -你現在
- Pay for it before you leave. - 54 million dollars...
(Likewise, the 7 members' rankings kept changing.)
如果有540億韓元的話 你現在
會有專業的攝影師給大家拍照
A professional photographer will take photos of you today.
(Likewise, the 7 members' rankings kept changing.)
- There. He's taking photos of us. - I see him.
正在那邊拍照啊
(Who will be the winner of all gifts with Kwang Soo...)
最後會將今天拍的照片作為禮物送給大家
We'll give you the photos as a gift.
(Who will be the winner of all gifts with Kwang Soo...)
(by taking the most photos with Kwang Soo?)
人人有份嗎
- Will all of us get photos? Nice. - Yes.
(by taking the most photos with Kwang Soo?)
-是的 -挺好
在移動到下個目的地之前
We'll do the first mission to reduce the sentence right here.
(by taking the most photos with Kwang Soo?)
(The first mission to reduce the sentence.)
開始可以減刑的任務
啊 一開始
From the beginning?
(The first mission to reduce the sentence.)
I'm worried.
去那邊吧 今天你被拍了很多次
(They're only into taking photos.)
- All right. - Go on.
今天你被拍了很多次
You've done a lot.
(They're only into taking photos.)
第一個任務是光洙早就知道
The first mission is...
(They're only into taking photos.)
(While the rankings are changing, the 1st mission begins.)
Kwang Soo Knows.
(The 1st mission, Kwang Soo Knows)
In 1 of the 2 boxes in front of you,
目前有兩個抽選盒子
(Numbers, Keywords)
顯示時機的提示語
there are keywords that indicate a certain time...
(Numbers, Keywords)
打個比方 今早之類的
such as "this morning".
(Numbers, Keywords)
(Keywords: Last Night, This Year, 20s, This Morning, Last Year)
such as "this morning".
另一個盒子中有數字1到7
(Numbers from 1 to 7)
In the other box,
- there are numbers from 1 to 7. - I see.
(Numbers from 1 to 7)
好的
李光洙要親自各挑選一個
Kwang Soo, pick one out of each box...
(Numbers from 1 to 7)
(Kwang Soo will pick one ball from each box.)
按照抽到的數字
and ask a question to which the same number...
(Kwang Soo will pick one ball from each box.)
選擇成員數量並製作相關的問題
of the member as the number you picked can say yes.
(Kwang Soo will pick one ball from each box.)
(He'll have to ask a question to which the same number...)
of the member as the number you picked can say yes.
(of the member as the number picked can say yes.)
提問時要包含提示語
You must include the keyword in your question.
(of the member as the number picked can say yes.)
That is, you succeed if the number of the members...
打個比方 聽到提問以後
who say yes to the question equals the number that you picked.
跟這個問題相關的成員舉手的數量
一致的話便成功
- Gosh, you punk. - He's taking a photo of us.
啊 你這傢伙
(Acting innocently)
啊 正在拍照啊
正在拍照啊
- He's taking a photo of us. - Gosh.
(Acting innocently)
看前面
- He's taking a photo of us. - Gosh.
(An abrupt photo time)
1 2
1, 2.
(An abrupt photo time)
Goodbye, Kwang Soo.
走好
(In the end, they got 1 photo where all 8 of them appear.)
- Okay. - Okay.
OK
(In the end, they got 1 photo where all 8 of them appear.)
我們回去吧
聽我打的比方吧
- Please listen to me. - Okay.
(In the end, they got 1 photo where all 8 of them appear.)
- Kwang Soo will ask a question. - Yes.
李光洙會進行提問
(It's a success if the number picked by Kwang Soo...)
聽到提問以後
And those of you that the question applies to...
(It's a success if the number picked by Kwang Soo...)
只跟這個問題相關的成員
And those of you that the question applies to...
(is the same as the number of people who said yes...)
從座位上站起來吧
will stand up.
(is the same as the number of people who said yes...)
(to a question Kwang Soo asked.)
但站起來的人數跟李光洙挑選的數字
You succeed if the same number of you as he picked stand up.
(to a question Kwang Soo asked.)
吻合的話便成功
- I see. - Okay. I get it.
(to a question Kwang Soo asked.)
OK
知道了
(to a question Kwang Soo asked.)
每次答對一個問題時就減刑50年
50 years will be deducted for each question you succeed.
(to a question Kwang Soo asked.)
(50 years will be deducted each time they succeed.)
50年嗎
- 50 years? - Okay, okay.
(50 years will be deducted each time they succeed.)
光洙哥 你知道我們的風格啊
- Kwang Soo, you know us well. - We can just succeed three times.
(50 years will be deducted each time they succeed.)
(The key is to make a good question that the number of members...)
只要成功3次就可以了
按照我們的風格進行吧
Since you know us well, just go for it.
(The key is to make a good question that the number of members...)
(who'll say yes equals the number that he picks from the box.)
光速進行吧
- Be confident. - Right.
(who'll say yes equals the number that he picks from the box.)
李光洙先抽選提示語吧
Kwang Soo, please choose the keyword first.
(who'll say yes equals the number that he picks from the box.)
(Keywords, Numbers)
Kwang Soo, please choose the keyword first.
(Kwang Soo will choose the keyword for the question.)
Please show us the keyword you picked.
公開提示語吧
Thank you. Now choose the number.
(Keyword, Last Night)
接著抽選數字吧
(Number, 1)
Now make a question that starts with the keyword...
根據這一數字和提示語製作問題吧
(Number, 1)
and would apply to that number of members.
(The question has to begin with "last night"...)
這個有點難搞啊
This is difficult.
(The question has to begin with "last night"...)
(and apply to only 1 member.)
Come on! Hurry up!
-趕緊的 趕緊的 -OK
- Last night, - Last night...
昨晚
-昨晚 -昨晚
which of you went to the gym?
去了健身房的人是
Which of you went to the gym last night?
昨晚去了健身房的人是
1, 2, 3.
1 2 3
(He aimed to make Jong Kook get up as he goes to the gym every day.)
1, 2, 3.
1 2 3
(If no one but Jong Kook stands up, 50 years will be deducted.)
- You failed. - Jong Kook, wasn't it you?
失敗
-鐘國昨晚沒去健身房嗎 -哥 您沒去健身房嗎
- Didn't you go last night? - I went to the gym early yesterday.
-沒去嗎 -我昨天去得早
I'm not lying, Kwang Soo. Believe me.
真的 光洙 我真的去得早
(Walking toward him)
-昨晚 -昨晚沒去
- I went to the gym early. - He didn't go there at night.
(Walking toward him)
應該說成前天去健身房的人
- You should've said "yesterday". - Right.
(Walking toward him)
是啊
- You should've said "yesterday". - Right.
(He's making a pose for an easier photo.)
雖然是昨天去的 但不是晚上去的
- But the keyword is "last night". - He went to the gym in the morning.
(He's making a pose for an easier photo.)
去健身房的人只有鐘國啊
- Kwang Soo. - Why don't you know that about him?
(He's making a pose for an easier photo.)
你為什麼這麼不瞭解鐘國啊
- Kwang Soo. - Why don't you know that about him?
- Why don't you know that? - He goes there on Sunday evening.
-你為什麼這麼不瞭解我 -哥
(He did what he came for.)
您一般都是晚上去的啊
-打住 看向前面 -他一般都是晚上去的
(He did what he came for.)
- Drop it and turn around. - He often goes to the gym at night.
- Hey, you made him a little upset. - That was disappointing.
(He did what he came for.)
-有點令人傷心 -有點傷心啊
- Hey, you made him a little upset. - That was disappointing.
(The rest of the crowd is busy complaining.)
It was disappointing.
好傷心
(The rest of the crowd is busy complaining.)
這 會讓人感到傷心
Is it something that could make you upset?
(The rest of the crowd is busy complaining.)
Kwang Soo failed this time.
-對啊 -李光洙這次沒有答對
(It's time for the second question.)
挑選下一個吧
Please move on.
(It's time for the second question.)
再稍微集中精神 嗯
- Try to focus, okay? - Right. Focus.
(It's time for the second question.)
集中精神
- Okay. - Try to be more cheerful.
對 對
提高興致
Make it look funny when you pick balls out of the boxes.
挑選球的時候也做得有趣一點
Smile a little while doing that.
抽的時候要面帶笑容
- Do something like this. - Exactly.
抽選球的時候應該做這種動作
(He can't get energetic as it's his last day.)
-要有活力啊 -是啊
-好樣的 -很好
Make it funny. That's good.
(He can't get energetic as it's his last day.)
- Yes. That's good. - Good job. That's better.
(Petty Kwang Soo's In-between Show)
提升氛圍
今天是最後一次啊
- This is your last time here. - Get as much air time as you can.
(Petty Kwang Soo's In-between Show)
-好樣的 -傾注所有能量
Pour out all you have!
傾注所有能量
(They told him off harshly for making it boring.)
- Okay. - Let's go. What's the keyword?
趕緊的 前面的到底是什麼問題
(Keyword, Last Night, Number, 2)
- Last night... - Last night!
昨晚
-昨晚 -昨晚
- They might switch the channels! - Wait. Give me a second.
人們快要換頻道了
(Pressuring)
等等 等等
人們快要換頻道了
They'll switch the channels!
(Pressuring)
(Those who love high energy are bursting with complaints.)
等等
- Just a moment. - This is a weekend variety show.
(Those who love high energy are bursting with complaints.)
這可是週末綜藝啊
-這個寂靜是什麼鬼啊 -不會
What's with this silence?
- They'll see "Boss in the Mirror". - No, no, no.
人們會換到老闆的耳朵是驢耳朵節目
(The rival program aired at the same time)
-不行 -人們會換頻道了
- No! Stay tuned! - They'll watch another show.
(The rival program aired at the same time)
別換頻道 別看 別看
- Don't watch that show! - Right.
(He started saying the question hastily not to lose viewers.)
昨晚
- Last night, - Last night.
(He started saying the question hastily not to lose viewers.)
昨晚
Which of you skipped dinner?
沒吃晚飯的人是
Which of you skipped dinner last night?
昨晚沒吃晚飯的人是
(2 people must stand up.)
1, 2, 3.
-我們會沒吃嗎 -那個哥
- You know we would never do that. - Dinner?
(2 people must stand up.)
Turn around.
回頭看吧
(No one stood up.)
- What's wrong with you? - All of you had dinner?
-幹嘛那樣 -都吃了嗎
(No one stood up.)
- Isn't it obvious? - Why would any of us skip dinner?
當然啊
(No one stood up.)
為什麼沒吃晚飯
- Hey. - I didn't get to eat dinner.
(No one stood up.)
- Why? - How could you skip dinner?
我沒吃
晚飯
- What's the number? - Two.
(His second attempt failed due to his selfishness.)
-不吃晚飯怎麼活啊 -多少人
2人 2人
Did you think we were too sad because of you to eat dinner?
(His second attempt failed due to his selfishness.)
怎麼 你以為我們會因為你走人
Did you think we were too sad because of you to eat dinner?
(Cold)
心痛到吃不下晚飯嗎
No, I didn't think that.
(Cold)
不是不是
No, I didn't think that.
(Putting the complaints behind, it's now his third attempt.)
這個
- I can't believe... - Let's just drop it.
(Putting the complaints behind, it's now his third attempt.)
-別做了 -這是容易的啊
- It was an easy one. - I'm sorry. I'll do better.
(Putting the complaints behind, it's now his third attempt.)
抱歉抱歉
Okay. Move on to the third question.
(Putting the complaints behind, it's now his third attempt.)
第三個
(Keyword, Last year)
然後請抽取數字
Next, choose the number.
(Keyword, Last year)
(Number, 1)
Let's do this.
走起走起
(Number, 1)
Let's reduce the sentence.
減少刑期吧
(He's thinking hard and carefully.)
Hey, Kwang Soo, it's getting boring. Hurry up.
光洙啊 沒勁兒了 麻溜的麻溜的
Got it.
知道了知道了
- This is difficult. - Hurry up!
-這個好難 真的好難 -快點
- This is a weekend show! - I'm sorry.
-這是週末啊 -抱歉抱歉
Just give up if it's so difficult, you punk.
難就別做了 小子
- Pardon? - I said, just give up.
(The two Grand Prize winners are harsh to the last moment.)
-什麼 -別做了
"It's getting boring." That was funny.
(The two Grand Prize winners are harsh to the last moment.)
沒勁兒了
- Last year, - Last year?
-在去年 -去年
- Okay. - which of you bought a new car?
買了車的人
(Expected number of members, 1)
Which of you bought a new car last year?
在去年買了車的人 123
(Expected number of members, 1)
1, 2, 3.
- What? Last year? - I bought a new car.
(Expected number of members, 1)
-去年 -我換車了
- Success. - Okay!
成功
OK
- Success. - Okay!
(Finally, he got 50 years deducted from his sentence.)
-怎麼會 -是想到我了嗎
- How did he pull it off? - Did you think of me?
(Finally, he got 50 years deducted from his sentence.)
Yes, I did.
嗯
- The SUV? - Give him a hug!
嘉年華車
哥 抱一個抱一個
- The SUV? - Give him a hug!
(You remembered!)
I'm impressed.
厲害了
(You remembered!)
Give him a hug.
抱一個
(You remembered!)
(Hugging)
他是知道的 抽到了數字1
I'm so touched.
(Hugging)
He knew it. He picked number one.
(The photographer was taking a photo.)
And he knew Haha was the only one who bought a new car.
只有一個人買車了
(You're right! I bought a car.)
因為多生了一個娃
I had another child. That's why.
(You're right! I bought a car.)
- He knew it. - Hey, come back.
-喂喂喂喂 -過來
(He's using emotions to get more photos.)
- Stop it. - Go back to your seat, Haha!
過來
(He's using emotions to get more photos.)
- Hey, hey. - Why are you trying to make...
-回來 小不點回來 -喂喂
- people cry already? - Don't make us cry already.
(He's not allowed to cry early on.)
這麼快就開始搞感動啊
不要這麼快開始擠眼淚
- Don't look up at the sky. - Don't do that.
(He's not allowed to cry early on.)
(Haha's face is getting ready to cry.)
-幹嘛這樣 -不要看天空
別擠眼淚 別擠眼淚
Don't make us cry.
(Haha's face is getting ready to cry.)
(Crying)
答對了
I pulled it off.
(Crying)
不要勉強
- Don't make it unnatural. - I pulled it off.
(Crying)
答對了
By the way, Kwang Soo did a great job.
但是好帥啊 光洙哥
(He is on a roll to get out of jail!)
You could be released from prison alive.
好好做的話 能活下來啊
(He is on a roll to get out of jail!)
能吃上豆腐了 (韓國出獄時會吃豆腐)
You can eat tofu to celebrate it.
(He is on a roll to get out of jail!)
(He tries his fourth question.)
Get more years deducted, Kwang Soo. Please.
多減點吧 哥 拜託了
(Keyword, This Year, Number, 2)
I'm sorry to say this, but I can't watch Running Man this week.
真的不好意思
這周的RM我是看不下去了
Gosh, it's not that bad.
幹嘛那樣
Are you trying to ruin the show because you're leaving?
I'm not trying to ruin the show.
你因為要走人了就在搗亂嗎
(We might get the lowest ratings on his last day on the show.)
- Why is it taking so long? - I can...
-看不下去了 -不是在搗亂
- I can do this... - He looks like a donkey.
你是要去另一個節目嗎
(Saying nonsense)
這麼一看那個哥長得像驢啊
Could he plan to join "Boss in the Mirror"?
(Saying nonsense)
你是想去驢嗎 長得像驢啊
Could he plan to join "Boss in the Mirror"?
(Breaking News: Is Kwang Soo joining the rival program?)
- Oh, right. - Could he join the show?
- Why would they accuse me of that? - Are you leaving our show...
(Breaking News: Is Kwang Soo joining the rival program?)
你是要去另一個節目嗎
- Why would they accuse me of that? - Are you leaving our show...
- to join another show? - I bet it's "Boss in the Mirror"...
你這個 你是想去別的節目
(Yang Se Chan, a short-tempered informant)
你是想去驢吧
seeing that you look like a donkey.
(Yang Se Chan, a short-tempered informant)
-不是 -看你長得像驢
- What's this? - I'm upset.
(Yang Se Chan, a short-tempered informant)
-在搗亂呢 -令人不悅
(The spy is caught red-handed.)
- I'll do better this time. - Try to pick a large number.
真的是
(The spy is caught red-handed.)
-隨便說吧 -你要有點sense啊
- I'll do it faster from now on. - Use your sense of humor.
(The spy is caught red-handed.)
-OKOK 我會做到的 -犯規啊
- This year, - This year.
-今年 -今年
Which of you haven't won any awards yet?
還沒拿到獎的人
(Expected number of members, 5)
不是飯桌這些
- Not like a toy? - A real award given at a ceremony.
(Expected number of members, 5)
-頒獎禮上的真的獎 -真的獎
- A real award? - Like a prize?
(Expected number of members, 5)
真的獎盃
No awards ceremonies have been held as it's the beginning of the year.
(Expected number of members, 5)
還沒拿到的人 因為這還是年初呢
Now turn around.
(Expected number of members, 5)
-回頭看吧 -OK
Now turn around.
(Successful)
- Okay! - Five of us stood up.
5個人
(Deducted 50 years, Current sentence is 950 years)
- A real award? - Yes, a real award.
真的獎
(Deducted 50 years, Current sentence is 950 years)
開過車的人
This year, has anyone driven?
(Deducted 50 years, Current sentence is 950 years)
(He continued the momentum...)
(and succeeded again.)
OK 6人
- Okay! - Six of us got up.
(and succeeded again.)
- I do but I don't have a car. - Kwang Soo.
怎麼
很好
- That one was heart-warming. - Because you don't have a car?
-因為沒有車 -光洙哥
It was heart-warming. Good job.
-這次的有些溫暖 -沒有車就沒開過車嗎
(He's getting compliments instead.)
-做得好 -不過
這次做得好
I admit it was a good one.
(He's getting compliments instead.)
這次的很溫暖
- It was heart-warming. - Indeed.
(He's getting compliments instead.)
是啊
Kwang Soo, it was heart-warming.
光洙哥 這次的有些溫暖
- As a result, - Yes.
就這樣
(He was able to deduct 150 years.)
正好減刑了150年
He got exactly 150 years deducted,
(He was able to deduct 150 years.)
先開始第一個禮物福不福
he's going to choose gifts at random.
(He was able to deduct 150 years.)
(He gets a chance for a gift for every 150 years deducted.)
- Right now? - Yes, we'll begin now.
馬上嗎 馬上嗎
(He gets a chance for a gift for every 150 years deducted.)
The first gift is a designer bag.
第一個禮物是名牌包包
(The first gift is a designer bag.)
1 of the 2 eggs is raw, and the other is boiled.
兩個中一個是生雞蛋
(Designer bag)
另一個是煮雞蛋
You'll receive the gift if you pick the hard-boiled egg.
(Designer bag)
是煮雞蛋就獲得禮物
You'll receive the gift if you pick the hard-boiled egg.
(Boiled egg, Wins the gift, Raw egg, Dud)
是生雞蛋就是咣
You will get nothing if you pick the raw egg.
(Boiled egg, Wins the gift, Raw egg, Dud)
-很難啊 -光洙啊 試試看
- It's hard to figure out. - Kwang Soo, go for it.
(Boiled egg, Wins the gift, Raw egg, Dud)
- Kwang Soo. - Go ahead.
-光洙啊 -試試看
Kwang Soo, pick one.
光洙 選吧
- I choose this one. - Good. I would choose that one too.
我選這個
(He immediately chooses the 1st egg.)
-是啊 我也選那個 -感覺不是那個
- Break it on your forehead. - I picked the same one.
(He immediately chooses the 1st egg.)
打在額頭上吧
-我也選那個 -我也選那個
- Me too. - I'm worried since I picked it too.
(He immediately chooses the 1st egg.)
(Everyone is not comfortable with the 1st egg.)
我也選那個 這句話有些不安
Let's stay away from him.
(Everyone is not comfortable with the 1st egg.)
離遠一些吧
- I picked it too, Kwang Soo. - Come on.
(Everyone is not comfortable with the 1st egg.)
我也選那個 光洙
- I picked it too, Kwang Soo. - Come on.
我也選那個
- I picked the same one. - If that's a hard-boiled egg...
(The first gift depends on the 1st egg!)
所以是煮雞蛋就是好的嗎
If it's a hard-boiled egg, he'll get the designer bag right away.
(The first gift depends on the 1st egg!)
是煮雞蛋就馬上獲得名牌包包
OK
- Right away? - Yes.
(The first gift depends on the 1st egg!)
-馬上嗎 -嗯
- I had a good feeling about it. - Let's go.
就是這個 我就選這個
(Breaking the egg)
(It was a boiled egg!)
- That's amazing. - Oh, my.
怎麼回事
(It was a boiled egg!)
- This can't be right. - He's already reformed.
他不能這樣的啊
(Everyone's staying close to him at the news of a designer bag.)
變好了變好了
- It's hard to believe. - Hey, you're leaving the show.
(Everyone's staying close to him at the news of a designer bag.)
馬上要走人了
- You should've failed. - People will switch the channel.
(Everyone's staying close to him at the news of a designer bag.)
給我嗎
- You should've failed. - People will switch the channel.
大家會換台的
You got the designer bag.
(Kwang Soo wins a designer bag!)
-厲害了 -獲得名牌包包
Okay!
(Kwang Soo wins a designer bag!)
-真的嗎 -OK
Okay!
- Hey, this is not right. - Hey.
- You should've chosen to be funny. - People will switch the channel.
你不能這樣啊
你都要走人了
- You should've chosen to be funny. - People will switch the channel.
(The spy is messing up with the random game too.)
得做得有趣些才行啊 這是什麼
不是這樣的
- I was just... - What's wrong with you?
(The spy is messing up with the random game too.)
Kwang Soo told us about the food...
在李光洙去社會之前
有想和成員們一起吃的食物
Kwang Soo told us about the food...
(Kwang Soo asked about the food...)
he wanted to eat with you guys before going back to society.
(he wanted to eat with the members before going back to society.)
是嗎
We'll move to the location to eat it.
(he wanted to eat with the members before going back to society.)
真的嗎
We'll move to the location to eat it.
現在出發去吃那個吧
(It's time to eat the last meal.)
- Let's go! - Okay.
走吧
(It's time to eat the last meal.)
Kwang Soo, please change into a prison uniform.
李光洙請換成囚服
A prison uniform?
(A prison uniform has been prepared for him.)
光洙有想和我們一起吃的食物啊
I didn't know that there was food that he wanted to eat with us.
(A prison uniform has been prepared for him.)
Jae Seok, can you drive?
這裡嗎
在錫哥開一下車吧
Of course. I'll drive.
好好 當然
(Jumping)
哥 不是去開車嗎
Jae Seok, why would you hop on my back?
(Jumping)
為什麼
Jae Seok, why would you hop on my back?
(He'll drive Kwang Soo instead of a car.)
- Why? - When will I get to do this again?
還能什麼時候被背呢
- Jae Seok. - Right?
Please take me to the driver's seat.
你帶哥到駕駛座吧
還能有誰背我呢
Who will give me a piggyback ride after you leave?
Are you giving him a piggyback ride for the last time?
最後一次背你嗎
(It's not even that far, )
是我讓他背我的
I got on his back.
(It's not even that far, )
所以啊 就是光洙背你
I know. I was talking to him.
(It's not even that far, )
(but Jae Seok's making an excuse to get his piggyback ride.)
Thank you, Kwang Soo.
-謝謝你 光洙 -不客氣 哥
That's okay, Jae Seok.
(but Jae Seok's making an excuse to get his piggyback ride.)
(Kwang Soo feels happy after his last ride for Jae Seok.)
Did everyone put on their seatbelts?
好 扣安全帶了嗎
- Yes! - Yes, I did.
-嗯 -嗯 扣了
I drive aggressively at times.
有時開車比較粗魯
(They're leaving while chatting as always.)
-左轉右轉會飛出去 -不要搞得那麼麻煩
- Don't cause us trouble. - I do that when making turns.
(They're leaving while chatting as always.)
(And Jae Seok is driving as always.)
3991號
- By the way, - Why me?
我們是去吃什麼
昨天看到 昭旻..
- By the way, - Why me?
(For the past 11 years, )
I realized that So Min... Did you guys notice it too?
你們感受到了嗎
(they felt natural in a crowded car.)
Have you ever seen a secret royal emissary?
哥 你有見過暗行御史嗎
(they felt natural in a crowded car.)
You saw her for the 1st time, and this is your 2nd time, right?
你那次是第一次見秀賢
(It felt natural...)
這次是第二次吧
- Do you have a crush on me? - No.
(It felt natural...)
哥 你喜歡我嗎
- Do you have a crush on me? - No.
(that Jae Seok drove all the time.)
I would even lend you money.
哥叫我借錢的話 我會借的
(Kwang Soo always sat at the passenger seat, )
I would even lend you money.
good boy good boy
(making him the most popular target for teasing.)
Good boy, good boy.
(Kwang Soo is sitting at the back because he's a prisoner.)
Don't you think Kwang Soo should be tied up like a prisoner?
但是哥 既然穿了囚服
- He should be tied up. - I'm not an actual prisoner.
不是得綁個警繩才對嗎
(He looks like a real prisoner.)
是得綁啊
不是真的犯人啊
(He looks like a real prisoner.)
How many years do you have left?
-不是 -你還有多少年啊
(He looks like a real prisoner.)
- A little more than 900 years. - We should tie him up.
還有900年
(900 years to be released from Running Man Prison)
900年
By the way, Kwang Soo, do you really have to...
(900 years to be released from Running Man Prison)
但是光洙啊 你真的..
你再考慮一下 你現在這個
Think again. You see, this is...
- It's not too late. - Exactly.
還沒晚呢
是啊
Apologize to the viewers at the end of the show.
在今天結束之前突然間說個很抱歉
(Goes back on his word)
反悔
你是可以的 你是可以這麼做的人設
(Goes back on his word)
Then he goes back on his word?
- You would be okay. - That would be funny.
The viewers would understand you.
-有意思 有意思 -是你的話
(He's the only person that viewers will forgive...)
很多觀眾都會理解的
The viewers would understand you.
(for going back on his word.)
-會一笑而過 -是啊 會一笑而過
- They'd just laugh it off. - Exactly.
(for going back on his word.)
(Laughing)
- They'd just laugh it off. - Exactly.
那個傢伙 那個那個
"Gosh, that brat."
(He's the only person licensed to con and cheat.)
真是淘氣包
They'd just think he's playful.
(He's the only person licensed to con and cheat.)
-會一笑而過 -說是隱藏攝像機
- They'd get mad and just laugh. - Say it was a camera prank.
(He's the only person licensed to con and cheat.)
Say, "I can't find any better jobs than this."
說著沒有比這個還好的職業了
(He'll be immune from criticisms if he takes back his words.)
今天是哥的特輯 哥挺享受的
"I had so much fun shooting the special episode."
(He'll be immune from criticisms if he takes back his words.)
(It's possible to say it was all a prank because it's Kwang Soo.)
That would be hilarious.
那肯定很搞笑
(It's possible to say it was all a prank because it's Kwang Soo.)
What are you going to do on Mondays from now on?
以後你週一要做什麼呢
(The day of Running Man shoot)
- You'll be bored on Mondays. - It's obvious.
以後週一會很空虛吧
He'll lie in his bed all day long.
還能做什麼呢 就是躺著唄
(He'll have no work on Mondays for a while.)
- Come to work as a cameraman. - Exactly.
-那你就來舉攝像機吧 -是啊
(He'll have no work on Mondays for a while.)
-估計你在週一 -會待在家啊
- Every Monday, - He'll be at home on Mondays.
(He'll have no work on Mondays for a while.)
You'll think of us a lot.
都會很想我們的
I know.
-是啊 -寶弼說什麼了
(While they laugh and talk, it brings back memories.)
I remember our trip to New Zealand.
想起新西蘭了
(While they laugh and talk, it brings back memories.)
There's a lot of reruns of the episodes...
最近的重播有很多那樣的
- where we traveled to Hong Kong... - Right.
我們去中國香港的
(Their memories abroad aired in the last episode.)
是啊
但是真的挺想念的
Watching it made me miss those days.
(Their memories abroad aired in the last episode.)
Recently, I watched the one where Ji Hyo, So Min, Seok Jin,
最近播了我和智孝和昭旻和哥
(They just want to take a trip down memory lane today.)
-去蒙古的 -是啊 之前去了
- and I went on a trip to Mongolia. - I remember that.
(They just want to take a trip down memory lane today.)
哥哥們去蒙古時
When you went to Mongolia, did Kwang Soo and I go to Russia?
光洙哥和我們是去俄羅斯了嗎
- Yes, you guys went to Russia. - That's right.
-俄羅斯 -去了俄羅斯
We ate snow crab.
-俄羅斯 -是啊
螃蟹
I miss those times.
很想念很想念
I miss you already.
I miss traveling freely.
也想念光洙哥
(Why miss me already?)
想念那樣的自由
I miss you already, Kwang Soo.
想念哥
Do you remember when we went to Russia?
還記得去俄羅斯那會嗎 哥
- He was right about that. - It was good.
那句話是對的
(They ruminate over the memories on the way.)
Are we going to have a buffet outside?
我們是去室外吃嗎
(They ruminate over the memories on the way.)
不知道啊
- I don't know. - This is Han River Park.
(They ruminate over the memories on the way.)
這裡是漢江公園啊
It must be a good place.
這是什麼
(What are they doing in the Han River when they're supposed to eat?)
- Where are we? - We're at Han River Park.
-這裡是漢江公園啊 -這是那個嗎
(What are they doing in the Han River when they're supposed to eat?)
Are we going to eat...
在船上吃的
(Are they eating on a cruise ship as Kwang Soo wanted?)
on a cruise ship?
-船上嗎 -在船上用餐嗎
- Could that be the case? - Will we eat on a cruise ship?
(Are they eating on a cruise ship as Kwang Soo wanted?)
-在船上吃 -估計是啊
- I guess that's the case. - Really?
(Are they eating on a cruise ship as Kwang Soo wanted?)
(The members also love the nice view.)
是那個
- That's it. - Oh, really?
(The members also love the nice view.)
真的是
I always wanted to eat there.
(The members also love the nice view.)
我很想去一次來著
- Thank you, Kwang Soo. - I've never eaten there either.
(The members also love the nice view.)
-謝謝 哥 -我還沒去過呢
- Thank you, Kwang Soo. - I've never eaten there either.
We came here for a shoot many times.
之前經常來這邊拍攝呢
(The Han River with good memories they made while shooting the show)
好多回憶
We made a lot of good memories here.
(The Han River with good memories they made while shooting the show)
Shall we walk hand in hand?
我們要手拉手走嗎
(Since it's his last day, they're trying things they never did.)
"Shall we walk hand in hand?"
要手拉手走嗎
- My gosh. - Are our hands warm?
怎樣 手暖和嗎
Yes, they're warm.
暖和
(Seok Jin was walking behind Kwang Soo.)
- Oh, my. - Seok Jin wants to hold your hand.
石鎮好像想說什麼
This will be a lovely but sad scene.
這個場面好揪心啊
(Laughing)
哥因為現在有攝像機在拍了
He's acting like that because the camera is rolling.
(Laughing)
- He didn't see it. - He just saw the camera.
真搞笑
(Seok Jin finally found the camera.)
發現攝像機了
誰
- Who? - Seok Jin. It makes me upset.
(Seok Jin finally found the camera.)
對石鎮哥好失落 那樣的
- What did you say? - I mean, in the elevator,
不是 在電梯上看都不看我一眼
he didn't even look at me.
- I'm going to take a photo. - He said it all of a sudden.
-因為有攝像機在拍 -得拍下來才行
就說 這個場面好揪心啊
(He brings out his camera in front of a camera.)
得拍下來才行
- I'm going to take a photo. - He's the worst.
(He brings out his camera in front of a camera.)
-真的是最糟糕的 -攝像機
- I'll take a photo of them. - What's wrong with him?
(He brings out his camera in front of a camera.)
-要拍下這個場面 -幹嘛那樣
- I'll take a photo of them. - What's wrong with him?
現在也是 哥 看看他那樣兒
Even now, look at what he's doing.
He's taking a photo of us.
還要拍我們
(The photographer already took a photo of them.)
- He's the worst. - He always does that.
那個哥真的是最糟糕的
(He's taking meaningless pictures of their backs.)
假石鎮
They look so lovely.
(He's taking meaningless pictures of their backs.)
很依戀
They look so lovely.
(The last feast with Kwang Soo)
What's this?
這是什麼
(The last feast with Kwang Soo)
Something smells good.
好香的味道
(They enjoy...)
I think we're going to eat pork belly.
好像是吃五花肉啊 哥
(pork belly looking at the Han River.)
-是烤肉吃嗎 -在室外吃啊
- We'll have a barbecue? - Oh, we'll eat outside.
(pork belly looking at the Han River.)
(Kwang Soo chose the most convenient and familiar menus.)
是烤肉吃啊
We'll have a barbecue.
(Kwang Soo chose the most convenient and familiar menus.)
- What's that? - We'll have a barbecue.
-這是什麼 -是烤肉吃
(Kwang Soo chose the most convenient and familiar menus.)
- Let's sit here together. - We'll actually eat pork belly.
-真的是吃五花肉 -坐這裡吧 我們坐一排
(Everyone wants to sit next to Kwang Soo.)
坐這裡
- Sit here. - Kwang Soo, sit in the center.
(Everyone wants to sit next to Kwang Soo.)
坐中間吧 光洙
光洙坐中間啊
- Kwang Soo, sit in the center. - Come over here.
(Everyone wants to sit next to Kwang Soo.)
過來
Kwang Soo, why did you take us here? Why didn't you choose simple food?
光洙啊 怎麼不說隨便吃點呢
- It's not like that. - Kwang Soo, what is this?
還要來這些地方
-就是啊 光洙 這是什麼 -為什麼
- It's not like that. - Kwang Soo, what is this?
(They're having pork belly outside on such a hot day.)
- I didn't ask for this. - Why must we eat out here?
本來不至於這樣的
(They're having pork belly outside on such a hot day.)
-本來不至於這樣 -真的是
I didn't ask for a meal outside.
(They're having pork belly outside on such a hot day.)
-不是 光洙啊 -真的是
- You see, Kwang Soo, - Gosh, seriously.
- you should've kept it simple. - What is this?
像今天這樣的日子
-這是什麼嘛 -得吃點簡單些啊
- Having a barbecue? - Why would you make a fuss?
-不是不是 -怎麼還烤肉吃
(Blaming)
幹嘛非得表現出來呢
- A bowl of noodles would be nice. - I mean...
(Blaming)
-不是 -嗦個面多好啊
- A bowl of noodles would be nice. - I mean...
- A bowl of gukbap would be enough. - Exactly. This is ridiculous.
吃個湯飯不就好了嗎
-就是啊 這是什麼 -吃什麼五花肉啊
Why didn't you order some lunchboxes so we could have a quick lunch?
乾脆簡單吃個盒飯結束就行了
They all seemed excited before the camera was rolling.
剛才還說 五花肉肯定很好吃
(He gets in a lot of trouble today.)
為什麼突然這樣 我什麼都沒做
- What is this? - You told the staff, right?
(He gets in a lot of trouble today.)
-這到底算什麼 –是你說的吧
- What is this? - You told the staff, right?
Kwang Soo, you should go home now.
喂 光洙 你今天還是回家吧
你先回家吧
- We'll see you next week. - We'll see you next week.
(He better quit next week.)
-下周再說吧 -下周再說吧 下周再說吧
- I should finish it today. - Just one more week.
(He better quit next week.)
真是的
The first menu that Kwang Soo chose is...
好 各位
(Kwang Soo's first menu is...)
李光洙說的食物
-首先是大家有很多回憶的五花肉 -嗯
- pork belly with a lot of memories. - Okay.
(Kwang Soo's first menu is...)
(reminiscent pork belly...)
還有是整雞刀切面
The second menu is chicken kalguksu.
(reminiscent pork belly...)
(and chicken kalguksu.)
- Oh, chicken kalguksu? - That's good.
整雞刀切面啊
(and chicken kalguksu.)
這個確實有
- Right. Whenever we visited him... - Whenever we went to his house...
(and chicken kalguksu.)
-去光洙家玩的話 -去光洙家玩的話
That's why I chose it.
所以就說了這個
(They often ordered it when they visited Kwang Soo's house.)
去光洙家玩的時候
When Seok Jin and I visited Kwang Soo's house,
(They often ordered it when they visited Kwang Soo's house.)
-我 石鎮哥還有光洙 -對 和光洙一起
we often ate chicken kalguksu.
(They often ordered it when they visited Kwang Soo's house.)
經常吃整雞刀切面
we often ate chicken kalguksu.
(It's the first menu cheap Kwang Soo paid for them.)
光洙第一次請我們吃的整雞刀切面
It was the first time Kwang Soo treated us.
(It's the first menu cheap Kwang Soo paid for them.)
You didn't have to point that out.
怎麼還說到這去了
(It's the first menu cheap Kwang Soo paid for them.)
- My gosh. - It's true. I won't deny it.
說得倒沒錯 說得倒沒錯
(It's the first menu cheap Kwang Soo paid for them.)
李光洙胸口上的數字
Do you know what the number on Kwang Soo's chest means?
(It's the first menu cheap Kwang Soo paid for them.)
(What does the number 3991 mean on Kwang Soo's chest?)
大家知道是什麼意思嗎
- What is it? - 3991.
(What does the number 3991 mean on Kwang Soo's chest?)
是什麼
-3991 -3991
(What does the number 3991 mean on Kwang Soo's chest?)
-3,991天 -對
3,991 days?
(What does the number 3991 mean on Kwang Soo's chest?)
- Correct. - Oh, my.
-好棒 世燦你太機智了 -有3991天了
- My, Se Chan is so smart. - It's been 3,991 days.
(3,991 days he spent with Running Man)
今天是第3991天
Today is the 3,991st day.
(3,991 days he spent with Running Man)
你說這個 Running Man嗎
- Since he joined Running Man? - Then it's been 3,991 days...
(3,991 days he spent with Running Man)
(Many viewers already expected the meaning of the number.)
-那我們也有3991天了 -我們也有這麼久了
- since we joined the show too. - Since we all joined the show.
(Many viewers already expected the meaning of the number.)
我們也一樣啊
- It's the same for us. - What about us?
(Many viewers already expected the meaning of the number.)
我們做了多少天
- It's been such a long time. - It'll be 4,000 days after 9 days.
(In 9 days, it will be 4,000 days.)
–真的好久了 -多少天嗎
再過9天就是4,000天了
The flame is too weak.
(In 9 days, it will be 4,000 days.)
火力不夠
-是該退出了 -我們要做更久
- It's time for you to leave. - I hope we last long.
(He approves Kwang Soo's leave.)
-我說 -怎麼了
- My gosh. - Why?
(He approves Kwang Soo's leave.)
I guess he can't stand any moment of warmth.
這哥片刻也忍受不了溫馨呢
Why? What did he say?
他說什麼了 說什麼了
(Instead of saying good work for 4,000 days...)
都4,000天啦 你是該退出了
He said, "It's been 4,000 days? It's time for you to leave."
(Instead of saying good work for 4,000 days...)
Did you want to do this that much?
你就那麼想做這些呀
You wanted to have a barbecue at the Han River?
來漢江烤肉吃
- Are you happy? - Why didn't you tell us?
-親愛的 -平時怎麼不說呀
(Seok Jin joins.)
那就可以一起做呀
- We could've done it for you. - You don't even answer my calls.
(Seok Jin joins.)
哥 你平時都不接我電話
- It'll be better than frozen meat. - Of course.
喂 不過…這肯定比冷凍五花肉好吃
(A familiar food with familiar members)
是吧 哥
- Kwang Soo. - The meat is quite thick.
(A familiar food with familiar members)
-光洙啊 -肉很厚
這個完全是…生五花肉 哇 厲害了
Look at the fresh meat. It looks so good.
(A familiar food with familiar members)
(Thick pork belly is roasted just right.)
Look at the fresh meat. It looks so good.
(Spicy chicken kalguksu with memories)
看起來好好吃
- It looks delicious. - It looks good.
(Spicy chicken kalguksu with memories)
這個看著也好吃
You see, chicken kalguksu is meaningful to us.
(Spicy chicken kalguksu with memories)
其實整雞刀切面很有意義
You see, chicken kalguksu is meaningful to us.
(It's time to enjoy the food...)
(It's time to enjoy the food that Kwang Soo chose.)
哥 熟了 先吃吧
It's cooked now. Let's eat.
(It's time to enjoy the food that Kwang Soo chose.)
Is the meat there cooked?
喂 那邊已經熟了嗎
(It's time to enjoy the food that Kwang Soo chose.)
好吃嗎
Is it good?
(Eating a thick piece of pork belly)
Try the soup first and see if it's good.
喂 你先嘗口湯 看看湯味道怎麼樣
(Eating a thick piece of pork belly)
好吃 好吃
It's good.
(A spoonful of chicken kalguksu soup)
It was cooked before it was delivered.
這邊也給一下
(A spoonful of chicken kalguksu soup)
好吃嗎
- Is it good? - It's so tasty.
(He's starting to get emotional again.)
嗯 好吃
It's good to eat outside.
而且在室外吃 別有風味啊
Kwang Soo, be quiet. We're eating here.
光洙 你安靜點 正吃飯呢
(Jae Seok cut him off successfully to the end.)
不是 哥…
But Jae Seok...
(Jae Seok cut him off successfully to the end.)
He's too chatty.
太吵了
We don't have time to laugh and chat.
我們還有閒情說說笑笑嗎
Then why did you...
-就是 -不是 那…
We don't have time...
(He laughed and chatted most loudly.)
Think before you talk.
說話之前先想一想
真好吃
(After Kwang Soo's endless social training, )
- Gosh. - It's good.
真好
This is so nice.
(After Kwang Soo's endless social training, )
We'll start the second mission now. It's a simple game.
馬上進行第二個簡單任務
(Kwang Soo succeeds to reduce...)
We'll start the second mission now. It's a simple game.
不讓水槍倒下 把布抽出來即成功
(150 years in the second mission.)
You have to pull the cloth out without the bucket falling.
Since you got 150 years deducted,
因此又減了150年
(He has 750 years left.)
再來抽一次禮物
- you'll choose a gift again. - Right now?
(He has 750 years left.)
(He draws the second gift.)
馬上就能抽嗎
-第二個禮物是 -又抽嗎
- The second gift is... - That again?
(He draws the second gift.)
(A designer hoodie)
名牌連帽衛衣
A designer hoodie.
(A designer hoodie)
(A designer hoodie is up to his hand.)
-這個 這個 -腳 腳
This is the best.
(A designer hoodie is up to his hand.)
- From B brand. - Go, Kwang Soo!
(Kwang Soo loves free stuff.)
走起 李光洙
好 我很想選這個
- Ready. - I have a good feeling about this.
(Kwang Soo loves free stuff.)
(He must pick a hard-boiled egg to get the gift.)
-這個嗎 -這個 嗯
- This one? - Yes.
(He must pick a hard-boiled egg to get the gift.)
- Me too. - I'd choose the other one.
-我也看中了這個 -我感覺是這個
Everyone else chose this one.
他們都感覺是這個 但我感覺是這個
- Seok Jin, you've been... - Why?
-不過哥 你今天特別… -怎麼了
Encouraging Kwang Soo by his side unlike you.
經常在光洙身邊安撫他
I've never seen you like this.
你以前從沒這樣過吧
Honestly, I'm most disappointed by him.
-最後一天嘛 -老實講 最讓我傷心的是他
When there was no camera around us, he walked far behind me.
(He doesn't appear unless there's a camera.)
-嗯 -沒有鏡頭就遠遠地都不搭理我
But he ran to me when he saw the helicam.
那啥 無人攝像機
(He's upset.)
看到無人攝像機就急忙向我跑過來
Come on. The viewers might think that's true.
(He's upset.)
人家聽了還以為是真的呢
Come on. The viewers might think that's true.
I hope you succeed.
-希望成功 希望成功 –我要選這個
(Kwang Soo chooses the second egg.)
Okay. Kwang Soo, that's the one.
OK 光洙就是那個
(Kwang Soo chooses the second egg.)
Go.
Go
(Kwang Soo got the first gift easily.)
- Kwang Soo seems quite lucky today. - Indeed.
-光洙今天運氣不錯啊 -嗯 今天
應該是真的吧
I'm sure it's a hard-boiled egg. It must not be a raw egg.
(Could he be lucky for the 1st time in 3,991 days?)
不會是假的 應該是真的
(It's a raw egg.)
- Oh, no. - That's Kwang Soo.
這才是李光洙
Finally, he's back to his true self.
李光洙終於… 我不是說了選這個嗎
- What was that? - I told you to pick this one.
Right. You should've picked the same number.
-是啊 應該兩次都選一樣的 -是啊
(A raw egg looks good on him.)
Right. You should've picked the same number.
本來挺好的
You won't get a designer hoodie since you failed.
選到了咣 就沒法拿到名牌連帽衛衣了
(After losing the designer hoodie, )
You won't get a designer hoodie since you failed.
(it's time to wash his face.)
What a shame.
好可惜
Hey, remove snot from his nose too.
給他擤個鼻涕吧 鼻涕
(A special face wash service wishing it's the last raw egg)
That's so heart-warming.
真溫馨
(A special face wash service wishing it's the last raw egg)
He's washing Kwang Soo's face. This is beautiful.
最後一次還給洗臉
真美麗
Are you happy that Jae Seok is washing your face?
哥哥們給你洗臉 開心嗎
Blow your nose.
哼一下 哼
(Squeezing his nose)
哎喲
Oh, my.
(Squeezing his nose)
(The good brother removes his old snot instead of tears.)
-哥 確實很爽 –是啊 我給你做的
- Jae Seok, you're skillful. - Of course. I've done this a lot.
(The good brother removes his old snot instead of tears.)
下一個地點乘著遊船前往
We'll ride a ferry to move to the next location.
(Along the sparkling Han River, )
(they move to the next spot on the cruise.)
-現在去嗎 -是 去吧
- Are we leaving now? - Yes.
(they move to the next spot on the cruise.)
-好 -好
- Okay. - Okay.
(they move to the next spot on the cruise.)
上去就可以了
- You can go up there. - How many photos of me are there?
我們拍了幾張照片
How many photos?
-什麼 -拍了幾張照片
(He's checking the number of photos of him with Kwang Soo.)
(1st, Haha, 2nd, Seok Jin, 3rd, So Min, )
(4th, Ji Hyo, 5th Jong Kook, 6th, Jae Seok and Se Chan)
Okay.
OK
(They check the hidden mission that Kwang Soo isn't aware of.)
Would you like some coffee?
要喝咖啡不
(They check the hidden mission that Kwang Soo isn't aware of.)
這原來是咖啡呀
Is that coffee?
(They check the hidden mission that Kwang Soo isn't aware of.)
(They moved to an improvised campsite on the ferry.)
This is what I like the most.
是我喜歡的感覺
(They moved to an improvised campsite on the ferry.)
撐著遮陽傘 坐在露營椅子上
(It's like the weather in California Jong Kook loves.)
I'm sitting on a camping chair under a parasol.
Thanks to Kwang Soo,
(It's like the weather in California Jong Kook loves.)
不過多虧了光洙 今天…
Thanks to Kwang Soo,
(Still)
-治癒呀 治癒 -還能坐遊船
- we're enjoying a relaxing time. - We got to ride a ferry too.
Exactly. We don't get to ride a ferry many times.
(A therapeutic time on a cruise with members)
是啊 還真是
我們還有什麼時候會乘這些
(A therapeutic time on a cruise with members)
Oh, gosh.
Kwang Soo... My gosh.
光洙…真是…
(Getting emotional)
哥 石鎮哥啟動了呢
Seok Jin is starting it.
(Getting emotional)
Seok Jin, stop gazing at him like that.
石鎮哥 你不要這麼深情地望著他
(Teasing)
Seok Jin, stop gazing at him like that.
-幹嘛製造氣氛 -幹嘛製造氣氛
- Why are you starting it? - Don't do that.
(As soon as the camera rolls, he tries to squeeze out tears.)
我不是製造氣氛
- It's not like that. - You're trying to make us cry.
(As soon as the camera rolls, he tries to squeeze out tears.)
-刺激淚腺 -嗯
Did you ever make good memories with him on a private occasion?
哥 你跟光洙私下里有回憶嗎
(Seok Jin's spokesperson)
有啊
- Of course, he did. - Really? When?
(Seok Jin's spokesperson)
-什麼 什麼時候 -有很多回憶
I think he played a card game with him.
哥好像打過花圖吧
(With Kwang Soo)
(It sounds too tasteless to call a good memory.)
- Did we? - Yes.
怎麼了
(It sounds too tasteless to call a good memory.)
- I spent a lot of time with him. - I bet...
我和光洙一起度過很多時間
(He remembered.)
you never let him win and tried to win more money.
所以拚命想贏光洙的錢
打了花圖吧 對 對
You played cards with him. I remember that now.
(Seok Jin was serious about emptying Jo Kka Chi's pocket.)
-是啊 -我還大聲喊了皮搏
- Right. - I remember I got double points.
(Seok Jin was serious about emptying Jo Kka Chi's pocket.)
(He accurately remembers.)
Right. You do share memories with him.
有 有 有
(Looking around)
Hey, Bo Pil, why are you crying?
喂 寶弼 你哭什麼
I'm not. I had something in my eye.
不是 眼睛裡進了東西
(Bo Pil suddenly wiped his eyes while they were talking.)
Hey, Bo Pil, why are you crying?
喂 寶弼 你哭什麼
(Bo Pil suddenly wiped his eyes while they were talking.)
不是 眼睛裡進了東西
I'm not. I had something in my eye.
(Bo Pil suddenly wiped his eyes while they were talking.)
- Is he crying? Oh, no. - Why are you crying already?
-怎麼哭了 -怎麼這麼快就哭了
(Why are you crying?)
哭什麼
Why are you crying?
(Why are you crying?)
你哭什麼
Why are you crying?
- Come on. Why? - Why are you crying?
-你幹什麼 -哭什麼
(He got a fly in his eye.)
-你幹嘛呀 -這是幹什麼
- What's with him? - Why are you crying?
(He got a fly in his eye.)
我們也沒哭呢
Bo Pil always cared about you, unlike the way he talked to you.
(He got a fly in his eye.)
雖然那麼對你說話 他還是很暖心的
Why are tears coming from only one eye?
不過怎麼只有一隻眼睛在流淚
(Because I got a fly only in one eye.)
- That's an unusual skill. - What are you doing?
-特技啊 -搞什麼
(Because I got a fly only in one eye.)
怎麼做到的
- How do you do that? - Why are you crying?
(Because I got a fly only in one eye.)
到底為什麼哭
- Only one of his eyes is red. - Everybody cries these days.
怎麼只有一隻眼睛紅紅的
-怎麼流行哭了 -哭什麼
Gosh. What's wrong with all of you?
啊 都怎麼了
(Imitating a drama scene)
Stop it.
你別這樣
(He's swallowing his tears by flexing his nostrils.)
Why are you crying? Why?
哭什麼 哭什麼
(Horn)
(While Haha imitates a drama scene, the cruise sets off.)
開船了
- They're leaving. - It blew its horn.
(While Haha imitates a drama scene, the cruise sets off.)
汽笛聲 嗡
(A cameraman is shooting on a different ship.)
- They're waving at us. - Bye.
跟我們招手呢
導演在跟我們招手
Where is Chan Hee going? Where is he going alone?
燦熙哥 你去哪兒啊
這哥自己去哪兒啊
Now he's shooting scenes without the director's directions.
PD都沒指示呢 這哥現在都自己開始拍了
- Chan Hee is here with us. - He's here.
-哥 燦熙哥在這裡 -燦熙哥在這裡
(Surprised)
He's here with us.
- Chan Hee, I'm sorry. - What's wrong with you?
-哥 對不起 -你幹嘛呀
(Angry)
- Chan Hee, I'm sorry. - What's wrong with you?
-對不起 -你怎麼當著面…哥
- I'm sorry, Chan Hee. - How could you say such a thing?
(Jae Seok gossiped in front of Chan Hee.)
Just because you thought Chan Hee wasn't here...
以為燦熙哥不在 你這是…
(Jae Seok gossiped in front of Chan Hee.)
道歉很快啊
- You cut him off at the right time. - Chan Hee, I'm sorry.
(Jae Seok gossiped in front of Chan Hee.)
You must never leave us.
-燦熙哥 對不起 -不能離開這裡
You complimented him so much when he was in front of you.
人在的時候 還說什麼始祖鳥呢
Please stay here with us.
請留在這裡
(He unexpectedly gossiped the broadcasting legend.)
-一定要留在這裡 -是啊
- Don't go anywhere. - Right.
(He unexpectedly gossiped the broadcasting legend.)
-一離開這裡就完了 -太搞笑了
- Once you leave, this will happen. - He's so funny.
(He unexpectedly gossiped the broadcasting legend.)
(Chan Hee. Don't go anywhere. Stay with us.)
出發了 出發了
- The ferry is leaving now. - Oh, my.
(Chan Hee. Don't go anywhere. Stay with us.)
(Meanwhile, the cruise sets off.)
-開了 船開了 開始動了 -真的
- This is exciting. - It's moving.
(Meanwhile, the cruise sets off.)
We haven't done things like this in a while.
真的很久沒有這樣了
(The cheap production crew rents a cruise as someone leaves.)
手筆很大嘛
You spent a lot of money on this episode.
(The cheap production crew rents a cruise as someone leaves.)
We came outside thanks to Kwang Soo.
多虧了光洙 我們也難得出來一次
(The donkey is happy as the other members are satisfied.)
Seok Jin is getting direct sunlight.
石鎮哥正在被陽光直射呢
(Only he is under direct sunlight.)
(UV rays right on Seok Jin's face)
Look at him.
It's as if he's at a tanning salon.
(UV rays right on Seok Jin's face)
這簡直就是美黑店
It's as if he's at a tanning salon.
(Seok Jin alone enjoys tanning.)
好樣的 位置選得好
Nice. I picked the right seat.
(Seok Jin alone enjoys tanning.)
眼睛得遮一下
- He needs to cover his eyes. - Gosh, seriously.
(Seok Jin alone enjoys tanning.)
這個
- I didn't know he liked tanning. - How can this be?
(He's getting cooked.)
原來他喜歡美黑呀
- I didn't know he liked tanning. - How can this be?
這麼會這樣
- Gosh. - I see seagulls flying around too.
還有海鷗飛來飛去呢 哥
- Seagulls are flying toward us. - I see them too.
-海鷗來了 -有海鷗 那邊還有無人機
There's a drone up there too. Look.
(The seagulls are here to say goodbye to Kwang Soo.)
看那邊
Oh, those punks. Right. Thank you.
(The seagulls are here to say goodbye to Kwang Soo.)
這些傢伙 真謝謝你們 又這樣…
Oh, those punks. Right. Thank you.
- Their eyes look scary. - Look at that.
眼神很凶
It has the R logo on the side.
-哥 他腋下有R標誌耶 -鳥身上…
- That's nonsense. - It has the logo on its body.
鳥身上怎麼會…
(Absurd)
- That's nonsense. - It has the logo on its body.
哥 鳥身上… 感覺得把它抓住
(It must be a mission.)
I think you should catch it.
- Why would a seagull have the logo? - One of those seagulls...
(It must be a mission.)
海鷗怎麼會有R標誌
坐到那上面了
I think the mission is to catch the seagull.
(It must be a mission.)
(Find the R logo on a Seagull's Side)
可能任務就是抓住海鷗
Look. It has the logo on its side.
(Find the R logo on a Seagull's Side)
你看 那個海鷗山上有R標誌
- Kwang Soo, hurry up and catch it. - Nonsense.
(Find the R logo on a Seagull's Side)
哥 得抓住那個 快點
- Kwang Soo, hurry up and catch it. - Nonsense.
Only then you can finish this.
什麼R標誌啊
(This most difficult mission will be the grand finale of his 11 years...)
這樣才能結束
It has the logo right here. Hurry up and catch it.
(This most difficult mission will be the grand finale of his 11 years...)
這邊有R標誌 快去抓呀
海鷗的腋下怎麼會有R標誌
- That doesn't make sense. - You might get 1,000 years...
(This most difficult mission will be the grand finale of his 11 years...)
(in Running Man.)
- That doesn't make sense. - You might get 1,000 years...
(Stop teasing.)
別說那種不著邊際的話…
- Hurry up and jump. - You might get 1,000 years...
(Stop teasing.)
能減刑1000年 減刑
You might get 1,000 years deducted.
(Stop teasing.)
(That should deduct 1,000 years.)
You can finish it right away. It has the logo on its body.
這樣就能結束了 有R標誌啊
- Hurry up and go. - No way.
(While the seagulls delivered the mission, )
快點 光洙哥 快去呀
要過橋底下了
We're passing the bridge.
(While the seagulls delivered the mission, )
(the cruise is passing the halfway point.)
I've never seen the bridge from below.
我第一次見到
(the cruise is passing the halfway point.)
There might be the monster from "The Host" hanging there.
或許會有怪物貼在上面
- Since we passed the second bridge, - Yes.
-各位 剛過了第二個橋 -是
(It's already time for a third mission.)
第3個任務是
- we'll begin the third mission. - Kwang Soo, come back to your seat.
(It's already time for a third mission.)
光洙過來坐吧
Well... As we continue missions...
任務…一直…
(Sad)
-還剩幾個任務啊 -越是進行下去
- How many are there left? - It feels...
(Sad)
能繼續做下去就好了
I hope there will be a lot of them.
(Sad)
It feels like we're counting down the hours before saying goodbye.
感覺在倒數我們分開
(The mission will be revealed while everyone's sad.)
光洙 到這來吧
All of you will work together on this mission.
(The mission will be revealed while everyone's sad.)
好 這是全員一起挑戰的任務
All of you will work together on this mission.
(It's a team mission where everyone participates.)
每個人看到依次提供的基礎難度的漢字
You will take turns to look at...
(It's a team mission where everyone participates.)
(They must say the meaning and pronunciation...)
an elementary-level Chinese character...
(of a Chinese character in 3 seconds to pass.)
3秒內答對就能通過
which you must guess in three seconds.
(of a Chinese character in 3 seconds to pass.)
八個人全部通過
If all eight of you guess correctly,
(of a Chinese character in 3 seconds to pass.)
(If all 8 members pass, Kwang Soo will shed 300 years off.)
就立刻減刑300年
Kwang Soo will get to shed 300 years off his sentence.
(If all 8 members pass, Kwang Soo will shed 300 years off.)
-300年嗎 -300年嗎
- 300 years? - 300 years?
(If all 8 members pass, Kwang Soo will shed 300 years off.)
300年 八個人都成功的話
If all eight of you guess correctly.
(If all 8 members pass, Kwang Soo will shed 300 years off.)
- 300 years? - That's a lot of years.
300年嗎
-嗯 成功的話 -減去很多 減去很多
This is bad. I don't know many Chinese characters.
-不好了 我對漢字真的很弱 -我很懂漢字
- Meanwhile, he knows a lot. - Him...
Haha, you don't know what "left" even is.
HAHA啊 你真的
連左字都不懂呢
- I don't know many. - I don't know any.
-我對漢字真的很弱 -我壓根就不懂
- Left. - The Chinese character for "left."
-左 左 -左字
("Jwa" meaning left)
-我真的不懂 -那右邊是 右邊的左嗎
Doesn't "woo" mean "right"?
- Do you know what "woo" is? - Left and right.
你知道右 右字 -右邊的左
"Woo" is the character for "right."
喂 右邊是右邊的右啊
(Pathetic)
右左
"Woo" is the character for "right."
Not "woo" and "jwa." Woo means right.
-不是右左 是右邊的右 -右左
Woo means right and jwa means left.
喂 右是右邊 左是左邊
- I know that. - We use it when driving.
這個我懂
(Croaking)
右轉 左轉
Are you laughing at us?
(Croaking)
-你居然笑 -什麼情況
-喂 你敢笑我 -你居然笑
- Are you laughing at us? - Seriously?
(Croaking)
海鷗還多呀
(Even the seagulls laugh at the empty heads.)
-你居然笑 -什麼情況
That one's definitely laughing at you.
(Even the seagulls laugh at the empty heads.)
這肯定是嘲笑
That one's definitely laughing at you.
那隻在嘲笑我們啊
(Smirking)
It's so annoying!
-我第一次見海鷗發出那樣的聲音-喂嘲笑人嗎
I've never heard seagulls make that sound before.
It was laughing at you like crazy.
-笑嗎 -笑很久啊
(I'm coming for you.)
It was laughing at you like crazy.
它笑了 貼著的它 站著的那隻
That one standing over there.
Why are the seagulls gathering over here?
-是啊 -為什麼這麼多海鷗啊
Isn't that the one with the R mark?
剛咯吱窩裡有R標誌的不是它嗎
(It was this one.)
-太過分了 -真是的
- There are too many. - What?
(It was this one.)
- Hold on. - We don't need an audience!
-喂喂喂 -喂喂喂 撤走觀眾
(Offended)
-心情真不好啊 -怎麼還邀請觀眾來了
- That's super annoying. - We have an audience.
(Offended)
-怎麼回事啊 -那麼馬上開始吧
- That's super annoying. - We have an audience.
(The mission begins amongst the mockery of seagulls.)
Let's start over on this side then.
-從這邊開始 -好的
(The mission begins amongst the mockery of seagulls.)
-好的 開始啦 -從李光洙開始 開始
Here we go.
(The mission begins amongst the mockery of seagulls.)
(Kwang Soo will go first.)
- Starting with Kwang Soo. - Right.
And go.
(Kwang Soo will go first.)
- 1, 2, 3. - "Month."
-1 2 3 -月 月 -就是這樣
That's right. Good.
-好 好 好 -這個認識 這個認識 這個認識
(Correct)
- That one I knew. - I didn't know.
-我不知道啊 -喂 無視我們嗎
(That's mean.)
- Don't you belittle us! - I knew that.
-那個知道啊 -哇 我不知道啊
- I didn't know. - Don't you belittle us!
-喂 無視我們
(Se Chan goes next.)
-開始 -就知道會出那樣的
I knew it'd be on this level.
(Se Chan goes next.)
1 2 3
- 1, 2, 3. - "Mouth."
(Correct)
口 口
Nicely done!
(Correct)
OK OK OK
Nicely done!
That one I knew.
到這兒為止我都認識 到這兒為止都認識
(The youngest empty head works a miracle.)
Those are the only two I know.
孩子們啊
Guys,
我這叔叔答對了
I got it right!
很好 很好
Did you know that?
(He smiles brightly after getting the most basic Chinese character.)
-答對啊 -這要怎麼答啊
What do I do? That's all I know.
(He smiles brightly after getting the most basic Chinese character.)
怎麼回答 給我說下漢字
Did you see that though? He didn't seem sure.
(He smiles brightly after getting the most basic Chinese character.)
看到了嗎 不自信
Did you see that though? He didn't seem sure.
(The next empty head gets nervous as Se Chan gets it right.)
口口我知道 到口口我是知道的
- That one I knew. - Here's the third one.
(The next empty head gets nervous as Se Chan gets it right.)
第三個了啊 -來吧 來吧
- "Mouth." - Haha, you're up.
(The next empty head gets nervous as Se Chan gets it right.)
開始 1 2 3
1, 2, 3.
"Wol."
風 月
- "Eye." - That's "eye."
-喂 -喂 是目 目 -風
(Unbelievable)
-喂 -喂 是目 目
- "Eye." - That's "eye."
(Unbelievable)
-風月是什麼啊 -目 目
- What? - "Wol"?
(The answer was "mok" for eye.)
風月是什麼啊
What on earth is "wol"?
(The answer was "mok" for eye.)
木 木月 木
It means "Thursday."
- It looks like an eye. - That is incorrect.
-那個 -那長得像眼睛一樣啊
(The youngest empty head heard it wrong.)
-不是風 風嗎 -竟然不認識這個 真是的
- Isn't it "wind"? - He didn't know.
(The youngest empty head heard it wrong.)
(These 3 empty heads are a mess.)
好難
It's too hard.
(These 3 empty heads are a mess.)
喂 口 口 但有點兒帥吧
Did I look cool when I got "mouth" right?
(These 3 empty heads are a mess.)
-哦 口 口 -口 口 我知道的
I knew "mouth" as well.
(He goes from Gum King to Mouth King.)
喂 因為換了位子
He changed seats and got caught with a character he didn't know.
(He goes from Gum King to Mouth King.)
就正好出了不認識的單字
He changed seats and got caught with a character he didn't know.
Mr. Empty Head!
鐵鐵哥
快開始吧
(This time, they start with So Min.)
-從那邊開始吧 -從那邊開始吧
- Let's start over there. - On that side.
(This time, they start with So Min.)
-不行啊 -看來第一個很簡單
(Lacking confidence)
- Oh, no. - The first one must be the easiest.
充分可以的
- Of course. - We can do this, guys.
Again, it's elementary level.
是超級基礎的漢字
- And... - Don't say things like that.
別說超級基礎那種話
(It hurts my pride.)
開始
And go.
(It hurts my pride.)
-這種 -八月
- 1, 2, 3. - "Wol."
- Wrong. - What?
-錯 -八月
- "Wol." - Wrong.
I meant that it's "eight."
八 八 八 八
(The answer is "pal" for eight.)
是八 八啊 八月是什麼啊
- The syllable is "pal." - It's "pal," not "wol."
(The answer is "pal" for eight.)
(That was it?)
為什麼會有月啊
Where did "wol" come from?
(That was it?)
是我慌神了 慌神了啊
It catches you off guard.
(The essay writer shows her lack of Chinese character knowledge.)
It catches you off guard!
-昭旻啊 -該守護的得守護啊
- So Min, this is bad. - Shouldn't we protect her?
(The essay writer shows her lack of Chinese character knowledge.)
-昭旻啊 你不行啊 -喂 你過來
- Sit over here. - It catches you off guard.
我慌了
- Sit over there. - Then I'd get a harder one.
-過來 -這樣子
去那兒的話會變難的
Let's go with those who haven't played yet.
請以沒答過的人為主
- We three have. - I'll get a harder one.
-因為我們答過了 -去這邊的話會變難啊
I got mine right.
-那啥 看到了嗎 -這邊
-厲害的人坐這邊 -哎喲 就回答了個口口
All this after getting "mouth" right?
- Sit over here if you get it right. - We got it right.
厲害的人坐這邊
("Moon" and "mouth" act like they belong in the upper ranks.)
我們答對了啊
- You should sit over there. - Right.
("Moon" and "mouth" act like they belong in the upper ranks.)
-那麼哥 大鐵 -那這位是第三個嗎
Leader of the Empty Head Clan, sit over there.
("Moon" and "mouth" act like they belong in the upper ranks.)
大鐵哥去那邊
Leader of the Empty Head Clan, sit over there.
(Leader of Empty Head Clan)
好的 那從這兒開始 從HAHA開始
We'll start with Haha then.
(Haha goes first.)
從HAHA開始
Haha will go first.
(Haha goes first.)
1, 2, 3.
1 2 3
I know this one.
知道啊
-多 多 -這是什麼字啊
- "Da." - It's "da."
"Da"!
Ta
- "Da"! - What does it mean?
-Ta -什ta
Why must I say it?
ta就是ta 還有什麼ta啊
It's just "da."
怎麼了 ta
(He's even shameless.)
就是
-喂 -不就是那個ta嗎
- It's not correct. - "Wol" is just "wol."
(He's even shameless.)
-就算答到了ta -ta
He at least got "da" right.
(He's even shameless.)
-答到ta了啊 -HAHA真不知道
(It was "da" for many.)
- He got "da" right. - Haha's clueless.
-是多 多 -多 多
The character means "many."
(It was "da" for many.)
-蒜嗎 蒜嗎 -我在學第二外語的時候寫過那個
- Isn't it better to give up? - Is it "garlic"?
But So Min knew that one.
但昭旻認識這個
- Se Chan... - Hey, come back here.
現在世燦
- No, don't. - Take this seat again.
昭旻 過來 昭旻 過來
- Unbelievable. - Please don't.
別說 別說
-我對他真沒感情了 -喂 沒寫過這字嗎
- I've had it with him. - Don't.
He asked if the character meant "garlic."
那是蒜嗎
說蒜的時候的那個蒜嗎
- Wait... - "Many."
-多 多 -你真是的
(Garlic lover)
哦嗚 我真覺得最差了
- He's the worst! - Don't do this on your last day.
你老實點兒 怎麼這樣啊
"Does that mean garlic?"
(He can't even understand Korean let alone Chinese characters.)
怎麼是蒜啊 那是蒜嗎
Stop it, okay?
(He can't even understand Korean let alone Chinese characters.)
真是的 你別說了
不是那個蒜
- It's not garlic. - It means "many."
(He can't even understand Korean let alone Chinese characters.)
-是多少的那個多 -但是你
- Many. - You thought it was "garlic"?
(She can relate to him.)
-世燦說這個 -世燦嗎
- No, Se Chan did. - Se Chan?
(She can relate to him.)
是多啊
I thought it was "garlic."
多 還以為是蒜
Like in "many" people.
會慌神的
(Empty Head learns another one.)
是多數人的那個多
I get it now. It means "many."
(Empty Head learns another one.)
-多 多 -突然出題 會慌神的
要不重新出答過的吧
Can you give us the one for "sun" again?
(Haha goes again.)
OK 開始
And go.
- 1, 2, 3. - "Baek."
1 2 3
百 百
1, 2, 3.
1 2 3
- It's "Baek." - "Baek."
-百 百 -百 是百啊
百 百
It's "Baek."
Peik
(He heard Se Chan.)
什麼peik 給你機會
What does it mean?
(He heard Se Chan.)
一對百
1 versus 100.
1 VS 100
Seriously? It means "100."
喂 喂
一百 百
Seriously? It means "100."
(Correct)
-我去 -是一百的百
(You can't help but drop your head.)
Is it "100"?
-我去 -是一百的百
- 1 versus 100? - Does it not mean "white"?
是一百的百
(Mr. Ha from Mapo-gu only knows about "1 versus 100".)
-這難嗎 -是一百的百
It means "100."
(Mr. Ha from Mapo-gu only knows about "1 versus 100".)
-不難吧 -一百的百
It means "100."
-一百的百 -一百的百
(He was confident enough to fight 100 men though.)
- Does it not mean "white"? - It means "100."
不是白色的白嗎
-是一百的百 -一百的百嗎
(He was confident enough to fight 100 men though.)
"100"?
- 1 versus 100? - 1 versus 100.
-一百 百 -一百的百
- That was hilarious. - It wasn't a bad answer though.
1vs100 好搞笑
(Dream, turn your TV off.)
不錯啊
- That was hilarious. - It wasn't a bad answer though.
那啥 但我們為了今後也能一直做
You know,
you need to protect our dignity...
so that we can stay on this show.
我們得守住某種水平啊
Viewers will get sick of us.
-那啥 -這程度就沒感情了啊
- Let them be adequately hard. - This will backfire on us.
要沒感情了
(3 seconds before getting sick of them)
-過頭的話 就沒感情了 -得守住一定的水平
-這個 -觀眾要是對我們沒感情了怎麼辦啊
What if the viewers don't want to see us?
(3 seconds before getting sick of them)
Even those who love us...
曾喜愛我們的人們也
will be appalled by how stupid we seem.
以前還有水準的 但這有點兒
(We actually edited out a few parts.)
They will be like,
這都不知道嗎
(We actually edited out a few parts.)
- "How can they not know that?" - Like this.
-是這樣的吧 -哦 -不知道啊
- "Seriously?" - I don't know any of them though.
(They go again before the viewers get sick of them.)
再開始吧
Ready, set, go.
(They go again before the viewers get sick of them.)
準備 開始
Ready, set, go.
1, 2, 3.
-1 2 3 -我知道啊
- You know this, right? - 4, 5.
這知道啊 這知道啊
(Time's up.)
Sa
- Seriously? - It means "four"!
(Time's up.)
Sa sa sa
- Seriously? - It means "four"!
(He doesn't know what it means.)
-sa -喂 你真不知道這個嗎
- Did you not know that? - Even I knew that.
(He doesn't know what it means.)
I thought about saying "Saturday."
不是
苦惱了下 是要說土
- Seriously... - How is that "Saturday"?
-喂 這真的是 -竟然到這程度啊
"Saturday" is this.
-喂 這個 -口 口加上有這個就是土嗎
Because there are two sticks inside the mouth?
(There are 2 lines in "mouth", so it means vomiting?)
-別說那樣的話 -什麼
Don't say things like that.
(There are 2 lines in "mouth", so it means vomiting?)
真的 別在節目裡說這種話
Kwang Soo, don't show that you're alarmed.
(Everyone is ashamed of him right now.)
得知道這個啊
You should know this one!
(Everyone is ashamed of him right now.)
-12345678 -真的嗎
(Not everyone can pass due to the empty heads.)
Seriously?
是四 是啊
(Not everyone can pass due to the empty heads.)
Yes, that's "four."
-給的是簡單的 -不知道 -四 四
- He gave you an easy one. - This is bad.
(Not everyone can pass due to the empty heads.)
How about 5 correct answers for 200 years?
要以5人成功押上200年來嗎
(Then...)
OK OK
- Okay. - I'll sit this out then.
(Then...)
(Deal.)
-就那樣吧 -那樣就快了啊 -就那樣吧
- Okay. - I'll sit this out then.
- Let's do this. - Just five?
-從我開始吧 -5人嗎
(They replay the game with an easier objective.)
"North"!
北 北
(Followed by Kwang Soo...)
好
Nicely done.
(Followed by Kwang Soo...)
血 血
- "Blood." - That is correct.
(Followed by Kwang Soo...)
對的
- "Blood." - That is correct.
(and Jong Kook, )
-OK -好樣的
- Of course. - Seriously?
(and Jong Kook, )
門 門
"Door."
(and Jong Kook, )
(even Seok Jin succeeds.)
到這個是知道的
And go. 1, 2, 3...
開始 1 2 3
(And it's now Cavewoman Ji Hyo's turn.)
And go. 1, 2, 3...
火 火
- "Fire." - Nice!
(Correct)
OK
- "Fire." - Nice!
-是的 -是的 對的 對的
- That's right. - Good job.
(Ji Hyo knows "fire"!)
對的 好的 做的好
來吧 來吧
- Good job, Ji Hyo. - Let's end this.
(Ji Hyo knows "fire"!)
-喂 答對5人吧 -來吧 來吧
- I can't believe it. - She got it right.
(Ji Hyo knows "fire"!)
(The mission will be accomplished if Jae Seok passes.)
那啥 這都不緊張
There's no need to even doubt it.
(The mission will be accomplished if Jae Seok passes.)
肯定會答對的
Jae Seok will get it right for sure.
(The mission will be accomplished if Jae Seok passes.)
-當然了 -OK
Jae Seok will get it right for sure.
但是也
- Still... - Let's shed 200 years.
減200年吧
"Flavor."
味 味
- That is correct. - All right!
-回答正確 -OK
- "Flavor"? - That's 200 years.
味 味
(5 of them get the answer to complete the mission.)
-味道的味 -味道的味 -味道的味
- "Flavor." - Yes, "flavor."
(5 of them get the answer to complete the mission.)
-味道的味 -味道的味
-說好吃的時候的那個味 -好的 好的
- It's used in the word "tasty." - Nicely done.
(5 of them get the answer to complete the mission.)
減了200年
That's 200 years off his sentence.
做的好
Good job.
(They managed to shed 200 years of sentence off.)
就那樣減了200年
So 200 years have been cut from your sentence,
(They managed to shed 200 years of sentence off.)
剩餘550年
and now you have 550 years left.
(They managed to shed 200 years of sentence off.)
(He has 550 years remaining.)
- Good. - It's not bad.
OK 還不錯
現在時間4點半
It's currently 4:30pm...
(2 hours until the end of the race)
現在還剩2小時
and you have two hours left.
(2 hours until the end of the race)
這次是最高級回音壁條狀音響
You'll be playing for a high-end soundbar.
(2 hours until the end of the race)
(He starts drawing the lot for the soundbar.)
我選好了
- Okay, I've chosen one. - All right!
(He starts drawing the lot for the soundbar.)
(He chooses egg number 1.)
OK
- Okay. - Let's do this.
來吧
(He must pick a boiled egg to get the prize.)
1 2
1, 2...
(He must pick a boiled egg to get the prize.)
-好像是熟的 -3
- I bet it's a boiled egg. - Three!
(It was a boiled egg!)
OK
- All right. - Nice!
(It was a boiled egg!)
喂 成了
Good one.
獲得回音壁條狀音響
- You get a soundbar. - A soundbar?
(He gets the high-class soundbar.)
回音壁條狀音響嗎
回音壁條狀音響 回音壁條狀音響
A soundbar?
(He gets the high-class soundbar.)
真給回音壁條狀音響嗎 OK
- Do I really get one? - Yes.
(The cruise resulted in years off his sentence and a gift.)
Good job.
-幹得好 -幹得好 幹得好
-再見 -辛苦了 -謝謝 -辛苦了
(They get off with light steps.)
- Thank you. - Thank you. Have a nice day.
Thank you.
(They get off with light steps.)
-謝謝 -謝謝
Gosh, check out this beautiful path.
哇 這兒路太美了
喂 真美啊
- It's stunning. - It really is.
太美了
- This is amazing. - It is.
這兒太美了
- It's so pretty. - Right, Ji Hyo?
-太美了 -是吧 姐姐
- This is stunning. - I feel like I'm on a picnic.
哦 太美了 就像來郊遊一樣
Let's take a photo, guys.
拍張照吧
(They take a photo between the flowers.)
1 2 3
- Thank you. - Thank you.
-謝謝 -謝謝 -謝謝
(Kwang Soo, let your path always be colorful.)
- I feel less queasy now. - I was a little queasy too.
下船了 胃好像也舒服些了
(They appreciated the flower path for a little while...)
暈了
好熱
It's hot today.
(They appreciated the flower path for a little while...)
好熱 好熱
It's hot today.
(and got on the bus to get to the final venue.)
- It's hot for me too. - Please close the door.
請繫上安全帶
(and got on the bus to get to the final venue.)
哦嗚 坐了船 狀態不怎麼好啊
- The cruise made me queasy. - Same here.
(and got on the bus to get to the final venue.)
是的 稍微有點兒暈船
- The cruise made me queasy. - Same here.
(They all complain of seasickness.)
胃不舒服啊
I don't feel that good either.
(They all complain of seasickness.)
啊額 因為光洙不幹了
Just because Kwang Soo's dropping out...
-莫名就 -哎 真是的
If it weren't for him,
要不是光洙的話
- we'd be doing something else. - Exactly.
我們應該就做其他的了啊
(The quitting donkey causes problems everywhere.)
為什麼要說不幹了啊
- You just had to quit the show. - Tell me about it.
(The quitting donkey causes problems everywhere.)
就是說啊
- You just had to quit the show. - Tell me about it.
就再推翻吧 說再做一會兒
Take it back and say you'll stick around a little longer.
Say this near the end of the show.
光洙呀 差不多結束的時候就說吧
"I'll choose one..."
代替我
(Peeking)
將指名一人
"to drop out instead of me."
(Peeking)
什麼 誰啊
That'd be fun.
應該很好
(They get a hint of who Kwang Soo will pick.)
Runningman
- It's very Running Man. - It'll be like a challenge.
(They get a hint of who Kwang Soo will pick.)
-有趣啊 -換人換人
Wouldn't it be fun?
(They get a hint of who Kwang Soo will pick.)
"Jee Seok Jin out."
池石鎮OUT
"I'll be dropping out of the show against my will."
儘管遺憾
無關我的意願 而要下車了
(As usual, they throw a few jokes...)
好的 作為Runningman新團長
"We'll be back after a refreshment period..."
(As usual, they throw a few jokes...)
新團長
A refreshment period?
(As usual, they throw a few jokes...)
(as the bus carries them to the final venue.)
現在時間5:18
The time is 5:18pm,
(as the bus carries them to the final venue.)
還剩1小時12分
The time is 5:18pm,
(It's 5:18pm, 1 hour and 12 minutes until the end of the race.)
which means you have an hour and 12 minutes left.
時間都快到了啊
(It's 5:18pm, 1 hour and 12 minutes until the end of the race.)
In this next round,
這次任務是模仿光洙模仿得越像
more years will be shed off...
(They can shed more years off if they imitate Kwang Soo well.)
減刑就越多的
if you're able to mimic Kwang Soo better.
(They can shed more years off if they imitate Kwang Soo well.)
喂 是我
This is Hello, It's Me.
(They can shed more years off if they imitate Kwang Soo well.)
(Hello, It's Me)
打電話那個啊
The one with the phone call, right?
(Hello, It's Me)
裝作是李光洙給李光洙的熟人打電話
You will call Kwang Soo's acquaintance...
(Hello, It's Me)
pretending to be him.
(In this mission, )
熟人啊
The more you...
(In this mission, )
要是能撐到
The more you...
哦 鐘國啊
(they must call Kwang Soo's acquaintance pretending to be him.)
哦 赫啊 在哪兒呢
- Hyuk, where are you? - Didn't he call you?
(they must call Kwang Soo's acquaintance pretending to be him.)
喂 你最近沒接到泰雅電話嗎
- Hyuk, where are you? - Didn't he call you?
(To win the round, they must fool the receiver.)
喂 要死了
He does, all the time.
(To win the round, they must fool the receiver.)
被電話騙了過去
He does, all the time.
哎 真是的
Why does he keep calling me after drinking?
他怎麼總是喝完酒給我打電話
(They'll lose the round if the receiver figures it out.)
These days, he...
他最近
(They'll lose the round if the receiver figures it out.)
This won't be easy at all.
(5 years of his sentence will be reduced every second...)
有點難啊 有點難
Can you say "Hello"?
(5 years of his sentence will be reduced every second...)
哥 來說一下吧 你好
Can you say "Hello"?
(until they're exposed, and they can go up to 1 minute.)
哥 你好
Hello.
(until they're exposed, and they can go up to 1 minute.)
-哥 你好 -哥 你好
- Hello. - Hello.
(They all practice imitating Kwang Soo.)
我是光洙
- Hello, I'm Kwang Soo. - Hello, I'm Kwang Soo.
(They all practice imitating Kwang Soo.)
你好 我是光洙
哥 你好
Hello.
(They all practice imitating Kwang Soo.)
你好
- Who will go first? - Se Chan.
Hello.
- Right. - Hello.
你好
- Hello. - Sure.
Seok Jin, are you willing to play?
哥要挑戰嗎
I should.
試一試吧
No, there's no need for that.
(He's too confident for his poor impression of Kwang Soo.)
-哥 不行 -竭盡全力
- I should give it a try. - Pick someone...
(He's too confident for his poor impression of Kwang Soo.)
還有另一方最好不在家
who isn't home.
(He's too confident for his poor impression of Kwang Soo.)
(It's advantageous if Kwang Soo's acquaintance is outside.)
-應該在外面 -對
- Someone who's outside. - That's right.
(It's advantageous if Kwang Soo's acquaintance is outside.)
在外面走動的人
Someone who's out and about.
(It's advantageous if Kwang Soo's acquaintance is outside.)
-聽不清 -有室外噪音就聽不清了
To mask the sound?
It'll seem less obvious if other sounds get mixed in.
Wait. How about...
-對 -哥 要不
-剛剛從沒跟安普賢打過電話 -普賢
I've never talked to Ahn Bo Hyun on the phone,
- but he texted me. - Really?
-來短信了 -普賢
- Ahn Bo Hyun? - Yes, he texted me.
來短信了
That's perfect.
He won't know my voice since we haven't talked before.
因為第一次打電話
(He might not recognize Kwang Soo's voice.)
-不知道聲音如何 -打電話 這樣挺好
If you call him... Yes, he might not realize it.
(He might not recognize Kwang Soo's voice.)
What did the text say?
說什麼了 內容是什麼
(They have a shot with him.)
-需要提前知道 -就是說辛苦了
- He said I did a good job. - We should know.
(They have a shot with him.)
普賢 普賢
- Perfect. - He told me...
to have a good last day.
- This will work for sure. - I bet it'll work.
這個絕對可以 這個絕對可以
(He calls Bo Hyun right away.)
石鎮哥感覺也可以模仿一下
Even Seok Jin could make it work.
(He calls Bo Hyun right away.)
石鎮哥 來一下
- Do you want to give it a go? - Would it work?
(He calls Bo Hyun right away.)
我來模仿能行嗎
- Do you want to give it a go? - Would it work?
(Enthusiastic Big Nose goes.)
Your voice has been exposed a lot lately.
他是幹什麼的來著
- Who is he though? - He's an actor.
演員 演員
(He gives it a go without even knowing who the receiver is.)
(He answered it!)
-嗯 -喂
- Wait. - Hello?
(He answered it!)
(Will Seok Jin be able to fool Bo Hyun?)
- Hello? - I see that you texted.
-喂 -來短信了
Yes?
- Hello? - I see that you texted.
-喂 -來短信了
(Who is he trying to sound like?)
Yes?
對
(Who is he trying to sound like?)
You did a good job on the show. Has filming ended?
辛苦了 拍攝結束了嗎
Yes, just a minute ago.
嗯 現在結束了哦
I congratulate you on a good job.
(What on earth is that?)
辛苦了 哥
I congratulate you on a good job.
謝謝你 這樣給我來短信哦
Thank you for texting me.
Please don't mention it. It was nothing.
哎 不要這麼說 沒什麼的
(He weirdly slurs the end of his sentence.)
- It was an emotional day today. - Right.
-今天心情有點奇怪 -嗯
(What is he doing?)
- It was an emotional day today. - Right.
謝謝你 普賢
- So I'm grateful. - He's emotionless.
Please don't mention it.
沒什麼 哥
(That's not it, Seok Jin.)
Then...
哪天一起健身吧
We should work out together sometime.
Sounds good. Anytime, Kwang Soo.
好 可以的 哪天都可以
Where exactly do you live again?
好 你是哪個區來著
Seongsu-dong. I live close to your place.
是聖水洞 離哥家很近
(Now he just speaks in his voice.)
-很 很近啊 -這是在跟石鎮哥打電話吧
That's right next to where I live.
(Now he just speaks in his voice.)
Isn't this him just talking to Seok Jin?
We're only five minutes away.
5分鐘就能到
Five minutes? We should meet up then.
(The worst impression of Kwang Soo, which he even gave up on imitating.)
那我們見面吧 我心情也不太好
I haven't been in the best mood these days.
(The worst impression of Kwang Soo, which he even gave up on imitating.)
- His mood? - Call me when you want to work out.
我都可以 都可以
Sure thing. Anyway,
好 謝謝你 以後請你吃飯
(He imitates Seok Jin until the end.)
thank you for the text. I'll treat you to dinner sometime.
好的 隨時聯繫我吧 辛苦了
Sure thing. Please give me a call. Once again, good job.
(But Bo Hyun never noticed it.)
好 等一下
Sure.
(But Bo Hyun never noticed it.)
Bo Hyun!
普賢
(Somehow, Big Nose accomplished the mission by imitating himself.)
- Hello? - Anyway, Seok Jin succeeded?
-普賢 -成功了
(Somehow, Big Nose accomplished the mission by imitating himself.)
Right.
是石鎮哥 石鎮哥
That was Seok Jin on the phone just now.
How could he not know? It sounded completely different.
怎麼能沒發現 完全不一樣啊
- Gosh, well... - It sounded completely different.
(He can't understand it either.)
完全不一樣
Just hang up.
(He can't understand it either.)
不是 普賢啊 這是石鎮哥 怎麼能不知道啊
Bo Hyun, that was Seok Jin. How could you not know?
(He can't understand it either.)
- Anyone could tell. - I thought he cried.
我也覺得完全不像
What?
I knew it didn't sound like him.
明明不是哥的聲音
I thought he sounded different, so I thought he cried.
感覺不像 以為哭了
No.
Even if he cried,
就算哭了聲音也過於不同
(Even if he cried, the voice was completely different.)
- his voice was very different. - Right.
對 我也想問一下
I know. That's why...
(Even if he cried, the voice was completely different.)
I was going to ask,
- Right. - but I thought he sounded upset.
-就是啊 -但是感覺有點憂鬱
You thought he sounded sad, so you couldn't ask?
怕心情不好 沒能問
(Bo Hyun let it go in case Kwang Soo was upset.)
- Okay. - Thank you, Bo Hyun.
(Seok Jin was able to win thanks to Bo Hyun.)
-普賢 謝謝你 -普賢 謝謝你
- Thank you. - Thank you.
(Seok Jin was able to win thanks to Bo Hyun.)
- Thank you. - He fell for this?
居然沒發現
模仿的時候最後都有點感覺對不起他
I started to feel guilty while I was doing it.
可以這樣嗎
You fulfilled the maximum time, so you reduced 300 years.
達到最大值1分鐘
(He was able to last a maximum of 1 minute.)
減少300年
You fulfilled the maximum time, so you reduced 300 years.
(300 years is deducted.)
300 years.
300年
(300 years is deducted.)
That's incredible. That's really incredible.
厲害 真的很厲害
(Thanks to Big Nose, Kwang Soo's release is getting closer.)
This is so funny. How did it work? How interesting.
真的好搞笑
真的可以 好神奇
The quiet that comes after laughing.
這笑完之後一片寂靜
(The quiet after the laughter comes more often today.)
真的 真的去光洙家
Right. We're really going to Kwang Soo's place.
(The quiet after the laughter comes more often today.)
這是去光洙家的路
真的留有餘韻
- There's a lingering feeling. - Right.
(The quiet after the laughter comes more often today.)
- Right. - Right.
(They started at SBS in Mok-dong, )
(and they are getting closer to Kwang Soo's home.)
Seok Jin's sleeping.
石鎮哥睡了
(He was talking about lingering feelings, )
He's sleeping.
哥哥睡了
(He was talking about lingering feelings, )
(but he fell asleep as soon as they stopped filming.)
- Kwang Soo! Congratulations! - Thank you!
光洙祝賀你
Kwang Soo! Congratulations!
謝謝
光洙祝賀你
Kwang Soo! Congratulations!
(Really surprised)
(Why are you congratulating him?)
謝謝
But seriously...
啊 真的
(They continue with the skit as if nothing happened.)
但是感覺真的要這麼做
I think it's right to do that.
(They continue with the skit as if nothing happened.)
-但是這樣才對 -這樣才對
- Right. It's right to do that. - Right.
- It's the right thing to do. - It was too cruel.
這樣才對
(Something's decided.)
但是又有點殘忍
But still...
(Something's decided.)
但是這樣才對
That's the right thing to do.
(Something's decided.)
真的 時間也是
- Even if you consider the time... - Right.
(He can't grasp the situation.)
那都同意了嗎
- So you all agree, right? - Right.
(He can't grasp the situation.)
是的
- We do. - Seok Jin...
就這樣吧
-不是怎麼能這麼做決定 -池石鎮
How could you decide like this though?
- About this, I... - You have to do it like that.
真的 我沒想到最後有這種反轉
I didn't expect such a twist.
Do you agree?
同意了吧
Seok Jin, what should we do? Should we do it like that?
-同意了嗎 -石鎮哥怎麼辦啊 就這樣決定嗎
(Nodding)
- Right. - Then Seok Jin will leave the show.
那池石鎮退出了
(He agreed to leave the show without realizing.)
Gosh, Bo Pil, you're really...
寶弼 真的
(The members and the staff are sincere about teasing Seok Jin.)
- He's so mean. - For the past 11 years...
-真的太壞了 -長長11年間
又會發池石鎮淺睡瞬間
This will be another moment of Jee Seok Jin's light sleep.
(Jee Seok Jin's moment of light sleep)
池石鎮淺睡瞬間
A moment of Jee Seok Jin's light sleep.
(Jee Seok Jin's moment of light sleep)
-嚇一跳 -真的嚇一跳
- Seok Jin was really surprised. - Gosh, I was so surprised.
(Jee Seok Jin's moment of light sleep)
We're arriving at the final reformation venue.
現在快要到達最後一個教化場所
(They arrived at the final reformation venue.)
為了下一個任務
For the next mission,
(They arrived at the final reformation venue.)
李光洙需要指定成員的下車順序
For the next mission,
(Kwang Soo will decide the order in which everyone gets off.)
Kwang Soo will decide the order everyone will get off in.
Send Seok Jin first.
先送走石鎮哥吧
It's not a bad idea to go in that order.
對 按順序來也行
- Shall we start from the front? - 1, 2, 3, 4,
-那從前面開始 -一二三四五六七
- 5, 6, 7. - Right.
What is it? I'm so curious.
是什麼呢 好好奇
(Seok Jin will go first.)
(What's the next mission?)
我去全都 打好基礎
I'll put down the foundations.
(What's the next mission?)
(There's a mysterious mission site before entering...)
Yes?
這次的任務是越瞭解光洙越能減刑的
- In this mission, - Yes?
(There's a mysterious mission site before entering...)
(the final reformation venue.)
- In this mission, - Yes?
You can reduce Kwang Soo's sentence according to how well you know him.
(You can reduce his sentence...)
(according to how well you know Kwang Soo.)
李光洙能力考試
It's the Lee Kwang Soo Aptitude Test.
(according to how well you know Kwang Soo.)
(Lee Kwang Soo Aptitude Test)
好
Right.
(Lee Kwang Soo Aptitude Test)
7名成員回答關於光洙的問題
All seven members will answer a question about Lee Kwang Soo,
(Lee Kwang Soo Aptitude Test)
(All seven members will answer a question about Lee Kwang Soo.)
1名答對的成員可減40年刑
and for each member who gets it right,
(All seven members will answer a question about Lee Kwang Soo.)
(And for each member who gets it right, )
Kwang Soo's sentence will be reduced by 40 years.
(Kwang Soo's sentence will be reduced by 40 years.)
關於光洙的問題嗎
They're questions about Kwang Soo?
(Kwang Soo's sentence will be reduced by 40 years.)
是的
As of this moment, the remaining sentence is 250 years.
(Kwang Soo's sentence will be reduced by 40 years.)
現在李光洙剩餘的刑期有250年
As of this moment, the remaining sentence is 250 years.
(They have about 1 hour left.)
在這裡7名全員都答對了
If all seven members answer correctly,
(They have about 1 hour left.)
(If all 7 members get it right, they can reduce 250 years.)
就能直接結束
the mission will end right away.
(If all 7 members get it right, they can reduce 250 years.)
好的
Okay.
(If all 7 members get it right, they can reduce 250 years.)
(Meanwhile, the other members are waiting for their turn.)
(Looking)
Do I have to divide everything I did with Kwang Soo?
以後跟光洙所做的一切 都需要分配一下嗎
(Now that they're at the final destination, )
(they feel that the time for farewell is much closer.)
I don't know anymore.
不知道該怎麼辦了
(they feel that the time for farewell is much closer.)
不知道該怎麼辦
"I don't know". You just have to do it.
(they feel that the time for farewell is much closer.)
The next person can go out now.
下一位選手請下車
- Haha. - It's Haha.
-HAHA -加油
(Haha who'll go 2nd also gets off the bus.)
加油
I can do it!
(Haha who'll go 2nd also gets off the bus.)
You can do it!
加油
(Haha who'll go 2nd also gets off the bus.)
Haha is on his way.
- Ji Hyo. You can do it! - I'll see you in a bit!
宋智孝 加油
(They send Ji Hyo and So Min with a loud cheer.)
我走了
可以
You can do it!
(They send Ji Hyo and So Min with a loud cheer.)
-宋智孝 加油 -加油
- Song Ji Hyo. You can do it! - You can do it!
(They send Ji Hyo and So Min with a loud cheer.)
- You can do it! - You can do it!
-加油 加油 -加油
(As each member leaves, )
(silence fills the bus.)
OK
Okay.
(silence fills the bus.)
This is the final destination!
來 最後一個場所
Gosh, Jong Kook. Don't look at him like that!
別這樣看 哥
(They spent the day laughing.)
Let's go. Okay.
走吧 OK
(But as the end gets closer, )
They say it's better to get it over with...
早挨打早輕鬆 早知道就先走了
(the word "last" is beginning to hit them more.)
(They take a photo while they wait for their turn.)
(They spent the past 11 years together, )
(and in the future, today will become a distant memory.)
(We will start the final trip down memory lane with Kwang Soo now.)
- Was it hard? - Mine was hard.
很難嗎
我的很難
- Was it hard? - Mine was hard.
(The members have gathered after answering each question.)
哥是什麼
What was your question?
(The members have gathered after answering each question.)
什麼
What?
(The members have gathered after answering each question.)
-問題都 -都不一樣吧
- Were all the questions different? - I think they're all different.
(The members have gathered after answering each question.)
There he is.
來了
(With familiar music, )
Hold on.
這個歌曲
(today's guest enters.)
Why do you keep playing this song?
We can't hear this song anymore.
(today's guest enters.)
這首歌 以後聽不了的歌曲
We can't hear this song anymore.
(Kwang Soo's theme song is being played for this special day.)
以後聽不了了
We can't hear this song anymore.
(Kwang Soo's theme song is being played for this special day.)
- Come in. - Come in.
-來 進來吧 -進來吧
(Kwang Soo's theme song is being played for this special day.)
這原來是個很悲傷的
This song is very sad.
(Kwang Soo's theme song is being played for this special day.)
(The person who turned this great song into...)
Gosh, it's Kwang Soo's last day.
光洙 最後一次真是可惜
(The person who turned this great song into...)
My gosh, it's so sad.
(a comic song takes his seat.)
來 各位都知道
- As you all know, - Yes?
(a comic song takes his seat.)
You all received a question about Kwang Soo as you got off the bus.
下車後每個人都拿到關於李光洙的一道題
(Each member was asked to answer a question on Kwang Soo.)
是的
- Right. - Right.
(Each member was asked to answer a question on Kwang Soo.)
第一位 池石鎮
The first person to get off the bus was Seok Jin.
(Each member was asked to answer a question on Kwang Soo.)
(The 1st runner is Seok Jin.)
His question asked what Kwang Soo's debut project was.
問題是
李光洙的第一部作品
His question asked what Kwang Soo's debut project was.
(What did Lee Kwang Soo debut with?)
I don't think I got it right.
我覺得不是我寫的這個
(Not confident)
Kwang Soo, what project did you debut with?
李光洙先說一下你的出道作品吧
"Here He Comes".
是他來了
("Here He Comes".)
-他來了 -他來了
- "Here He Comes"? - "Here He Comes".
("Here He Comes".)
-這有點難啊 -挺難的
- That one was hard. - That's hard.
("Here He Comes".)
The first question was hard.
出道作很難回答的
(No one knew.)
估計哥哥答不上來了
I don't think he got it right.
(No one knew.)
-答不上來了 -肯定回答錯誤
He didn't get it right.
(No one knew.)
(What did Seok Jin write?)
He couldn't have gotten it right.
- Right. - I was in...
-對啊
"High Kick Through The Roof".
-還有我出演的是
Was it "High Kick Through The Roof"?
啊 穿透屋頂的HighKick
(He wasn't even in it.)
- The first... - How do you really feel?
-好 第一題 -哥真的搞什麼啊
- 191cm. - Right.
190...
(What's Lee Kwang Soo's height and shoe size?)
- 191cm. - Right.
-191 -191
(Height: 191cm)
是的
- 300mm. - 290mm.
(Height: 191cm)
-300 -鞋碼是290
- 300mm. - 290mm.
(Shoe size: 290mm)
- 290mm. - 290mm.
-290 -是290
(Shoe size: 290mm)
- He got it wrong. - He was off by 1cm.
-怎麼寫的 -高了1cm
He was close but didn't get it right.
1cm and 10mm.
-差1cm 差10mm -是290mm
He was close but didn't get it right.
- You wear 300mm. - He was wrong.
你鞋碼明明是300mm
There's a toe that's more rotten.
雙腳都有壞掉的指甲
(Which of the toes is more rotten? Right or Left?)
-最後寫了壞得多的 -是的 壞得多的
The main one.
(Which of the toes is more rotten? Right or Left?)
- Right. That's why... - The right toe.
-所以 -右腳
(Which of the toes is more rotten? Right or Left?)
- What is the answer? - My right toe.
-是右腳 -是右腳
(The answer is right.)
- That's right. - It's his right toe.
-是右腳 -是右腳
(The answer is right.)
-還塗黑過的 -總是說這腳
- He used to paint it. - Back in the day.
(The answer is right.)
(Even So Min who had a 50 percent chance got it wrong.)
- I changed it. - It's his right toe.
-早知道換邊寫了 -是右腳 右腳
(Even So Min who had a 50 percent chance got it wrong.)
之前塗黑過這只腳的
We used to color it with a permanent marker.
(Even So Min who had a 50 percent chance got it wrong.)
Nobody got a single question right.
目前為止連一題都沒答對嗎
(Disappointed)
接下來到劉在錫
Next up is Yu Jae Seok.
(Disappointed)
(After 3 incorrect answers, it's Jae Seok's turn.)
李光洙父親的姓名是
What's Kwang Soo's father's name?
(After 3 incorrect answers, it's Jae Seok's turn.)
I had a hard time remembering.
我真的不太記得了
Did you remember?
記起來了嗎
If you get this right, it would be unbelievable.
哇 答對這題的話就真的太不可思議了
It was a long time ago.
真的過了好久了
- Can you tell us his name first? - I believe that this is his name.
先說一下姓名吧
(What did Jae Seok, the king of memorizing names, write?)
我感覺應該是這個
I believe that this is his name.
(What did Jae Seok, the king of memorizing names, write?)
我感覺應該是這個
I believe that this is his name.
(Lee Jong Ho.)
- "Lee Jong Ho"? - What is his name?
李宗浩
(Lee Jong Ho.)
-好 姓名是 -是對的
His name is Lee Jong Ho.
(Lee Jong Ho.)
是李宗浩沒錯
-對嗎 -對的對的
- Did I get it right? - You got it right!
(Lee Jong Ho.)
-對嗎 -對的對的
- Did I get it right? - You got it right!
(He's surprised too.)
How do you remember the names of celebrities' fathers?
(Jae Seok is the first person to answer correctly.)
連藝人父親的名字都能記得很清楚啊
- It's like "TV Brings Love". - Am I right?
(Jae Seok is the first person to answer correctly.)
-像不像啊 -對嗎
Doesn't it seem like "TV Brings Love"?
(Jae Seok is the first person to answer correctly.)
-像不像啊 -對嗎
- That's incredible. - That's right.
-對的 -厲害了
That's his name!
是那位沒錯
- Right. - Am I right? Is this his name?
-這是對的 -對嗎 這是叔叔的名字嗎
(Everyone's celebrating, )
-對的 -是啊
- I think you're right. - It's like "TV Brings Love".
(Everyone's celebrating, )
How did you know?
你怎麼知道的
(Everyone's celebrating, )
- Are you crying? - Are you crying?
(but Kwang Soo starts to tear up.)
-你在哭嗎 -哭了嗎
Kwang Soo...
(but Kwang Soo starts to tear up.)
光洙
- Are you crying? - All of a sudden?
哭了嗎
Why are you crying?
-突然 突然間 -你幹嘛哭啊
- Why are you crying so suddenly? - This isn't the right timing.
突然間幹嘛呢
- Why are you crying? - Why are you crying?
不是現在啊
-幹嘛哭啊 -因為叔叔
- Why are you crying? - Why are you crying?
(The prisoner starts to cry.)
- He said your father's name. - Why are you crying?
幹嘛哭啊
(The prisoner starts to cry.)
-因為提到了叔叔的姓名 -幹嘛哭啊
- His father was mentioned. - His father.
(The prisoner starts to cry.)
He thought of his father.
幹嘛哭啊
- He was a part of Running Man too. - That's right.
(Kwang Soo's father is special to Running Man too.)
因為提到了叔叔
-叔叔 -因為想起了叔叔
(Kwang Soo's father is special to Running Man too.)
-叔叔也一起拍攝過RM -是的是的
- His father was on the show too. - Right.
(Kwang Soo's father is special to Running Man too.)
叔叔也一起拍攝過的
Hello, sir.
叔叔 您好
He hits me even when there aren't any cameras.
他在沒有攝像頭的地方也打我
(He is a special guest who joined us a few times with his kind smile.)
Hey.
I saw that you got hit 3 or 4 times yesterday too.
(He is a special guest who joined us a few times with his kind smile.)
你昨天也被打了三四下啊
- Really? - He was improvising.
(He is a special guest who joined us a few times with his kind smile.)
-叔叔真的 -即興發揮真的厲害
- Really? - He was improvising.
- How did you... - But this...
怎麼會把這個
(Jae Seok remembered his name.)
If this is the case, I know Seok Jin's father's name...
但是現在這個樣子的話
(Jae Seok remembered his name.)
既然說過石鎮哥 光洙父親的名字
as well as Kwang Soo's father.
(Jae Seok remembered his name.)
- Right. - I must memorize everyone's names.
那都得記下來了
- Next was Jong Kook. - Right.
-好 接下來到了金鐘國 -嗯
(Next is Jong Kook.)
是答案寫得最快的一位
He wrote the answer down the fastest.
(Next is Jong Kook.)
(He was the fastest one to write down the answer.)
Really?
-是嗎 -真的嗎
(He was the fastest one to write down the answer.)
- I wrote it as soon as I heard it. - He really did.
-我聽到問題立刻寫了答案 -馬上就寫了
What's the design of Kwang Soo's bike?
李光洙自行車的花紋是
Zebra.
斑馬紋 斑馬紋
- That's correct. - Right.
-沒錯 -沒錯
- The answer is? - Zebra.
-正確答案是 -是斑馬紋沒錯
- Of course. - He's seen it.
我知道的 不可能不知道
I know what it looks like. It's hard for me not to know.
I've seen it before.
我有看到過的 一起騎自行車
We went cycling together...
(The 11 years of memory goes beyond the filming set.)
and rode around the Han River for four hours.
有一起在漢江邊騎過4個小時
(The 11 years of memory goes beyond the filming set.)
His sofa has a zebra print too.
-沙發也是斑馬紋 -斑馬紋 斑馬紋
(They know each other's taste very well.)
- Right. It's zebra. - Right.
-內褲也是的 -內褲也是斑馬紋
- His underwear is zebra print too. - His underwear too.
(They know each other's taste very well.)
What's the title of the movie that Kwang Soo is filming right now?
李光洙現在所拍攝的電影題目是
- "Happy New Year". - "Happy New Year".
-新年快樂 -新年快樂 請公開答案
Please show us what you wrote.
你怎麼知道的
(Even Ji Hyo answered the question correctly.)
- How did you know? - How did you know?
你怎麼知道的
- It's because she's an actress. - She got it right.
(Even Ji Hyo answered the question correctly.)
-絕了 -是啊
- That's right. - Thank you. I'm touched.
(Even Ji Hyo answered the question correctly.)
(Touched)
很感謝 很感動啊 很感動
This is the last question.
(Touched)
最後的問題
This is the last question.
(It's now Se Chan's turn.)
It was "What is Lee Kwang Soo's phone number?"
李光洙的手機號碼是什麼
- What? - This is hard.
-好難 -好難
- This is hard. - This is really hard.
真的很難
- Nobody memorizes numbers anymore. - Right.
-其實最近不怎麼記號碼的 -是的
(Nowadays people don't memorize it unless it's your family's.)
If he gets four consecutive numbers right,
四位四位的寫 不管是哪四位
(Nowadays people don't memorize it unless it's your family's.)
we will count that as correct.
能答對的話便認可
(What about Se Chan who's closest to Kwang Soo?)
- Let's look at your answer. - Okay.
-來看一下吧 -好的
(What about Se Chan who's closest to Kwang Soo?)
Out of the eight numbers?
在8個數字中
010-2753-8...
010-21753-8XX
I've never even heard of this number before.
這是我這輩子第一次聽說的號碼
Seriously.
我真的...
(The moving moment is ruined.)
I seriously... Gosh, this is...
我真的 真的這個
My tears just dried up.
眼淚瞬間收回的感覺是這樣的啊
He didn't get a single number correct.
沒1個數字是對的
- I thought it was right. - Me too.
-我還以為是對的 -我以為是對的
(He didn't get one number right.)
He sounded so confident.
說得信誓旦旦的
(He didn't get one number right.)
Why were you so confident?
你為什麼表現得這麼自信
It's not even close.
不對 根本不對
I'm sorry. I always look up your name.
對不起 哥
(He trusted Se Chan, but he got it wrong.)
我一直都是發消息給你的
- My tears dried up too. - Isn't this too hard?
(He trusted Se Chan, but he got it wrong.)
但你的眼淚真的瞬間收回去了
As a result, you got three questions right.
總之一共答對了3題
(Jae Seok, Jong Kook, and Ji Hyo answered the questions.)
For each question, you got 40 years, so it will be reduced by 120 years.
每題減去40年 一共減去120年
(He gets 40 years deducted per question.)
- How many years do we have left? - How much is left?
還剩下多少年
(120 years reduced, )
現在還剩下多少年
You guys have 130 years left, and the current time is...
(120 years reduced, )
(and he still has 130 years left.)
還剩下130年
現在剛過5點59分
(and he still has 130 years left.)
It just turned 5:59pm.
(Right now, it's 5:59pm.)
-這種程度的話 -那光洙得被關進去了啊
- That means Kwang Soo... - Then Kwang Soo...
(Right now, it's 5:59pm.)
will be imprisoned.
- He can just go in right now. - Right.
感覺可以去監獄裡生活了
(He has to reduce 130 years in 30 minutes.)
If you combine what you got on the bus,
現在加上剛剛在大巴上獲得的減刑
(Combining the bus mission, )
you get a total of three chances to choose gifts at random.
進行總共3次的禮物抓鬮
(he has 3 chances to choose gifts at random.)
What is it this time?
這次的是什麼啊
This time, it is a pair of trendy and expensive pants.
(Among 3 gifts, )
這次是很潮的最高級褲子
This time, it is a pair of trendy and expensive pants.
(the first one is an expensive pair of pants.)
- What's trendy and expensive? - What is trendy?
很潮的最高級褲子是什麼啊
(the first one is an expensive pair of pants.)
I think these pants might be from a popular brand.
很潮的物品
I hope you win today.
感覺是品牌的
(He means it.)
今天真的希望你能拿到禮物
- I hope you win. - Seriously. We're being serious.
(He means it.)
-我希望你能拿到 -我們是真心的
- The right one? - Yes. Go ahead.
(If it's a hard-boiled egg, he gets a pair of expensive pants.)
-右邊 -OK
This might be a splash.
(If it's a hard-boiled egg, he gets a pair of expensive pants.)
這樣的話就聽命吧
You have to hit it on your forehead.
(If it's a hard-boiled egg, he gets a pair of expensive pants.)
額頭額頭 得打到額頭上
You have to hit it on your forehead.
(Hard-boiled egg)
(Kwang Soo is doing well today. He gets a pair of nice pants.)
- An expensive bedding set. - Go ahead.
最高級床品套裝
(Next is an expensive bedding set.)
1 2 3
- An expensive bedding set. - Go ahead.
(Another hard-boiled egg?)
(He goes beyond everyone's expectations...)
Did you see that? Why is he doing so good today?
對吧
他的感覺為什麼這麼好
Did you see that? Why is he doing so good today?
(and gets the bedding too.)
Hey. It's your favorite, champagne.
-是你喜歡的香檳 -香檳
(With continuous miracles, next is the champagne.)
- You'll get a lot of gifts today. - You can do it.
今天勝率挺高的
(He gets another hard-boiled egg.)
- What's with him today? - I can't believe it.
(He can't believe his luck on his last day.)
他今天怎麼了
你今天怎麼回事
- Gosh, this is... - I can't believe it.
(He can't believe his luck on his last day.)
哇 這個
- Gosh, this is... - I can't believe it.
無法置信 是不是兩個都是熟雞蛋啊
Aren't they both hard-boiled eggs? I can't believe this.
(Suspicious)
無法置信
- You can tell when you spin it. - What's with you both?
(Suspicious)
轉一下這個就知道了
- See? - You're right.
怎麼回事
-你看這個 -是啊
Raw eggs don't spin.
生的轉不起來啊
(Hard-boiled eggs spin well, and raw eggs don't.)
-是的 -真的是生雞蛋
Right. These are raw eggs.
(Hard-boiled eggs spin well, and raw eggs don't.)
是誒
- You're right. - Hard-boiled eggs spin.
(Hard-boiled eggs spin well, and raw eggs don't.)
-熟雞蛋會轉起來的 -會轉起來的
- You're right. - Hard-boiled eggs spin.
(The other egg is raw. It's all Kwang Soo's luck.)
- Raw eggs don't. - This one doesn't.
這個轉不起來
Now that it's time for Kwang Soo to leave,
(The other egg is raw. It's all Kwang Soo's luck.)
估計是因為光洙快要走了
his luck is going back to normal.
所以運氣變得正常了
Hey, Bo Pil, why are you putting your head down?
寶弼啊 你為什麼躲在那啊
(Even the production crew is flustered by what's happening.)
As a result you were successful all three times.
所以現在3個禮物全部獲取成功
(He unbelievably wins all 3 gifts.)
- See? - No way.
無法置信
- He got it all. - You're incredibly lucky today.
(He unbelievably wins all 3 gifts.)
As a result, you have about 20 minutes left.
所以現在還剩下20多分鐘
(He has 20 minutes left.)
The time you have left is 130 years.
還剩下130年
(He must reduce 130 years before time's up.)
I'll give you the mission to take care of the 130 years.
立刻發佈可以減去130年刑量的任務
In this mission, Unlucky Kwang Soo's soulmate,
(The last mission)
這次任務是臭手李光洙永遠的夥伴
In this mission, Unlucky Kwang Soo's soulmate,
the pirate, must come out to get rid of the remaining years.
(The pirate must come out to get rid of the remaining sentence.)
只有桶大叔跳出來才消除剩餘刑量的
我最後的桶大叔
My Last Pirate Roulette.
(The pirate must come out to get rid of the remaining sentence.)
(My Last Pirate Roulette)
- It has to come out? - My Last Pirate Roulette.
-跳出來才行啊 -我最後的桶大叔
When you stab the pirate with the knife,
往桶大叔裡插刀時
you will get 150 years reduced if you get it on the 1st try,
一次性跳出的話減去150年
140 years reduced if you get it on the 2nd try,
第二次跳出的話減去140年
130 years on the 3rd try, and 120 years on the 4th try.
第三次跳出的話減去130年
第四次跳出的話減去120年
We will continue until the 8th player like this.
就這樣直到第8位選手
(Once the 8th player has gone, )
Once the 8th player has gone,
(the pirate gets reset, and you can try again.)
第8位選手挑戰完畢後
the pirate gets reset, and you can try again.
(the pirate gets reset, and you can try again.)
桶叔叔會被重置
可以重新挑戰
(the pirate gets reset, and you can try again.)
- However, that much time will pass, - Right.
-但是時間也一直在流逝 -是啊
(However, if the mission continues, )
And if that's the case,
有可能在剩下的20分鐘裡
(he'll run out of time and won't be able to get out.)
you may not get rid of it all within 20 minutes.
無法清完剩下的量刑
It will be best for you to hurry.
(It's always been easy for Kwang Soo, but what about today?)
-最好快一點進行 -快點減吧 快點減
Let's hurry.
(It's always been easy for Kwang Soo, but what about today?)
I'll give it to you.
我這就拿給你們
(It's always been easy for Kwang Soo, but what about today?)
It's 150 years if I get it on my 1st try?
我先來嗎 第一次
(Kwang Soo, the pirate roulette expert)
It's impossible to do that.
第一次不可能彈出來
(Kwang Soo, the pirate roulette expert)
- You've done it before. - You have.
-但是你做到過 -有過
It would be cool if you do it at the last moment and leave.
最後再展示一次
(The probability is very low. Other guys instigate him.)
-然後離開也可能挺帥的 -沒錯
- Right. - Did the spirit of variety shows...
(The probability is very low. Other guys instigate him.)
綜藝神最後可能降臨了
come at the end?
(The probability is very low. Other guys instigate him.)
(He catches his breath and gives it a try.)
- Don't be burdened. - I don't know.
不要有壓力
(He catches his breath and gives it a try.)
-我也拿不準了 -就玩唄
- I'll just... - Right. It's impossible.
(He catches his breath and gives it a try.)
當然了 有可能的
- I'll just... - Right. It's impossible.
(It came out!)
It popped out!
(He succeeded on the first try.)
(It's really shocking.)
- Kwang Soo... You... - Hey.
- Does this make sense? - You're insane.
(It's really shocking.)
這像話嗎
喂 瘋了吧
This isn't a lie.
這是真的嗎
(Everyone's flustered for real.)
Really?
真的嗎
(Everyone's flustered for real.)
- Did you mark it? - You can't mark it.
什麼啊
你做標記了嗎
- Did you mark it? - You can't mark it.
(The roulette resets every time.)
這個做不了標記的 不知道位置在哪裡
You don't know where it would be. Every time...
(The roulette resets every time.)
每次都不一樣
I don't think they'll believe this.
(The roulette resets every time.)
感覺觀眾們會不相信
Because it's random...
因為是隨機的
No, there's nothing here.
(Both production crew and members are frozen.)
沒有 沒有
Don't go!
(Both production crew and members are frozen.)
別走了
Does this make sense?
(Both production crew and members are frozen.)
這像話嗎
Just don't go!
乾脆別走了
Why are you leaving when you're like this?
為什麼要走
There really is a spirit of variety shows!
都這樣了
(Excited)
-這是真的有綜藝神 -看來是真的有
Seriously.
(Excited)
The person behind us must be surprised too.
坐在後面的那位 嚇到了吧
- Weren't you surprised? - He looks really surprised.
是吧
非常吃驚吧
- You saw everything, right? - We didn't plan this, right?
(Even the LP bar owner can't believe what he saw.)
-看到了吧 -看到了吧 我們沒做手腳
- Does this make sense? - How does this make sense?
(Even the LP bar owner can't believe what he saw.)
-對吧 -這像話嗎
- Does this make sense? - How does this make sense?
這像話嗎
(Kwang Soo succeeded in reducing his sentence by 150 years.)
It doesn't make sense, but with 12 minutes left, at 6:18pm,
完全不像話的
在還剩12分鐘的6點18分時
It doesn't make sense, but with 12 minutes left, at 6:18pm,
(At 6:18pm with 12 minutes remaining)
Lee Kwang Soo is released after serving his full sentence.
李光洙刑滿出獄
(Lee Kwang Soo is released after serving his full sentence.)
- Does this make sense? - The expression sounds a bit...
這像話嗎
哎呀 單詞
- Does this make sense? - The expression sounds a bit...
(After serving his full sentence?)
- Does this make sense? - He's being released.
-這像話嗎 -出獄了
(After serving his full sentence?)
There must be ghosts.
真的有鬼
- Seriously. - I'm at a loss for words.
(The deity of variety looked after Kwang Soo.)
真的
-難以置信 -好可怕
It's so scary.
(The deity of variety looked after Kwang Soo.)
Are we just letting him go? Or are we clinging onto him?
這是要好好地送走 還是要挽留
(He will make a wonderful finale.)
- We're being cool. - We're being cool, right?
帥氣地送走
(He will make a wonderful finale.)
是要帥氣地送走
- This is your last gift. - I have chills.
(He will make a wonderful finale.)
最後的禮物
- This is your last gift. - I have chills.
起雞皮疙瘩了都
(It's his last chance to choose a gift at random.)
When will you get to do this again?
光洙啊 你還什麼時候能有機會玩啊
(It's his last chance to choose a gift at random.)
- At this timing, - You should go.
-現在 -走吧
現在是會爆開的時間點 神降臨了
It's time to let things explode.
(So far, he got 5 out of 6 gifts.)
You got everything but the hoodie.
除了連帽衛衣 都得到了
(A trendy interior frame)
Okay.
OK
(A trendy interior frame)
- It's the trendy decorative frame. - A frame.
-來 很潮的裝飾畫框 -畫框 OK
(Will he be able to get the frame too?)
- Okay. - A frame.
畫框
It will look really pretty in your home.
(Will he be able to get the frame too?)
擺在家裡很好看的
- Look at that. - In the end, this happened.
(Raw egg)
最後還這樣
(The deity of variety has created the timing for this song.)
So this is how the spirit of variety shows...
綜藝神最後就這樣送走了他
(The last touch of the deity of variety)
sends Kwang Soo off in the end.
光洙
He did this for you.
(The last touch of the deity of variety)
神的旨意
He did this for you.
(Cracking)
(The last hard-boiled egg isn't chosen by Kwang Soo.)
- That's right. - As a result,
好了好了好了
(The last hard-boiled egg isn't chosen by Kwang Soo.)
所以李光洙獲得的禮物是
the gifts that Kwang Soo received are...
(The last hard-boiled egg isn't chosen by Kwang Soo.)
a bag, sound bar, pants, bedding, and champagne.
包 音響 褲子 床品套裝 香檳
You weren't unlucky today.
今天不是臭手呢
(It's a big development to get 5 out of 7.)
- This... - You were blessed.
-這個 -是祝福啊 祝福
(It's a big development to get 5 out of 7.)
In any case, you got rid of all 1,050 years of the sentence.
-總之 李光洙的1050年全部減刑成功 -嗯嗯
(Kwang Soo reduced all 1,050 years successfully.)
- Right. - Right.
The photos we took today have been printed...
(Kwang Soo reduced all 1,050 years successfully.)
一整天拍的照片 正在旁邊洗著呢
The photos we took today have been printed...
(While getting pictures developed, )
- and are on their way. Yes. - Are they?
-在洗嗎 -嗯
(While getting pictures developed, )
In the meanwhile, since we're at an LP bar,
既然咱們來到了LP廳
(they'll have time to write a memory about Kwang Soo.)
each of you can write a message,
各自寫一小段信
(they'll have time to write a memory about Kwang Soo.)
and we can listen to some songs.
各聽一首歌吧
(they'll have time to write a memory about Kwang Soo.)
Since one song per person is too many,
每個人都聽一首的話太多了
(Everyone will make a request for one song.)
the four older guys will request one song,
4位哥哥共同申請一首歌
(Everyone will make a request for one song.)
and Ji Hyo and the two youngest members...
智孝和弟弟妹妹們再選一首歌
(Everyone will make a request for one song.)
will request a song.
- Let's make it light. - Of course.
要寫得不那麼煽情
當然了
We need to make it light.
得寫得不煽情
- We'll make it light, okay? - Right.
(The oldest guys hate things that make them cringe.)
-光洙啊 我們就不煽情了 -當然了
(While they all start writing carefully, )
- It's already... - 30?
這麼快
(While they all start writing carefully, )
(the LP bar owner begins choosing the song.)
(It's hard to see the members...)
(acting so serious and sentimental on Running Man.)
(With every word that they write down, )
(they reminisce bits of their memories.)
I feel sad as I'm thinking about what to write.
真要寫了覺得有點難過
It's starting to hit me now that I'm writing this.
-要寫信才有了點實感 -是啊 這才
Me too. This is...
A little bit.
就一點 也就一點
(What does Kwang Soo want to say to the members as he leaves?)
When we read our messages, the music...
行啊 一會兒讀的時候的音樂
Okay.
Do you want to start with the older members first?
先從哥哥們的開始讀吧
(The older members will go first.)
久違地給光洙畫得帥一點
I should draw a nice picture of Kwang Soo.
(The older members will go first.)
-先看池石鎮的開始 -從我開始嗎
- We'll start with Seok Jin. - Me?
(The older members will go first.)
- Seok Jin is starting. - Seok Sam...
先看石鎮哥的信
(Seok Jin will read his letter first.)
-我們石三哥 -我寫的很平淡
- I wrote it calmly. I just... - Okay.
(Seok Jin will read his letter first.)
就那麼寫的
- You can start. - Should I start?
-可以讀了嗎 -讀吧
Don't cry.
別哭
- Don't cry. - I don't even know.
我也不管了
(He holds back his emotions so that he won't cry, but he's tearing up.)
I don't even know.
我也不管了
(He holds back his emotions so that he won't cry, but he's tearing up.)
Whose is it?
是誰的 是誰的信
- I'll read it. - It's Seok Jin's.
我幫你讀
-石鎮哥 是石鎮哥的 -別哭
Don't cry.
This one is from Seok Jin.
是石鎮哥的 是石鎮哥的
"It has already been 11 years since I first met you."
光洙啊 已經認識你11年了
"You were just Long Legs Lee Kwang Soo whom I met at work,"
對我來說本來只是在節目中遇到的
大高個李光洙
"but now you're my little brother whom I'll be with forever."
現在卻成了要相處一輩子的弟弟李光洙
"Kwang Soo."
光洙啊 和你一起喊必觸cross的時候
"I was happy when I shouted..."
"'Feeling! Intuition! Cross!' with you."
我很幸福
"I was happy when I shouted..."
和你一起喊必觸cross時候我很幸福
(He skipped the development and went straight to saying he's happy.)
"'Feeling! Intuition! Cross!' with you."
He ruined the moment.
(He skipped the development and went straight to saying he's happy.)
-突然破壞感動 破壞感動 -突然
He ruined the moment.
(The moving moment was broken into pieces.)
真是的 哥
- He ruined the moment so suddenly. - So suddenly.
(The moving moment was broken into pieces.)
-突然破壞感動 破壞感動 -突然
- He ruined the moment so suddenly. - So suddenly.
- My gosh. - Gosh, Seok Jin is...
哥
"'Feeling! Intuition! Cross!' might've been nothing to others,"
在別人看來什麼也不是的必觸cross
"but I was sincerely grateful for each moment of it."
每時每刻對我來說真的是很感謝的瞬間
"Kwang Soo, you are kind and cool. One day..."
比誰都善良的光洙
比誰都帥氣的光洙 在某一天
Easy, or Lee Jee, like Lee Kwang Soo and Jee Seok Jin.
easy easy 李光洙 池石鎮
You guys are incredible.
真厲害
(The Lee Jee Brothers were famous for being the weaklings, )
- This is no big deal. - You guys are incredible.
-這個主意是從哪裡冒出來的
-節目組真的太厲害了
(The Lee Jee Brothers were famous for being the weaklings, )
We are Lee Jee
我們是 easy
(but whenever they were together, they were quite reliable.)
但是不會 easy
But we are not easy
(but whenever they were together, they were quite reliable.)
(They have good feelings and good intuition.)
-必 -觸
- Feeling! - Intuition!
(They have good feelings and good intuition.)
cross
- Cross! - Cross!
(They have good feelings and good intuition.)
"Kwang Soo, let's see each other forever."
光洙 我們永遠在一起吧
"Let's be friends forever. Even if you're not on Running Man,"
就算不在Running Man我們也是家人
"we're family. I love you, Kwang Soo."
光洙 我愛你
That's what he wrote.
是這樣寫的
Why did your handwriting get so big as it progressed?
-越往後 字體變得越大 -哥
- Right. - Well...
不是 就是
I experienced my tears drying up again.
現在又經歷了一次眼淚嗖的憋回去的經歷
(As it went beyond five lines, he began to scribble it down.)
- This time it's my turn. - Okay.
等一下 這次是我
(They continue with Jae Seok's message.)
"To my beloved brother Kwang Soo."
給親愛的弟弟光洙
"It has already been 11 years since we started Running Man."
和你一起參與Running Man已經11年了
"It's hard to put into words how much effort you put in."
這期間真的辛苦到了
無法用言語來形容的程度 辛苦了
"You did so well."
雖然不知道以後該打斷誰的話 讓誰騎肩膀
"I don't know who to interrupt..."
"and who to ask for piggyback rides anymore,"
"but I think it will end up being Se Chan or Seok Jin."
暫時的想法 我想應該是世燦和石鎮哥吧
(Me?)
He's telling him not to be worried.
不用擔心
(Me?)
He's telling him not to be worried.
My tears are drying up.
眼淚一下子就憋回去了
(He makes a suggestion for a substitution out of nowhere.)
I'm going to suffer more because of you.
因為你我更累了
(He makes a suggestion for a substitution out of nowhere.)
My tears don't go beyond this point.
眼淚從這裡流不下來
(He only thinks about joking around.)
- Don't worry. - He's saying he has alternatives.
-不用擔心 光洙 -有的是
Right. I have alternatives. It could be Se Chan or Seok Jin.
有的是
先世燦和石鎮哥來就可以了
"It will feel empty and be hard without you around,"
沒有你的話 會很空虛 會很累
"but don't worry about us."
不要擔心我們
不要擔心我們 想做什麼就做什麼吧
"Do everything that you've wanted to do."
光洙 我們經常見面吧
"Let's see each other often."
"Call me if you ever need anything. Thank you, Kwang Soo."
有什麼事常給我打電話 謝謝你 光洙
"It wasn't boring because of you."
因為你沒那麼無聊
Gosh, I...
真的
"It wasn't boring because of you."
因為你沒那麼無聊
Whenever we had a shoot,
真的 來錄節目的話
雖然整體上也如此
Kwang Soo kept me from feeling bored.
因為光洙不無聊
Se Chan and Seok Jin should play that role from now on.
感覺世燦和哥哥要扮演那個角色
- We will work hard. - You aren't transferring duties.
嗯 我會努力的 大哥
現在不是交接的時候啊
- Kwang Soo. - Look at him.
光洙 光洙
You are giving him no chance to cry.
他本來想流眼淚的 但是一下子就憋回去了
(Retirement ceremony of Jae Seok's toy)
Since Seok Jin has a bad back, I will give you piggyback rides.
石鎮哥的腰不太好
(Retirement ceremony of Jae Seok's toy)
-騎肩膀由我 -騎肩膀由你來
- Give me piggyback rides. - I will strengthen my legs.
(Retirement ceremony of Jae Seok's toy)
我會努力增強下肢力量
- Give me piggyback rides. - I will strengthen my legs.
(Jae Seok's toy spot became empty after 11 years.)
Jong Kook can do it too.
或者叫鐘國也行
(Jae Seok's toy spot became empty after 11 years.)
Kwang Soo really kept us from getting bored.
但是因為光洙確實不無聊
鐘國的 鐘國的
Let's read Jong Kook's letter.
(Jong Kook's letter)
- Is it mine? - Read Jong Kook's letter.
-讀一下 -是我的嗎
-你來讀一下鐘國的 -好
"I don't know why it was so fun."
不知道為什麼那麼開心
"We used to laugh every time our eyes met."
只是對視也那樣咯咯笑著的我們
"I thought we would stay this way..."
就這樣認為我們好像永遠都不會變
"Stay this way forever."
而且比任何人都覺得堅持到最後會是光洙
"And I thought..."
"you would be there until the end,"
"which is why I think I feel even sadder."
所以更加遺憾
"We won't be together on Running Man anymore,"
雖然不能像往常一樣
在Running Man裡一起參與
"but let's be together for the rest of our lives."
剩下的人生一直在一起吧
"Be healthy always, you punk."
要一直健康 你這傢伙
(Be healthy always, you punk.)
- This is a song for you. - Here you go.
your song 是獻給你的歌 your song
(Be healthy always, you punk.)
- Seriously. - Take the drawing too.
光洙 把畫也拿走吧
- My goodness. - He drew Kwang Soo nicely.
Thank you.
-什麼時候畫的啊 -謝謝 哥
(Jong Kook shyly handed over...)
他有多少個才能啊
(a portrait of Kwang Soo he drew.)
- Seriously. - Take the drawing too.
把畫也拿走吧
(a portrait of Kwang Soo he drew.)
My goodness.
-什麼時候畫的啊 -謝謝 哥
- He drew Kwang Soo so nicely. - Thank you.
How many talents does he have?
他有多少個才能啊 -大概有3個
About three.
Singing, variety shows, and drawing.
-唱歌 綜藝 畫畫 -原來如此
(The man of 3 skills smiles shyly.)
- I see. - Yes.
加上運動是4個
If we include exercising, that makes four.
(The man of 3 skills smiles shyly.)
(Next is Haha's letter.)
"To my younger brother, Kwang Soo. To my lovely Kwang Soo."
致我弟弟光洙 親愛的光洙
"Hello, Kwang Soo. It's me, Haha."
你好光洙啊 是東熏哥
"Since I saw you every week for the past 11 years,"
因為是11年來每週見面的我們光洙
"I feel like I will see you next week..."
理所當然以為是下周也能見到的光洙
"as well."
一直以來光洙盡了全力
"It's because you did your best..."
認真地展現出了極限的努力
"and showed an incredible amount of effort..."
"that so many viewers are upset..."
感覺許多觀眾們都會很遺憾並且一起傷心呢
"and as sad as we are."
"You worked hard."
辛苦了
"Kwang Soo, who will I tease now?"
光洙啊 現在要捉弄誰呢
"Who will I con now?"
現在誰來騙人呢
"With whom will I stay up all night talking?"
現在該跟誰徹夜聊天呢
"I love you."
愛你
"I will pray that you stay dazzling and cool..."
無論在哪兒都能夠閃閃發光
"and realize your dreams no matter where you are."
帥氣地實現追求的夢想 我為你祈禱
"I love you, Kwang Soo!"
愛你 我們光洙
"Stay healthy and happy."
保重 一定要幸福
"This is a passionate goodbye. From Haha."
熱烈地與你道別 東熏哥
- Toy's song. - "Passionate Goodbye".
Toy的
(The guys requested "Passionate Goodbye" by Toy.)
-火熱的告別 -火熱的告別
- "Passionate Goodbye". - "Passionate Goodbye" is nice.
(The guys requested "Passionate Goodbye" by Toy.)
很好 很好 火熱的告別不錯
- All right. - "Passionate Goodbye" is nice.
(The guys requested "Passionate Goodbye" by Toy.)
火熱的告別
"Passionate Goodbye".
(The guys requested "Passionate Goodbye" by Toy.)
火熱的告別
- "Passionate Goodbye" is nice. - All right.
火熱的告別 很好
"Passionate Goodbye" is nice.
很好 火熱的告別不錯
(This is a passionate goodbye. From Haha.)
- It's a very nice song. - It's really nice.
-這首歌真的很好 -非常好
- I think it's perfect. - It's really nice.
感覺正合適
(Kwang Soo, )
太好了 開心的再見
It's a cheerful goodbye.
(Kwang Soo, )
Yu Hui Yeol has only one talent.
(Kwang Soo, it's a happy, cheerful, and passionate goodbye!)
Only one talent.
(As friends and colleagues, they stayed by Kwang Soo's side.)
(Seok Jin, Jae Seok, )
(Jong Kook, )
(and Haha)
- Five. - Gosh, what was that?
4 5
(In his mid-20s, Kwang Soo was the immature youngest member.)
怎麼這麼長
Count to three, okay?
(In his mid-20s, Kwang Soo was the immature youngest member.)
It's because of you!
因為你真的是沒一件事能成的 真的
(He truly liked and cherished Kwang Soo.)
- No! - Nothing is going right.
等一下 我先來
- Hold on. Let me go first. - Why are you cutting?
(He truly liked and cherished Kwang Soo.)
-好的 -為什麼啊
- Hold on. Let me go first. - Why are you cutting?
- What? What is it? - It's like a party.
怎麼了 怎麼這樣
(The man who is number 1 at teasing Kwang Soo, Jae Seok)
因為像是開宴會
- What? - Kwang Soo.
(The man who is number 1 at teasing Kwang Soo, Jae Seok)
- Hold on. - That's how it's done!
本來就是這樣做的
(Despite being scared of him, )
(Kwang Soo turned to him first in times of need.)
(Kwang Soo's moral support, Jong Kook)
找錯人了吧
We did it.
(Kwang Soo's forever ally, Seok Jin)
We look like beggars.
這是叫花子吧
(Kwang Soo's forever older brother, Haha)
- Let's go! - Yes!
(They are precious men who filled Kwang Soo's 11 years...)
- High heels - High heels
光洙啊你今天好帥
- Kwang Soo, you are cool today. - Gosh, Seok Jin.
(They are precious men who filled Kwang Soo's 11 years...)
- Hey! - My goodness.
(with happiness.)
(And as Kwang Soo was once to the others, )
(Se Chan became Kwang Soo's happiness.)
Look at Se Chan.
Se Chan.
Se Chan, come on.
(The youngest members burst out in tears.)
(Kwang Soo was Se Chan and So Min's biggest support.)
Don't cry.
不要哭
(Kwang Soo was Se Chan and So Min's biggest support.)
Why are you crying?
為什麼哭啊
(Their hearts are full of sadness, )
(but they will say a passionate goodbye.)
再見
All right.
是啊 很好
- My goodness. - That was nice.
(It's Ji Hyo and the youngest members' turn.)
現在 接下來
The next ones are...
(It's Ji Hyo and the youngest members' turn.)
Se Chan, So Min, and Ji Hyo.
世燦 昭旻 宋智孝
(It's Ji Hyo and the youngest members' turn.)
"During the mean, happy, exhausting,"
討厭的時候也是 幸福的時候也是
辛苦的時候也是
"stressful, touching moments..."
覺得吃力時候也是 艱難的時候也是
"and when we went to unfamiliar places, and saw..."
去到陌生地方的時候也是
神奇的東西
What is this letter?
這是什麼字啊
"And saw fascinating things".
看到神奇的東西的時候也是
"And saw fascinating things,"
"thank you..."
11年
- "Thank you..." - Seriously.
"Thank you for staying with me through thick and thin..."
11年時間陪伴在身邊
(Ji Hyo's hand-written letter is harder to crack than a code.)
"for the past 11 years."
與我一起經歷那一切
(Ji Hyo's hand-written letter is harder to crack than a code.)
謝謝你 謝謝你
"Thank you. You worked hard."
(Ji Hyo's hand-written letter is harder to crack than a code.)
辛苦了李光洙 我的弟弟李光洙
"Kwang Soo, you are my younger brother."
"I love you, Kwang Soo."
最後 愛你 光洙啊
That's simple.
很簡單呢
(She's extremely composing.)
- That suits Ji Hyo. - Is that all?
很符合智孝姐姐
(She's extremely composing.)
-結束了嗎 -很簡單
- That's simple. - That's all.
(She's extremely composing.)
- Is that all? - That's healthy.
-結束了 -啊結束了啊 -很健康
(Ji Hyo stayed the most composed.)
李光洙 我的弟弟李光洙
"Kwang Soo, you are my younger brother."
(Ji Hyo stayed the most composed.)
(Two hours later, )
(she stayed behind after the shoot...)
(to write the words...)
"Kwang Soo, it's me."
光洙啊 是姐姐
(she was too shy to deliver in a letter.)
"Like I said earlier,"
其實姐姐剛剛也說了
"it still doesn't feel real to me."
姐姐還沒有實感
(She even recorded it.)
"I think deep sadness will hit me and make me crumble..."
對於總是在那裡的你會不在這件事
(She even recorded it.)
"when it hits me that you are no longer here."
雖然感覺如果某一天突然意識到
將會悲傷得無法承受
"Visit whenever you miss us."
無論何時都可以來找我們
如果想念我們的話
"I love you, Kwang Soo."
愛你 光洙啊
- So Min's letter. - So Min's letter.
-昭旻的 -昭旻的
(So Min's letter)
"Kwang Soo."
光洙哥哥
"I am really thankful that I got to know you..."
在這說短不短說長不長的時間裡
"during the time that is either short or long."
非常感謝能夠與你結緣
"I am really thankful for the unforgettable memories."
謝謝你給了我一輩子都忘不了的回憶作為禮物
"I will pray for you each step of the way,"
哥哥的每一步我都會在心裡為你祈禱的
"and I will keep the show going."
我們會好好堅守的
"Visit Running Man anytime. We will be waiting."
歡迎你隨時到running man來玩兒
我們等你
All right.
(Se Chan's letter comes next.)
Okay.
好 梁世Bali
(Se Chan's letter comes next.)
Yangsebari.
"Kwang Soo, you worked hard for the past 11 years."
光洙哥 11年來辛苦了
"I was happy to spend four years with you."
和哥哥在一起4年的時間裡 很幸福
"We used to call each other after every shoot..."
拍攝結束後 每次通電話
"and have long conversations. I guess that won't happen now."
聊過很多 現在不能了
"I will miss you a lot."
我會很想念的
"I will always miss you, think of you, and feel empty."
會想念你 想起你會感到空落落的
"Now, do everything you want to do in the world without penalties."
以後在沒有懲罰的世界裡
做你想做的一切吧
- That's right. - The world without penalties.
-是的 是的 -沒有懲罰的世界
- He is right. - He is good.
-沒錯啊 -說的好
(We'll protect the world with penalties. Don't worry, Kwang Soo.)
- It is the world without penalties. - He is good.
沒有懲罰的世界 沒錯
(We'll protect the world with penalties. Don't worry, Kwang Soo.)
- It is the world without penalties. - He is good.
-是啊 沒有懲罰的世界 -寫的好
(We'll protect the world with penalties. Don't worry, Kwang Soo.)
Se Chan doesn't disappoint.
果然寫的很好啊
Which song did they request?
那麼 申請曲是什麼
(The song Ji Hyo, So Min, and Se Chan requested is...)
-嗯 -走好
It's "Goodbye".
(The song Ji Hyo, So Min, and Se Chan requested is...)
("Goodbye" by Jung Jae Wook.)
- "Goodbye"? - It's a song by Jung Jae Wook.
-走好 是嗎 -是的 鄭在旭的
("Goodbye" by Jung Jae Wook.)
-走好 我珍貴的人 -走好 我珍貴的人
- Goodbye, my precious one - Goodbye, my precious one
("Goodbye" by Jung Jae Wook.)
- Thank you - Thank you
-謝謝你 -謝謝你
(A song for grateful and precious Kwang Soo)
-鄭在旭 -這首歌 我真的很喜歡的
Jung Jae Wook.
(A song for grateful and precious Kwang Soo)
- I love this song. - It's a good song.
嗯 是很好的歌
(A song for grateful and precious Kwang Soo)
(Kwang Soo, goodbye.)
A slave.
-是奴隸吧 奴隸 -這裡完全就是
(Don't be sorry)
吐出來
Spit it out.
(Don't be sorry)
- You told me to eat it! - You punk!
不是讓我吃嗎
這個 我是讓你剝 誰讓你吃了
I told you to unwrap it, not eat it.
(They fought without feeling sorry for the past 11 years.)
- It's an actual fight. - She hit him for real.
真的打了
(They fought without feeling sorry for the past 11 years.)
- How dare you! - Ji Hyo!
-你往哪兒 -智孝啊
(They fought without feeling sorry for the past 11 years.)
(Since she was so close and precious to him, )
- I need to imitate Jong Kook. - Thank you. I love you.
原來真的會變成這樣啊
(Kwang Soo wanted to fall into her arms first.)
謝謝你 愛你
- All right. - Hug.
(Kwang Soo wanted to fall into her arms first.)
You have a long torso.
是啊 哥哥的腰不是很長嗎
(From the moment they visited the show as guests, )
我來跳下去吧
- I will dive in first. - He is telling a lie.
(From the moment they visited the show as guests, )
-乾脆就說謊說是40個 -好的
- I will dive in first. - He is telling a lie.
(So Min and Se Chan bonded with Kwang Soo.)
你就做你之前做的就行
This place...
(So Min and Se Chan bonded with Kwang Soo.)
- We decided to join Kwang Soo! - Let's go!
-我們要選擇李光洙線 -選擇你
- Really? - Young blood!
-真的 -年輕血液
(They formed the young members' clique.)
老幺線 嘿嘿嘿
- The young members! - This is fun!
(They formed the young members' clique.)
哇 真有趣 真有趣
- The young members! - This is fun!
(They were happy when they were together.)
This is fun!
真有趣
(They were happy when they were together.)
- You kept it. - Of course. I wore it all summer.
-其實我喜歡 -那我會好好戴著這個的
(They were happy when they were together.)
It's pretty, right?
漂亮吧
(They were happy when they were together.)
We did it!
(I was happy)
(The younger members are special to Kwang Soo, )
(and he will never forget them.)
(Goodbye, my precious one.)
Now...
-那麼 現在剩下李光洙的信 -光洙的信
(Now it's time...)
- Kwang Soo's letter remains. - Kwang Soo's letter.
(to listen to the last letter.)
嗯 是的
All right.
(to listen to the last letter.)
(Kwang Soo will deliver...)
(his last story.)
"Members,"
成員們
"you helped me become the person I am today..."
是你們造就了現在的我
"and gave me another family."
讓我感受到了另一個家庭
"Thank you so much."
非常非常感謝
"I am sorry."
對不起
"Again, I am sorry."
還是對不起
"I didn't do well over the past 11 years,"
11年的時間雖然沒能好好表現
"but I think I did my best."
每週都盡全力了
"Every week, the Running Man members do their absolute best."
每週都全員到齊
粉身碎骨盡全力的Running Man
"Please continue to give the show a lot of love and attention."
希望大家以後更多多關心喜愛
"Thank you."
謝謝
(Kwang Soo left an empty spot in Running Man, )
He always sits there.
哥哥還偏偏要坐在那裡
(and Running Man left an empty spot in Kwang Soo.)
- That means he is confident. - Yes.
一直到最後
不管多少都能趕上來
- That means he is confident. - Yes.
是啊
(We hope pretty flowers will grow...)
- Come on. - How pretty!
太漂亮了
(We hope pretty flowers will grow...)
Seriously.
你看那些花
Will we listen to a song Kwang Soo requested?
要放一下光洙的歌嗎
Which song would you like to listen to?
推薦一下想聽什麼歌
I was going to pick "Goodbye Now".
本來是想要現在再見這首歌
(in those empty spots.)
你說啥
- Which song? - I was going to pick "Goodbye Now".
(in those empty spots.)
本來是想要現在再見這首歌
是啊
-現在再見 -是啊
- "Goodbye Now". - Yes.
(in those empty spots.)
好的好的
- "Goodbye Now". - Yes.
(The song Kwang Soo requested will be played soon.)
因為經常會聽
We listened to the song many times.
(The song Kwang Soo requested will be played soon.)
-再見並不是永遠的分別 -沒錯
- It isn't an endless parting - It isn't an endless parting
(The song Kwang Soo requested will be played soon.)
It's played the most often.
最常用的就是這首歌
The album that contains the day with Kwang Soo is here.
承載著和光洙一天時間的相冊已經到達了
(Photos of a day with Kwang Soo are already here.)
- Did it arrive? - Really?
-已經來了嗎 -真的嗎
(Photos of a day with Kwang Soo are already here.)
這麼快
- Already? - Before I hand over the album,
(Photos of a day with Kwang Soo are already here.)
在即將送上這相冊之前
- Already? - Before I hand over the album,
I will announce a few results.
需要公佈幾個結果
(It's time to reveal the hidden mission results...)
-對的 -對哦
- That's right. - That's right.
(It's time to reveal the hidden mission results...)
That's right.
(that everyone forgot for a moment.)
對哦
Today, the seven members except for Kwang Soo...
(that everyone forgot for a moment.)
其實今天一天的時間
Today, the seven members except for Kwang Soo...
(The hidden mission for the 7 members)
除李光洙在外的7位
今天的隱藏任務就是要和李光洙一起拍照
had the hidden mission of getting photos taken with him.
(The hidden mission for the 7 members)
(Get as many photos as possible taken with Kwang Soo.)
The first place with the most number of photos with Kwang Soo...
和李光洙一起拍照數量最多的人就是第1名
(The winner will get the same prize that Kwang Soo acquired.)
will acquire the same presents as Kwang Soo.
可以獲得和光洙一樣的禮物
(The winner will get the same prize that Kwang Soo acquired.)
The last place will receive the penalty.
最後一名要接受懲罰
(The bottom place will have to get the penalty.)
I don't think I am in last place.
感覺不是最後一名
(The bottom place will have to get the penalty.)
這就公佈結果
- I will announce the results. - Okay.
(The bottom place will have to get the penalty.)
好的好的
(They had a fierce competition to stand next to Kwang Soo.)
- And those of you... - Will you give us the brand?
舉個例子
聽完問題以後
是說品牌名嗎
- And those of you... - Will you give us the brand?
什麼時候才能有機會讓你背我
When will I get a piggyback ride from you again?
(They made memories as they got the photos taken.)
哥
(Who will place 1st and receive the present?)
- I will announce the results. - Okay.
這就公佈結果
(Who will place 1st and receive the present?)
好的好的
Jae Seok,
(Who will place 1st and receive the present?)
劉在錫27張
Jae Seok,
27 photos.
27 photos?
27張嗎
Seok Jin,
池石鎮27張
27 photos.
What?
什麼呀什麼呀
- 27 photos. - What?
27張
Jong Kook, 27 photos. Haha, 27 photos.
什麼呀什麼呀
金鐘國27張
HAHA 27張
Ji Hyo, 27 photos. So Min, 27 photos.
宋智孝27張
全昭旻27張
- No way. - Se Chan, 27 photos.
梁世燦27張
Everyone was in the same number of photos.
所有人都拍了同樣張數的照片
- What? - What is going on?
-什麼呀 -太壞了
(The hidden mission was competitive.)
什麼呀
-什麼呀 -太壞了
(The hidden mission was competitive.)
(How did they get the same result?)
- What? - What is going on?
-什麼呀 -太壞了
(How did they get the same result?)
Since everyone won,
所有人都是共同第1名
Kwang Soo succeeded in his last hidden mission.
所以李光洙在最後的隱藏任務中成功了
(Kwang Soo succeeded in his last hidden mission.)
Kwang Soo succeeded in his last hidden mission.
在最後的隱藏任務中成功了
- Did you have a hidden mission? - I see.
你有隱藏任務嗎
(Did Kwang Soo have a hidden mission?)
你也有隱藏任務嗎
- Kwang Soo succeeded? - Did you have a hidden mission?
(Did Kwang Soo have a hidden mission?)
光洙哥
I see.
(Did Kwang Soo have a hidden mission?)
Kwang Soo had a hidden mission.
光洙也有任務的
Today, Kwang Soo carried out...
其實今天李光洙在瞞著成員們實行隱藏任務
a hidden mission behind the members' backs.
(Kwang Soo also had a hidden mission!)
有些什麼
What was it?
(Kwang Soo also had a hidden mission!)
今天在福不福抽籤出示過的7個禮物
The seven presents that were shown,
(Kwang Soo also had a hidden mission!)
a premium champagne, a brand-name hoodie,
最高級香檳 名牌連帽衛衣
(The 7 gifts were really extravagant.)
裝飾畫框 音響 床品套裝
a decorative picture frame, a sound bar,
(The 7 gifts were really extravagant.)
a bedding set, and the others are ready.
全都準備好了
(The 7 gifts were really extravagant.)
其實這些是李光洙在上週上上週
Last week and the week before that,
(The 7 gifts were really extravagant.)
(These gifts were actually...)
為了成員們親自購買的禮物
Kwang Soo actually bought these for the members.
(These gifts were actually...)
(handpicked and bought by Kwang Soo during the past 2 weeks.)
什麼呀
- What? - Really?
(handpicked and bought by Kwang Soo during the past 2 weeks.)
Kwang Soo actually bought these for the members.
為了成員們親自購買的禮物
(handpicked and bought by Kwang Soo during the past 2 weeks.)
-什麼呀 -真的嗎
- What? - Really?
(handpicked and bought by Kwang Soo during the past 2 weeks.)
你為啥要買名牌啊
Why did you buy such nice items?
(handpicked and bought by Kwang Soo during the past 2 weeks.)
(They were his presents for the members.)
I didn't know he would reveal it.
並不知道會這樣不自然
(They were his presents for the members.)
Kwang Soo had to complete his hidden mission...
李光洙要在自己的隱藏任務中獲得成功
to deliver the presents on the show.
才能將這些禮物送上
(It's the last surprise Kwang Soo prepared.)
Are they really for us?
真的哥
是給我們的嗎
(It's the last surprise Kwang Soo prepared.)
(10 days before the shoot)
In any case...
不管怎樣
(10 days before the shoot)
(Kwang Soo was preparing gifts for the members.)
I want to give presents to the members.
成員們的禮物
(Kwang Soo was preparing gifts for the members.)
I won't do that on the show, but...
這並不是因為節目才準備的
不管怎樣
Are you preparing presents?
是在準備禮物對吧
I don't know if I will be able to deliver them.
但是不知道能不能送上禮物
- They get a bit... - They think it's cringe-worthy.
這有點不好意思
(He knew that the members would hate even a small gift.)
不知道該怎麼送出去
They don't even like receiving birthday presents.
(He knew that the members would hate even a small gift.)
甚至很不喜歡收生日禮物
They don't even like receiving birthday presents.
(Kwang Soo was looking for a natural way to give them.)
They get embarrassed.
很不好意思所以
(Kwang Soo was looking for a natural way to give them.)
但其實雖然是為了成員們沒錯
The presents are for the members...
(Kwang Soo was looking for a natural way to give them.)
as well as myself.
不管怎樣也算是為了我自己
稍微準備了點禮物
- My heart will be lighter. - If you give the presents?
唯有這樣才能讓我心裡好受些
(On behalf of Kwang Soo who felt sorry for the members...)
-付出一些 -嗯嗯
付出一些
That's right.
(On behalf of Kwang Soo who felt sorry for the members...)
(On the day of the shooting, )
- You prepared presents. - Yes.
聽說你準備了禮物
(the staff notified him of a surprise hidden rule.)
對的
我們瞞著李光洙
We received the presents from your manager.
(the staff notified him of a surprise hidden rule.)
(The race where the staff will take credit...)
通過經紀人收到了那些禮物
準備了用這些禮物來進行的競賽
We plan to use them for the race today.
(The race where the staff will take credit...)
(for Kwang Soo's gifts is now ready to go.)
The members think those presents are for you,
成員們都以為是李光洙的禮物時間
(Kwang Soo's last race...)
but it's actually your chance...
其實李光洙要選擇
(will be over the gifts that Kwang Soo prepared.)
是否能將準備好的那些禮物
to deliver them to the members.
(will be over the gifts that Kwang Soo prepared.)
送到成員們的手上
You must pick a boiled egg to give each member a present.
(will be over the gifts that Kwang Soo prepared.)
要選中煮熟的雞蛋才能給該成員送上禮物
You must pick a boiled egg to give each member a present.
- I think he will succeed. - My goodness.
感覺這次會成功
(Kwang Soo picked the eggs carefully for the members.)
哎喲喂
Until the end...
(Kwang Soo picked the eggs carefully for the members.)
在最後
Until the end...
It will be hard to pick a boiled egg seven times in a row,
其實很難連續7次選中熟雞蛋
(It's very unlikely that Kwang Soo will choose...)
It will be hard to pick a boiled egg seven times in a row,
(boiled eggs 7 times in a row.)
所以也給予李光洙特別的隱藏規則
so you will have a special hidden rule.
(boiled eggs 7 times in a row.)
(That's why Kwang Soo will be given a hidden rule.)
與李光洙拍最多張照片的人
The members think that the person who has...
(That's why Kwang Soo will be given a hidden rule.)
(Members' hidden mission is that whoever gets...)
the most number of photos with you...
(the highest number of photos taken with Kwang Soo...)
就能獲得同樣的禮物
receives the same presents,
(the highest number of photos taken with Kwang Soo...)
(will win and acquire gifts.)
while the person in last place gets a penalty.
最後一名要接受懲罰
是這樣告訴他們隱藏規則的
(will win and acquire gifts.)
所以李光洙如果讓他們成為
If you help all of them tie for first place,
(will win and acquire gifts.)
(Kwang Soo's mission...)
隱藏任務的共同第1名
If you help all of them tie for first place,
(is to make them all win.)
全員都能獲得第1名
they will receive the presents...
(is to make them all win.)
就可以成功獲得獎品
所有人都可以免除受罰
and be exempt from the penalty.
(is to make them all win.)
(It's the only way for him to give his gifts...)
So they need to be in the same number of photos.
要讓拍照的照片張數保持一致
(and avoid the penalty.)
So they need to be in the same number of photos.
(He must make sure that the number of photos...)
That's right.
對的
(are the same for all members.)
The real-time rankings will be shown to you secretly...
所以成員們的實時張數
(The staff will show the ranking in secret just for Kwang Soo.)
我們會通過骰子悄悄告訴你
through the dice in front of the production crew.
(The staff will show the ranking in secret just for Kwang Soo.)
It will be in the order of age starting from the left.
每個骰子從左開始按照成員們的年齡來排列
(The dice order will be in the members' age.)
每個骰子的數字
Each die's number shows the member's ranking.
(The dice order will be in the members' age.)
(Each die's number shows the member's ranking.)
就代表該成員隱藏任務的目前排名
Each die's number shows the member's ranking.
(He must make sure that all dice have 1...)
進入LP BAR 開始秘密任務就結束了
The moment you enter the last venue, the LP bar,
(He must make sure that all dice have 1...)
(before he enters the LP bar.)
the hidden mission will end.
What?
怎麼了 怎麼了
(Thus started Kwang Soo's game of wits.)
怎麼了啊
為什麼總是要說孩子
Let me see the rankings.
(He checked with the producer from time to time.)
Is Se Chan in last place?
世燦是最後一名嗎
(He checked with the producer from time to time.)
(Kwang Soo learned that Se Chan is in the bottom place...)
How many remains?
還剩幾個
(Kwang Soo learned that Se Chan is in the bottom place...)
It's nice.
-越來越覺得 -還要繼續
(and stayed close to Se Chan.)
(He followed Se Chan around.)
That's a lot.
來了好多啊
(When he pulled Se Chan up in the rankings, )
(he saw that Jae Seok was in the bottom place.)
Come on.
還是這裡好
(Kwang Soo was busy all day long.)
What are you doing?
你怎麼了
(Kwang Soo was busy all day long.)
The last place.
誰是最後一名
(Checking the rankings again)
Ji Hyo is in last place.
最後一名是智孝姐嗎
(Then he targeted Se Chan, Jong Kook, and Ji Hyo.)
- We were here before. - I recognize this place.
我們今天去哪裡啊
(While everyone looked at the scenery, )
這裡是那裡
是那裡
Me too.
(While everyone looked at the scenery, )
(Kwang Soo looked at the members.)
哦 是啊
- You are right. - We were here before.
(Kwang Soo looked at the members.)
這裡和哥哥家很近
是啊
- Aren't those evening primroses? - How pretty!
(Kwang Soo looked at the members.)
這是不是夜來香
真好看
(Even the moments that seemed like lucky chances...)
(were parts of Kwang Soo's love.)
怎麼總是拍照片啊
Hyung Gu, what are the rankings?
(were parts of Kwang Soo's love.)
亨久 現在排名怎麼樣了
Hyung Gu, what are the rankings?
(Curious)
Really?
哦 真的嗎
(Kwang Soo's busy day...)
(had a happy ending.)
He completed the mission.
但是最後完成了所有的任務
That's how we got the same number.
所以結果才這樣的
(Since everyone won 1st place, )
Since all of you are first place, you can take your present.
因為大家是共同第一
(they all get the gifts and no penalty.)
所有人可以拿走各自的禮物
I can't believe they are from Kwang Soo.
不是 光洙給了我們禮物
Why did you buy such expensive presents?
這禮物太貴了吧
Did you control the numbers?
也就是說他調整了張數 是嗎
(The last presents from Kwang Soo, )
You knew about it.
原來你都知道
(the man who wanted to give, not receive.)
嗯
Thanks to Kwang Soo, everyone is exempt from the penalty.
(the man who wanted to give, not receive.)
就這樣因李光洙的成功
Thanks to Kwang Soo, everyone is exempt from the penalty.
沒有最後一名 全員免除了懲罰
I will reveal the presents Kwang Soo prepared.
首先公開李光洙親自準備的禮物
(It's time to reveal the presents Kwang Soo prepared.)
- We didn't prepare any presents. - I know.
可我們沒有準備禮物啊
(It's time to reveal the presents Kwang Soo prepared.)
太多了
We didn't prepare any presents.
(It's time to reveal the presents Kwang Soo prepared.)
可我們真沒準備 怎麼辦
We didn't prepare any presents.
What?
什麼啊
- What is that? - It's a present.
哇 那是禮物
- There is a present for everyone. - There is a present for everyone.
不是 這禮物 每個人都有
(These 7 gifts match the members' tastes.)
都有
There are names.
(These 7 gifts match the members' tastes.)
還有名字
Kwang Soo bought a present that suits each member.
(These 7 gifts match the members' tastes.)
各自拿走自己喜歡的東西就行了
Kwang Soo bought a present that suits each member.
Really?
真的嗎
This is for Haha.
這裡還有HAHA
Seok Jin.
石鎮哥
- What? - It's yours.
(Seok Jin likes to use clutch bags.)
Is that Seok Jin's?
這些都是禮物嗎
(Seok Jin likes to use clutch bags.)
- I didn't prepare anything. - It's Seok Jin's.
哥哥的禮物很好啊
什麼啊
What is this?
這是什麼 這是什麼
(Jae Seok often wears hoodies.)
Why did you get such an expensive present?
為什麼送我這個 很貴的
(Jae Seok often wears hoodies.)
Why is mine small?
我的為什麼這麼小
(Dong Hoon likes to wear clothes from this very brand.)
You will like it.
哥 你會喜歡的
(Dong Hoon likes to wear clothes from this very brand.)
You will like it.
昭旻的是什麼
What's So Min's present? Oh, the champagne.
(Dong Hoon likes to wear clothes from this very brand.)
昭旻的是酒
- I love it. - Right. That's what she likes.
(So Min likes sweet champagnes.)
啊 我 真的
不是 這個
- Gosh, this is... - What's this, So Min?
(So Min likes sweet champagnes.)
這是昭旻的嗎
The bedding set is for Ji Hyo.
還有智孝的
(Sleeping is Ji Hyo's best cure.)
That's because she sleeps a lot.
她總愛睡覺 所以送了床品套裝
(Sleeping is Ji Hyo's best cure.)
What's for me?
我的會是什麼呢
Why does it always have to be so big for me?
為什麼總是送我這麼大的
It's a sound bar.
這是音響
(Jong Kook often watches Netflix on TV.)
- It's a sound bar. - I don't even know what it is.
是音響
哦 音響 這個就是音響的樣子
(Jong Kook often watches Netflix on TV.)
你就當做是電視音響就行了
- It's like a TV speaker. - Really?
(Jong Kook often watches Netflix on TV.)
(For Jong Kook to enjoy binge-watching...)
哦 是嗎
- So you can watch Netflix. - I've never had this before.
(For Jong Kook to enjoy binge-watching...)
我沒想到我人生裡有人會送我這個
This is really nice.
(For Jong Kook to enjoy binge-watching...)
是啊
Why are you giving this to me?
你為什麼送我這個啊 小子
Se Chan, this is a picture frame.
世燦 這是相框
(He got a picture frame for Se Chan.)
這怎麼辦啊
Gosh, what do I do?
(He got a picture frame for Se Chan.)
We once went to buy a painting together.
之前我和他一起出去逛街買畫
- He didn't buy it that day. - I can't believe this.
是啊
可當天沒有買
I guess Jong Kook will have to move.
真好
(All the gifts show how much he thought about them.)
鐘國 你是不是應該搬家了
- This is really nice. - It's so good.
(All the gifts show how much he thought about them.)
光洙
放客廳
In the living room...
(Kwang Soo can finally relax.)
I felt a little shy about giving this to you,
這要是放客廳
這直接給的話我有點不好意思
(Kwang Soo can finally relax.)
so I met Bo Pil and talked about this.
-所以我見了寶弼 -是啊
他替我想了方案
Gosh, this is really...
這是什麼
(Now, it's the production crew's gift for Kwang Soo.)
紀念牌 紀念牌
- It's a commemorative plaque. - It says Lee Kwang Soo.
(Now, it's the production crew's gift for Kwang Soo.)
李光洙 這個
純金紀念牌
- What's that? - It's pure gold.
(Now, it's the production crew's gift for Kwang Soo.)
(It's a golden name tag, the symbol of Running Man.)
It's a name tag.
是姓名牌
(It's a golden name tag, the symbol of Running Man.)
(Lee Kwang Soo)
I really want one.
這個真想要
(You can stop running and walk now.)
現在你不用跑了可以走路了
"You can stop running and walk now."
(You can stop running and walk now.)
我們特別的兄弟 李光洙
"Our special brother, Lee Kwang Soo. From the Running Man crew."
(You can stop running and walk now.)
(Our special brother, Lee Kwang Soo.)
"Our special brother, Lee Kwang Soo. From the Running Man crew."
是節目組的
- That's really cool. - It's gold.
真酷啊
(A big gift from a cheap production crew)
是黃金啊
- It's pure gold. - Thank you.
(A big gift from a cheap production crew)
是黃金 是黃金
- That's very rare. - Sure.
(A big gift from a cheap production crew)
真的好珍貴啊
這真的很珍貴
And here's our second gift.
(A big gift from a cheap production crew)
還有第二個禮物是
All the 112 crew members wrote messages to him.
今天一整天在座的112名工作人員寫的
(By Running Man)
All the 112 crew members wrote messages to him.
(The 112 crew members left him messages.)
- Really? - It's like a Rolling Paper.
真的嗎
(The 112 crew members left him messages.)
這也是
- My gosh. - This will make you cry.
(The 112 crew members left him messages.)
看了這個要流眼淚了
There's one from Kang Chan Hee.
(The 112 crew members left him messages.)
我們的燦熙
There's one from Kang Chan Hee.
是姜燦熙導演寫的
(Kwang Soo. It's from Kang Chan Hee.)
寫得誠意滿滿
- Thank you. - It looks very sincere.
(Kwang Soo. It's from Kang Chan Hee.)
他寫得很認真
- Thank you. - It looks very sincere.
(Take care and be sincere. You must come back.)
- He wrote with his sincere heart. - I can see that.
真的很認真
哇 看光洙
- Gosh, Kwang Soo. - There's even a drawing.
(The production crew is sad...)
真的寫得很認真
這真的很珍貴
- This is a great gift. - It's really nice.
(The production crew is sad...)
(as much as the members.)
這是很好的禮物
- This is the best gift. - Thank you so much.
(as much as the members.)
真的是很珍貴的禮物
There are so many things.
有好多東西啊
(There's more?)
This is our third gift, a speaker.
還有第三個禮物是
一個音響
This is our third gift, a speaker.
(They got Kwang Soo a speaker as he was thinking of getting one.)
- He loves music. - Thank you.
因為他喜歡音樂
(They got Kwang Soo a speaker as he was thinking of getting one.)
謝謝
- Is this product placement? - I bet it is.
(They got Kwang Soo a speaker as he was thinking of getting one.)
-光洙也有了一個音響 -這是PPL嗎
- Is this product placement? - I bet it is.
是PPL
- He will use it every day. - This is really...
這真是
(The product placement monster's last effort in vain)
一家人一起聽吧
- He'll use it with his girlfriend. - Enjoy it with your girlfriend.
(The product placement monster's last effort in vain)
這是PPL
It's perfect for a date.
(The product placement monster's last effort in vain)
相冊 相冊
There's a photo album.
(The fourth gift is a photo album.)
- The next gift is... - There's a photo album.
It's amazing that we got it done so soon.
(The fourth gift is a photo album.)
這麼快就做成了 好神奇啊
It's amazing that we got it done so soon.
These are the photos we took today.
是今天一天拍到的照片
(It resembles every moment from today's episode.)
這是今天拍的照片
- They are from today. - This is really good.
(It resembles every moment from today's episode.)
這真的是 怎麼說呢
Gosh, when did you take this photo?
這是什麼時候拍的啊
- Did they take photos? - When did you take this?
什麼時候拍的
這是什麼時候拍的
I saw him make a V with his fingers.
在後面一直舉著V
- Kwang Soo did? - We did.
光洙哥嗎
- We did. - What a great world.
我們
哦 是我們
現在世界變得好發達啊
- We get it right away. - Can we get the files as well?
很快就洗出來了
- I bet we can get the files. - Yes. We will give you the files.
這是不是傳送文件
不 可以接受文件
I want the files as well.
給我們發文件吧
He always talks about coffee trucks, so we got him a coupon.
咖啡車使用券
(The last gifts are revealed.)
平時總是講關於咖啡車的事
- A free pass to Running Man? - Good.
(The last gifts are revealed.)
Running man 隨時出演劵
- A free pass to Running Man? - Good.
好 好 好
You can come anytime without making a call.
隨時可以來
(The production crew's gifts are delivered to Kwang Soo.)
你不用事先聯絡
謝謝
- Thank you. - All right.
(The production crew's gifts are delivered to Kwang Soo.)
This is really precious.
真珍貴呢
Lastly, tell us how you feel.
最後聽一下感想吧
(It's time to say goodbye.)
All right, Kwang Soo. Say something to our viewers.
是啊 光洙
向喜愛Running man的觀眾朋友們
All right, Kwang Soo. Say something to our viewers.
(Kwang Soo's last song request, "Goodbye Now")
說一句吧
這比什麼都
(Kwang Soo's last song request, "Goodbye Now")
- Say goodbye. - Okay.
好
All right.
Thank you...
這段時間 非常感謝大家
for everything.
I was happy.
我很幸福
My name is Lee Kwang Soo, and I'm 26 years old.
(Kwang Soo joined Running Man as the youngest member 11 years ago.)
我叫李光洙
26歲
(Kwang Soo joined Running Man as the youngest member 11 years ago.)
Kwang Soo is crying.
光洙要哭了
(He loved laughter more than anyone.)
Kwang Soo is...
光洙
(He loved laughter more than anyone.)
好樣的
This is our first time to win on Running Man.
哥哥和我參加Running man
(He was more serious about Running Man than anyone.)
以來第一次拿到第一
- You have to film the whales. - Film the whales.
(He was more serious about Running Man than anyone.)
一個攝像頭得拍這個鯨魚
- You have to film the whales. - Film the whales.
不要拍 不要拍 轉向吧
- Film this. - This isn't about me.
Go, Jong Kook!
加油
(Behind the glittering glamour of Running Man, )
(he always shouted his head off to cheer for his members...)
Go, Jong Kook!
金鐘國加油
(he always shouted his head off to cheer for his members...)
Go, Song Jeoktoma!
宋兔馬加油
(and shared joy with them.)
Jong Kook!
哥
(and shared joy with them.)
(He was always very considerate and thoughtful.)
真是的
My gosh.
(He was always very considerate and thoughtful.)
理解 充分理解你的心情
- I understand how you feel. - I'm sorry.
(He was always very considerate and thoughtful.)
對不起
That was a good one.
(He was always very considerate and thoughtful.)
運營挺不錯
擔心你 反正…
(To some people, Kwang Soo is their childhood memories...)
I'm the master of Choo Shin Soo!
支配者
(and the pillar of hope that made them through hard times.)
什麼
(Now he says goodbye to you.)
Thank you for everything. Thank you.
一直非常感激
謝謝
All right.
Well done, Kwang Soo.
- You've worked so hard, Kwang Soo. - Good job.
你受苦了 光洙
You've done a great job for 11 years.
辛苦你了
真的辛苦你了 這11年 真的
We will see you again.
以後經常聚聚
Like we said before,
是啊 光洙…
this is...
這應該是光洙最後一次道別
our last episode with Kwang Soo.
I don't know how to express our feelings.
這種空落落的內心
I believe our viewers would feel the same way.
我想其實觀眾們也跟我們一樣
(Everyone's sad.)
But the thing is,
可是…
(Everyone's sad.)
life doesn't always go as we planned.
人生並不會隨我們的心意而動
Even after Kwang Soo leaves,
光洙離開之後 我們也會像剛才所說的那樣
(However, Running Man will continue even without Kwang Soo.)
like we said before,
-努力與製作組一起 -沒錯
- we will keep working hard... - Sure. We'll try our best.
(However, Running Man will continue even without Kwang Soo.)
必須努力
為大家獻上歡笑
To make our viewers happy.
(However, Running Man will continue even without Kwang Soo.)
I'd like to thank Kwang Soo again...
一直陪伴我們的光洙
(Kwang Soo, )
for the time he's spent with us.
再次表示感謝
(thank you for joining us.)
想再說一次 我們因你而開心幸福
Thanks to him, we were really merry and happy.
(thank you for joining us.)
(We had a great time, and we were happy.)
雖然光洙不在了
Kwang Soo won't be there, but please keep watching our show.
(We had a great time, and we were happy.)
但還請大家繼續期待下周Running Man
Kwang Soo won't be there, but please keep watching our show.
I'll buy this there.
像一家人
(The last photo time to put a period in Kwang Soo's 11 years)
All right.
光洙 你有交換證嗎
- Do you have the receipt for this? - Yes.
(The last photo time to put a period in Kwang Soo's 11 years)
- I want one. - Can you give me one?
可以出來嗎
No?
1, 2, 3.
1 2 3
(8 people's distant memory will remain as a photo.)
最後一張照片了 光洙
This is the last photo.
(8 people's distant memory will remain as a photo.)
- Thank you. - Thank you.
-謝謝 -謝謝
(8 people's distant memory will remain as a photo.)
辛苦了
Well done.
(8 people's distant memory will remain as a photo.)
- Thank you, Kwang Soo. - You punk.
光洙 謝謝你
你小子 哎呦
Look at you.
-真的 -辛苦了
- Kwang Soo. - Thank you so much.
光洙 真的辛苦了
- Oh, gosh. - Good work today.
今天辛苦了
Thank you.
-好好幹 -辛苦了
You were very lucky on your last day here.
因為最後一次 還給予各種幫助
今天簡直了
It was amazing.
Kwang Soo, clap your hands once.
請拍下板就好
- Okay. - It's the last time.
好啊
(The Long Legs' last slate)
好 這是你在Running Man
All right. That's your last slate on Running Man.
(The Long Legs' last slate)
最後一次打板了 光洙
別又弄哭他了
- Stop saying that. - Here I go.
(The Long Legs' last slate)
我拍了
- 1, 2... - Are you coming back next week?
1 2
不會下周還來吧
I hope so.
記得會多出來一週呢
- He can do one more week. - Like a prank.
整蠱攝像機
1, 2, 3. Thank you.
1 2 3
-辛苦了 -辛苦了
1, 2, 3. Thank you.
(Just like that, )
- Thank you. - Thank you.
(Kwang Soo stopped running after 3,991 days of running.)
辛苦了
Our oldest member, Seok Jin.
Running Man的老大哥 石鎮哥
Jae Seok, who helped me...
讓我有如今成就的 恩人在錫哥
come this far.
My moral support, Jong Kook.
我的精神支柱 鐘國哥
Haha, who is always like my family and friend.
一直像朋友像哥哥像家人般的HAHA哥
Ji Hyo who's like my real sister.
像親姐姐一樣的智孝姐
So Min and Se Chan...
像親弟弟妹妹一般的
who are like my sister and brother.
昭旻 世燦
我會一輩子懷著這份感恩之情
With my gratitude to all of them, I'll try my best...
for the rest of my life.
努力用心活下去
I love you.
我愛你們
(Our special brother Lee Kwang Soo, )
(thank you for the past 11 years.)
Dear members of the board game club.
Running Man桌面遊戲同好會會員朋友們
(The 1st get-together of the Board Game Club)
Dear members of the board game club.
(Hi, everyone. We have a get-together today.)
黑色龍卷是誰
- Let's meet in person. - Who is Pink Princess?
(Hi, everyone. We have a get-together today.)
粉色公主是誰
- Let's meet in person. - Who is Pink Princess?
(- Let's meet in person. - Don't you know what that means?)
為了殺我簡直了
They want to beat me.
(- Let's meet in person. - Don't you know what that means?)
這是我朋友 王子
- My friend, Kwang Ja. - Don't be afraid.
(All the weird members are getting together.)
魯尼 別怕魯尼
Strong guys use nicknames like this.
厲害的人就像這樣子
Look at the weak guys.
而弱的人反而是什麼爆炸 黑色龍卷
(They try to look strong...)
Look at the weak guys.
(with their nicknames.)
They have nicknames like exploding and dynamite.
我說了別說
- That's mine. - Hold it in your mouth.
(with their nicknames.)
(The 7 members enjoy the get-together...)
用嘴咬住
- Come here. - I'm sorry.
(The 7 members enjoy the get-together...)
(with every fiber of their bodies.)
等等
對不起 對不起
- Come here. - I'm sorry.
(Then they find a box.)
You need to jump.
跳一下就好
I'm going to win.
(The 1st Game Lover Get-together)
You need to jump.
跳一下就移動嗎
Do we teleport by jumping?
- What? - Where are we?
-什麼 -這是什麼 這裡是哪
(The members get into a board game.)
- What? - Where are we?
Where did Jae Seok go?
在錫去了哪兒呢
(I'm the protagonist of the game.)
為什麼在裡面
- What should we do? - Where's the way out?
(I'm the protagonist of the game.)
(They ally with each other...)
出去的路
這裡肯定有門 啊 沒有
I'm sure he's in here.
(They ally with each other...)
(and betray each other to win.)
He's not here.
喂 別這樣
(Who will be the strongest player?)
I'm going to win.
我一定要拿第一